<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on MH&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/categories/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on MH&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 17:01:09 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://minghaochen.github.io/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》31</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5431/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 17:01:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5431/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-sculptor-speaks&#34;&gt;The sculptor speaks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appreciation of sculpture depends upon the ability to respond to form in three dimensions. That is perhaps why sculpture has been described as the most difficult of all arts; certainly it is more difficult than the arts which involve appreciation of flat forms, shape in only two dimensions. Many more people are &amp;lsquo;form-blind&amp;rsquo; than colour-blind. The child learning to see, first distinguishes only two-dimensional shape; it cannot judge distances,depths. Later, for its personal safety and practical needs, it has to develop(partly by means of touch) the ability to judge roughly three-dimensional distances. But having satisfied the requirements of practical necessity, most people go no further.
Though they may attain considerable accuracy in the perception of flat form, they do not make the further intellectual and emotional effort needed to comprehend form in its full spatial existence.
this is what the sculptor must do. He must strive continually to think of, and
use, form in its full spatial completeness. He gets the solid shape, as it were, inside his head&amp;ndash;he thinks of it, whatever its size, as if he were holding it completely enclosed in the &lt;strong&gt;hollow&lt;/strong&gt; of his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hollow /&amp;lsquo;hɑlo/ 空的；中空的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He mentally visualizes a complex form from all round itself; he knows while he looks at one side what the other side is like;
he identifies himself with its centre of gravity, its mass, its weight; he realizes
its volume, as the space that the shape displaces in the air.
And the sensitive observer of sculpture must also learn to feel shape simply as shape, not as description or &lt;strong&gt;reminiscence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reminiscence /&amp;lsquo;rɛmə&amp;rsquo;nɪsns/ Someone&amp;rsquo;s reminiscences are things that they remember from the past, and which they talk or write about. 回忆&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He must, for example, perceive an
egg as a simple single solid shape, quite apart from its significance as food,or from the literary idea that it will become a bird. And so with solids such as a
shell, a nut, a plum, a pear, a &lt;strong&gt;tadpole&lt;/strong&gt;, a mushroom, a mountain peak, a kidney, a carrot, a tree-trunk, a bird, a bud, a lark, a ladybird, a &lt;strong&gt;bulrush&lt;/strong&gt;, a bone. From
these he can go on to appreciate more complex forms of combinations of several forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tadpole /&amp;lsquo;tæd&amp;rsquo;pol/ 蝌蚪&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bud /bʌd/ A bud is a small pointed lump that appears on a tree or plant and develops into a leaf or flower. 芽; 花蕾&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lark /lɑrk/ 云雀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ladybird /&amp;lsquo;ledɪbɝd/ 瓢虫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bulrush /&amp;lsquo;bʊlrʌʃ/ 芦苇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》29~30</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5429~30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 17:01:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5429~30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hovercraft&#34;&gt;The hovercraft&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hovercraft /ˈhʌvɚˌkræft/ 气垫船&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hover /&amp;lsquo;hʌvɚ/ To hover means to stay in the same position in the air without moving forward or backward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;craft /kræft/ You can refer to a boat, a spacecraft, or an aircraft as a craft. 船; 航天器; 航空器&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many strange new means of transport have been developed in our century, the strangest of them being perhaps the hovercraft. In 1953, a former electronics engineer in his fifties, Christopher Cockerell, who had turned to boat-building
on the Norfolk Broads, suggested an idea on which he had been working for
many years to the British Government and industrial circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turn to 转行&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;industrial circles 工业界&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the idea of supporting a craft on a&amp;rsquo; pad &amp;lsquo;, or &lt;strong&gt;cushion&lt;/strong&gt;, of low-pressure air, &lt;strong&gt;ringed&lt;/strong&gt; with a &lt;strong&gt;curtain&lt;/strong&gt; of higher pressure air. Ever since, people have had difficulty in deciding whether the craft should be ranged among ships, planes, or land vehicles&amp;ndash;for it is something in between a boat and an aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cushion /&amp;lsquo;kʊʃən/ A cushion is a fabric case filled with soft material, which you put on a seat to make it more comfortable. 坐垫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ringed with：If a building or place is ringed with or by something, it is surrounded by it. 围住&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curtain /&amp;lsquo;kɝtn/  something that covers or hides something else — usually + of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ever since 从那时起&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a shipbuilder, Cockerell was trying to find a solution to the problem of the wave resistance which wastes a good deal of a surface ship&amp;rsquo;s power and limits its speed. His answer was to lift the
vessel out of the water by making it ride on a cushion of air, no more than one or two feet thick.
This is done by a great number of ring-shaped air jets on the bottom of the craft. It &amp;lsquo;flies&amp;rsquo;, therefore, but it cannot fly higher&amp;ndash;its action depends on the surface, water or ground, over which it rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first tests on the Solent in 1959 caused a &lt;strong&gt;sensation&lt;/strong&gt;. The hovercraft
travelled first over the water, then mounted the beach, climbed up the &lt;strong&gt;dunes&lt;/strong&gt;,
and sat down on a road. Later it crossed the Channel, riding smoothly over the waves, which presented no problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sensation /sɛn&amp;rsquo;seʃən/ If a person, event, or situation causes a sensation, they cause great interest or excitement. 轰动&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dune /dʊn/ A dune is a hill of sand near the ocean or in a desert. 沙丘&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; first &amp;hellip;, then &amp;hellip;, and &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since that time, various types of hovercraft have appeared and taken up regular service&amp;ndash;&lt;strong&gt;cruises&lt;/strong&gt; on the Thames in London, for instance, have become an annual attraction. But we are only at the beginning of a development that may transport net-sea and land transport. Christopher Cockerell&amp;rsquo;s craft can establish transport
works in large areas with poor communications such as Africa or Australia; it
can become a &amp;lsquo;flying fruit-bowl&amp;rsquo;, carrying bananas from the plantations to the
ports, giant hovercraft liners could span the Atlantic; and the railway of the
future may well be the &amp;lsquo;hovertrain&amp;rsquo;, riding on its air cushion over a single rail,
which it never touches, at speeds up to 300 m.p.h.&amp;ndash;the possibilities appear unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bowl /bol/ 碗&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plantation /plæn&amp;rsquo;teʃən/ A plantation is a large piece of land, especially in a tropical country, where crops such as rubber, coffee, tea, or sugar are grown. (尤指热带国家的橡胶、咖啡、茶、甘蔗) 种植园&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the possibilities appear unlimited 前途不可限量&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;exploring-the-sea-floor&#34;&gt;Exploring the sea-floor&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sea floor 海底&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our knowledge of the oceans a hundred years ago was confined to the two-dimensional shape of the sea-surface and the hazards of navigation presented by the irregularities in depth of the shallow water close to the land. The open sea was deep and mysterious,and anyone who gave more than a passing thought to the bottom confines of the oceans probably assumed that the sea-bed was flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the shallow water 浅水区&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a passing thought  A sudden desire or change of mind, especially one that is unusual or unexplained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir James Clark Ross had obtained a sounding of over 2,400 &lt;strong&gt;fathoms&lt;/strong&gt; in 1836 but
it was not until 1800, when H.M.S. Porcupine was put at the disposal of the
Royal Society for several &lt;strong&gt;cruises&lt;/strong&gt;, that a series of deep &lt;strong&gt;soundings&lt;/strong&gt; was obtained
in the Atlantic and the first samples were collected by &lt;strong&gt;dredging&lt;/strong&gt; the bottom. Shortly after this the famous H.M.S. Challenger expedition established the study of the sea-floor as a subject worthy of the most qualified physicists and geologists. A burst of activity associated with the laying of submarine cables soon confirmed the Challenger&amp;rsquo;s observation that many parts of the ocean were two to three miles deep, and the existence of underwater features of considerable magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fathom /&amp;lsquo;fæðəm/ A fathom is a measurement of 6 feet or 1.8 metres, used when referring to the depth of water. 英寻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dredge /drɛdʒ/ When people dredge a harbour, river, or other area of water, they remove mud and unwanted material from the bottom with a special machine in order to make it deeper or to look for something. 清淤; 挖掘&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cruise /krʊz/ A cruise is a holiday during which you travel on a ship or boat and visit a number of places. 海上航游&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;worthy of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the most qualified &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;热潮 a brust of activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today enough soundings are available to enable a relief map of the Atlantic to
be drawn and we know something of the great variety of the sea-bed&amp;rsquo;s topography. Since the sea covers the greater part of the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface it is quite reasonable to regard the sea-floor as the basic form of the &lt;strong&gt;crust&lt;/strong&gt; of the earth, with &lt;strong&gt;superimposed&lt;/strong&gt; upon it the continents, together with the islands and other features of the oceans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sounding /&amp;lsquo;saʊndɪŋ/ 水深测量&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;topography /tə&amp;rsquo;pɑgrəfi/ 地形学&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is quite reasonable to xxx 因此完全有理由xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;crust /krʌst/ A crust is a hard layer of something, especially on top of a softer or wetter substance. 硬外壳&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The continents form rugged &lt;strong&gt;tablelands&lt;/strong&gt; which stand nearly three miles above the floor of the open ocean. From the shore-line out to a distance which may be anywhere from a few miles to a few hundred miles runs the gentle slope of the continental shelf, geologically part of the continents. The real dividing-line between continents and oceans occurs at the foot of a steeper slope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rugged /&amp;lsquo;rʌɡɪd/ A rugged area of land is uneven and covered with rocks, with few trees or plants. 崎岖多岩的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tableland /&amp;lsquo;tebllænd/ a plateau 高地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slope /slop/ A slope is the side of a mountain, hill, or valley. (山丘或山谷的) 斜坡&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the gentle slope of the continental shelf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dividing line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This continental slope usually starts at a place somewhere near the ice-fathom mark and in the course of a few hundred miles reaches the true ocean-floor at 2,500-3,000 fathoms. The slope averages about 1 in 30, but contains steep, probably vertical, cliffs, and gentle sediment-covered &lt;strong&gt;terraces&lt;/strong&gt;, and near its lower reaches there is a long tailing-off which is almost certainly the result of material transported out to deep water after being eroded from the continental masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the course of xxx 延伸到xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;average about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 in 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sediment /&amp;lsquo;sɛdɪmənt/ 沉积物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;terrace /&amp;lsquo;tɛrəs/ 梯田&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lower reaches 低处&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;erode /ɪˈrod/ If rock or soil erodes or is eroded by the weather, sea, or wind, it cracks and breaks so that it is gradually destroyed. 侵蚀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tailing-off 尾沙地带&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》27~28</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5427~28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 19:59:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5427~28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-vasa&#34;&gt;The ‘Vasa’&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the seventeenth-century empire of Sweden, the story of a &lt;strong&gt;galleon&lt;/strong&gt; that sank at the start of her &lt;strong&gt;maiden&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;voyage&lt;/strong&gt; in 1628 must be one of the strangest tales of the sea. For nearly three and a half centuries she lay at the bottom of Stockholm harbour until her discovery in 1956. This was the Vasa, royal &lt;strong&gt;flagship&lt;/strong&gt; of the great imperial fleet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;galleon /ˈɡæliən/ A galleon is a sailing ship with three masts. Galleons were used mainly in the fifteenth to seventeenth centuries. 大型三桅帆船&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maiden /&amp;lsquo;medn/ The maiden voyage or flight of a ship or aircraft is the first official journey that it makes. (航行、飞行) 首次的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voyage /&amp;lsquo;vɔɪɪdʒ/ A voyage is a long journey on a ship or in a spacecraft. 航程&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flagship /&amp;lsquo;flæɡʃɪp/ A flagship is the most important ship in a fleet of ships, especially the one on which the commander of the fleet is sailing. 旗舰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;King Gustavus Adolphus, &amp;lsquo;The Northern Hurricane&amp;rsquo;, then at the height of his military success in the Thirty Years&amp;rsquo; War, had &lt;strong&gt;dictated&lt;/strong&gt; her measurements
and &lt;strong&gt;armament&lt;/strong&gt;. Triple gun-decks mounted sixty-four bronze cannon. She was intended to play a leading role in the growing might of Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at the height of xxx 鼎盛阶段&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dictate /&amp;lsquo;dɪktet/ If someone dictates to someone else, they tell them what they should do or can do. 指示; 命令&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;armament /&amp;lsquo;ɑrməmənt/ weaponry used by military or naval force&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;measurement /&amp;lsquo;mɛʒɚmənt/ 尺寸，规模&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mount /maʊnt/ If you mount an object on something, you fix it there firmly. 安装&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;might /maɪt/ Might is power or strength. 力量&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she was prepared for her maiden voyage on August 10, 1628, Stockholm was in a &lt;strong&gt;ferment&lt;/strong&gt;. From the Skeppsbron and surrounding islands the people watched this thing of beauty begin to spread her sails and catch the wind. They had laboured for three years to produce this floating work of art; she was more richly &lt;strong&gt;carved&lt;/strong&gt; and ornamented than any previous ship. The high &lt;strong&gt;stern&lt;/strong&gt; castle was
&lt;strong&gt;a riot of&lt;/strong&gt; carved gods, demons, knights, kings, warriors, &lt;strong&gt;mermaids&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cherubs&lt;/strong&gt;; and zoomorphic animal shapes &lt;strong&gt;ablaze with&lt;/strong&gt; red and gold and blue, symbols of courage, power, and cruelty, were portrayed to stir the imaginations of the superstitious sailors of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ferment /&amp;lsquo;fə:ment/ Ferment is excitement and trouble caused by change or uncertainty. 骚动&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;floating work of art 水上艺术品&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stern /stɝn/  the rear or after part of a vessel, opposite the bow or stem 船尾; 艉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you say that there is a riot of something pleasant such as colour, you mean that there is a large amount of various types of it. (颜色等) 丰富多样&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a place is ablaze with lights or colours, it is very bright because of them. 光彩夺目的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the cannons of the &lt;strong&gt;anchored&lt;/strong&gt; warships thundered a salute to which the Vasa fired in reply. As she emerged from her drifting cloud of gun smoke with the water churned to foam beneath her bow, her flags flying, pennants waving, sails filling in the breeze, and the red and gold of her superstructure &lt;strong&gt;ablaze&lt;/strong&gt; with colour, she presented a more majestic spectacle than Stockholmers had ever seen before. All gun-ports were open and the muzzles peeped wickedly from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anchor /&amp;lsquo;æŋkɚ/ If a boat is at anchor, it is floating in a particular place and is prevented from moving by its anchor. 停泊&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;warship /&amp;lsquo;wɔrʃɪp/ A warship is a ship with guns that is used for fighting in wars. 战舰; 军舰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;salute /sə&amp;rsquo;lut/ If you salute someone, you greet them or show your respect with a formal sign. Soldiers usually salute officers by raising their right hand so that their fingers touch their forehead. 向…打招呼; 向…行军礼&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;churn /tʃɝn/ Churn up means the same as . 剧烈搅动&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;majestic /mə&amp;rsquo;dʒɛstɪk/ If you describe something or someone as majestic, you think they are very beautiful, dignified, and impressive. 壮丽的; 雄伟的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drifting /&amp;lsquo;driftiŋ/ 飘动的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;muzzle /&amp;lsquo;mʌzl/ The muzzle of a gun is the end where the bullets come out when it is fired. 枪口&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;peep /pip/ If you peep, or peep at something, you take a quick look at it, often secretly and quietly. 瞥一眼&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wicked /&amp;lsquo;wɪkɪd/ You use wicked to describe someone or something that is very bad and deliberately harmful to people. 邪恶的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the wind freshened there came a sudden squall and the ship made a strange movement, listing to port.
The Ordnance Officer ordered all the port cannon to be heaved to starboard to counteract the list, but the steepening angle of the decks increased. Then the sound of rumbling thunder reached the watchers on the shore, as cargo, ballast, &lt;strong&gt;ammunition&lt;/strong&gt; and 400 people went sliding and crashing down to the port side of the steeply listing ship. The lower gun-ports were now below water and the &lt;strong&gt;inrush&lt;/strong&gt; sealed the ship&amp;rsquo;s fate. In that first glorious hour, the mighty Vasa, which was intended to rule the Baltic, sank with all flags flying&amp;ndash;in the harbour of her birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squall /skwɔl/ A squall is a sudden strong wind which often causes a brief, violent rainstorm or snowstorm. 飑; 突起的狂风(常引起短暂暴雨或暴雪)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list /lɪst/ to lean over or cause to lean over to one side (尤指船)倾侧&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordnance /&amp;lsquo;ɔrdnəns/ Ordnance refers to military supplies, especially weapons. 军需品&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heave /hiv/ If you heave something heavy or difficult to move somewhere, you push, pull, or lift it using a lot of effort. (用力地) 推; 拉; 举起&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;counteract /ˌkaʊntɚ&amp;rsquo;ækt/ To counteract something means to reduce its effect by doing something that produces an opposite effect. 对…起反作用; 抵消&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;steepen /&amp;lsquo;stipən/ If a slope or an angle steepens, it becomes steeper. 变得陡峭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rumble /&amp;lsquo;rʌmbl/ A rumble is a low, continuous noise. 隆隆声&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cargo /&amp;lsquo;kɑrɡo/ The cargo of a ship or plane is the goods that it is carrying. 货物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ammunition /ˌæmju&amp;rsquo;nɪʃən/ Ammunition is bullets and rockets that are made to be fired from weapons. 弹药&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inrush /&amp;lsquo;ɪn&amp;rsquo;rʌʃ/ a sudden usually overwhelming inward flow or rush; influx 涌入; 流入&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;patients-and-doctors&#34;&gt;Patients and doctors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a sceptical age, but although our faith in many of the things in which our forefathers &lt;strong&gt;fervently&lt;/strong&gt; believed has weakened, our confidence in the &lt;strong&gt;curative&lt;/strong&gt; properties of the bottle of medicine remains the same as theirs. This modern faith in medicines is proved by the fact that the annual drug bill of the Health Services is mounting to astronomical figures and shows no signs at present of ceasing to rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curative  /&amp;lsquo;kjʊrətɪv/ Something that has curative properties can cure people&amp;rsquo;s illnesses. 有疗效的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fervently /ˈfə..vəntlɪ/ with passionate fervor
&amp;ldquo;both those for and against are fervently convinced they speak for the great majority of the people&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this modern faith in xxx 现代人对xxx的依赖&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;astronomical figures 天文数字&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;signs of ceasing to xxx 停止xxx的迹象&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of the patients attending the medical out-patients departments of our hospitals feel that they have not received adequate treatment unless they are able to carry home with them some tangible remedy in the shape of a bottle of medicine, a box of pills, or a small jar of ointment, and the doctor in charge of the department is only too ready to provide them with these requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the majority of the xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tangible /&amp;lsquo;tændʒəbl/  If something is tangible, it is clear enough or definite enough to be easily seen, felt, or noticed. 清晰明确的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ointment /&amp;lsquo;ɔɪntmənt/ An ointment is a smooth thick substance that is put on sore skin or a wound to help it heal. 药膏&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no quicker method of disposing of patients than by giving them what they are asking for, and since most medical men in the Health Services are overworked and have little time for offering time-consuming and little-appreciated advice on such subjects as diet, right living, and the need for abandoning bad habits, etc., the bottle, the box, and the jar are almost always granted them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grant /ɡrænt/ If someone in authority grants you something, or if something is granted to you, you are allowed to have it. 准予&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nor is it only the ignorant and ill-educated person who has such faith in the bottle of medicine, especially if it be wrapped in white paper and sealed with a dab of red sealing-wax by a clever chemist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dab /dæb/ A dab of something is a small amount of it that is put onto a surface. 少量&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is recounted of Thomas Carlyle that when he heard of the illness of his friend, Henry Taylor, he went off immediately to visit him, carrying with him in his pocket what remained of a bottle of medicine formerly prescribed for an indisposition of Mrs Carlyle&amp;rsquo;s. Carlyle was entirely ignorant of what the bottle in his pocket contained, of the nature of the illness from which his friend was suffering, and of what had previously been wrong with his wife, but a medicine that had worked so well in one form of illness would surely be of equal benefit in another, and comforted by
the thought of the help he was bringing to his friend, he hastened to Henry Taylor&amp;rsquo;s house. History does not relate whether his friend accepted his medical help, but in all probability he did. The great advantage of taking medicine is that it makes no demands on the taker beyond that of putting up for a moment with a disgusting taste, and that is what all patients demand of their doctors&amp;ndash; to be cured at no inconvenience to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recount /rɪ&amp;rsquo;kaʊnt/ If you recount a story or event, you tell or describe it to people. 叙述; 描述&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an indisposition of xxx 小病&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hasten /&amp;lsquo;hesn/ If you hasten to do something, you are quick to do it. 急忙&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;history does not relate whether xxx历史没有记载是否xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the great advantage of xxx is that yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disgusting /dɪs&amp;rsquo;ɡʌstɪŋ/ If you say that something is disgusting, you are criticizing it because it is extremely unpleasant. 令人厌恶的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》26</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5426/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 20:18:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5426/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-past-life-of-the-earth&#34;&gt;The past life of the earth&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is animals and plants which lived in or near water whose remains are most likely to be preserved, for one of the necessary conditions of preservation is quick &lt;strong&gt;burial&lt;/strong&gt;, and it is only in the seas and rivers, and sometimes lakes, where mud and &lt;strong&gt;silt&lt;/strong&gt; have been continuously deposited, that bodies and the like can be rapidly covered over and preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remain / rɪˈmeɪn / The remains of a person or animal are the parts of their body that are left after they have died, sometimes after they have been dead for a long time. (人的) 遗体; (动物的) 残骸&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deposit /dɪ&amp;rsquo;pɑzɪt/ A deposit is an amount of a substance that has been left somewhere as a result of a chemical or geological process. 沉积物; 矿床&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx and the like；xxx之类的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in the most favourable circumstances only a small fraction of the creatures that die are preserved in this way before decay sets in or, even more likely, before &lt;strong&gt;scavengers&lt;/strong&gt; eat them. After all, all living creatures live by feeding on something else, whether it be plant or animal, dead or alive, and it is only by chance that such a fate is avoided. The remains of plants and animals that lived on land are much more rarely preserved, for there is seldom anything to cover them over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;favourable /&amp;lsquo;feivərəbl/ Favourable conditions make something more likely to succeed or seem more attractive. 有利的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a small fraction of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scavenger /&amp;lsquo;skævɪndʒɚ/ 食腐动物；清道夫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;更可能 even more likely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set in  If something unpleasant sets in, it begins and seems likely to continue or develop. (不好的事物) 来了&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is only by chance that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of the innumerable birds that one sees flying about, not to mention the equally numerous small animals like field mice and &lt;strong&gt;voles&lt;/strong&gt; which you do not see, it is very rarely that one comes across a dead body, except, of course, on the roads. They decompose and are quickly destroyed by the weather or eaten by some other creature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;destroyed by the weather 风化&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is almost always due to some very special circumstances that traces of land animals survive, as by falling into inaccessible caves, or into an ice &lt;strong&gt;crevasse&lt;/strong&gt;, like the Siberian mammoths, when the whole animal is sometimes preserved, as in a refrigerator. This is what happened to the famous Beresovka &lt;strong&gt;mammoth&lt;/strong&gt; which was found preserved and in good condition. In his mouth were the remains of fir trees&amp;ndash;the last meal that he had before he fell into the crevasse and broke his back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;crevasse /krə&amp;rsquo;væs/ A crevasse is a large, deep crack in thick ice or rock. (厚冰或岩石中大而深的)裂缝&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fir /fɝ/  冷杉；枞木&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mammoth has now been restored in the Palaeontological Museum in Leningrad. Other animals were trapped in &lt;strong&gt;tar&lt;/strong&gt; pits, like the elephants, sabre-toothed cats, and numerous other creatures that are found at Rancho la Brea, which is now just a suburb of Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trap /træp/ If you are trapped somewhere, something falls onto you or blocks your way and prevents you from moving or escaping. 困住&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tar /tɑr/ Tar is a thick black sticky substance that is used especially for making roads. 沥青&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pit /pɪt/ A pit is a large hole that is dug in the ground. 大坑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently what happened was that water collected on these tar pits, and the bigger animals like the elephants &lt;strong&gt;ventured&lt;/strong&gt; out on to the apparently firm surface to drink, and were promptly &lt;strong&gt;bogged&lt;/strong&gt; in the tar. And then, when they were dead, the &lt;strong&gt;carnivores&lt;/strong&gt;, like the sabre-toothed cats and the giant wolves, came out to feed and suffered exactly the same fate. There are also endless numbers of birds in the tar as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venture /&amp;lsquo;vɛntʃɚ/ If you venture somewhere, you go somewhere that might be dangerous. 冒险去 (某处)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bog /bɑɡ/ A bog is an area of land that is very wet and muddy. 沼泽&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carnivore /&amp;lsquo;kɑrnɪvɔr/ A carnivore is an animal that eats meat. 食肉动物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》25</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5425/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 11:42:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5425/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;non-auditory-effects-of-noise&#34;&gt;Non-auditory effects of noise&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;auditory / ˈɔːdɪtərɪ / Auditory means related to hearing. 听觉的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people in industry and the Services, who have practical experience of noise, regard any investigation of this question as a waste of time; they are not prepared even to admit the possibility that noise affects people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have practical experience of xxx； 对xxx有切身体会&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regard xxx as xxx；认为&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, those who dislike noise will sometimes use most inadequate evidence to support their pleas for a quieter society. This is a pity, because noise &lt;strong&gt;abatement&lt;/strong&gt; really is a good cause. and it is likely to be &lt;strong&gt;discredited&lt;/strong&gt; if it gets to be associated with bad science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abatement / əˈbeɪtmənt / Abatement means a reduction in the strength or power of something or the reduction of it. 减少&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx really is a good cause；是件好事&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is likely to be discredited；不会被信任&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One &lt;strong&gt;allegation&lt;/strong&gt; often made is that noise produces mental illness. A recent article in a weekly newspaper, for instance, was headed with a striking illustration of a lady in a state of considerable distress, with the caption &amp;lsquo;She was yet another victim, reduced to a screaming wreck &amp;lsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allegation / ˌælɪˈɡeɪʃən / An allegation is a statement saying that someone has done something wrong. 指控&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was headed with xxx；以xxx为标题&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with the caption xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distress /dɪ&amp;rsquo;strɛs/ 危难，不幸；贫困；悲痛&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;screaming /&amp;lsquo;skrimɪŋ/ When someone screams, they make a very loud, high-pitched cry, for example, because they are in pain or are very frightened. (人因痛苦或恐惧而) 尖叫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wreck  / rɛk / If you say that someone is a wreck, you mean that they are very exhausted or unhealthy. 疲惫不堪的人; 不健康的人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On turning eagerly to the text, one learns that the lady was a typist who found the sound of office typewriters worried her more and more until eventually she had to go into a mental hospital. Now the &lt;strong&gt;snag&lt;/strong&gt; in this sort of &lt;strong&gt;anecdote&lt;/strong&gt; is of course that one cannot distinguish cause and effect. Was the noise a cause of the illness, or were the complaints about noise merely a symptom? Another patient might equally well complain that her neighbours were combining to &lt;strong&gt;slander&lt;/strong&gt; her and persecute her, and yet one might be cautious about believing this statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snag / snæɡ / A snag is a small problem or disadvantage. 小问题; 小挫折&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anecdote /&amp;lsquo;ænɪkdot/   An anecdote is a short, amusing account of something that has happened. 趣闻轶事&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slander /&amp;lsquo;slændɚ/ Slander is an untrue spoken statement about someone which is intended to damage their reputation. Compare . 诽谤&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;persecute /&amp;lsquo;pɝsɪkjut/ If someone is persecuted, they are treated cruelly and unfairly, often because of their race or beliefs. (因种族或信仰) 迫害&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is needed in the case of noise is a study of large numbers of people living under noisy conditions, to discover whether they are mentally ill more often than other people are. The United States Navy, for instance, recently examined a very large number of men working on aircraft carriers: the study was known as Project Anehin. It can be unpleasant to live even several miles from an aerodrome; if you think what it must be like to share the deck of a ship with several squadrons of jet aircraft, you will realize that a modern navy is a good place to study noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case of ;对于xxx问题&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aerodrome /&amp;lsquo;ɛrə&amp;rsquo;drom/ An aerodrome is a place or area where small aircraft can land and take off. 小型机场&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squadron  /&amp;lsquo;skwɑdrən/ A squadron is a section of one of the armed forces, especially the air force. (尤指空军的) 中队&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But neither psychiatric interviews nor objective tests were able to show any effects upon these American sailors. This result merely confirms earlier American and British studies: if there is any effect of noise upon mental health
it must be so small that present methods of psychiatric diagnosis cannot find it. That does not prove that it does not exist; but it does mean that noise is less dangerous than, say, being brought up in an &lt;strong&gt;orphanages&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;which really is a mental health hazard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;psychiatric /ˌsaɪkɪ&amp;rsquo;ætrɪk/ Psychiatric means relating to psychiatry. 治疗精神病的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;objective /əb&amp;rsquo;dʒɛktɪv/ Objective information is based on facts. 客观的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if there is any effect of xxx，it must be so small that yyy；如果有xxx影响，那也是很小的yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that does not prove that it does not exist： but it does mean xxx is yyy；这并不是证实不存在xxx但是确实说明了yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;orphanage /&amp;lsquo;ɔrfənɪdʒ/ An orphanage is a place where orphans live and are cared for. 孤儿院&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》24</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5424/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 09:38:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5424/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beauty&#34;&gt;Beauty&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do glimpses of beauty, either in nature or art, often suggest to the human mind?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;often suggest to xxx 对xxx产生启发的感觉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young man sees a sunset and, unable to understand or to express the emotion that it rouses in him, concludes that it must be the gateway to a world that lies beyond. It is difficult for any of us in moments of intense &lt;strong&gt;aesthetic&lt;/strong&gt; experience to resist the suggestion that we are catching a glimpse of a light that shines down to us from a different &lt;strong&gt;realm&lt;/strong&gt; of existence, different and, because the experience is intensely moving, in some way higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in moments of xxx 在xxx时刻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aesthetic  / iːsˈθɛtɪk, ɪs- / Aesthetic is used to talk about beauty or art, and people&amp;rsquo;s appreciation of beautiful things. 审美的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resist  / rɪˈzɪst / If you resist something such as a change, you refuse to accept it and try to prevent it. 抵制&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;realm  / rɛlm / You can use realm to refer to any area of activity, interest, or thought. (活动、兴趣、思想的) 领域&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, though the &lt;strong&gt;gleams&lt;/strong&gt; blind and dazzle, yet do they convey a hint of beauty and &lt;strong&gt;serenity&lt;/strong&gt; greater than we have known or imagined. Greater too than we can describe, for language, which was invented to convey the meanings of this world, cannot readily be fitted to the uses of another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gleam  / ɡliːm / If an object or a surface gleams, it reflects light because it is shiny and clean. 闪光&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yet do they xxx； 但它确实xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serenity /si&amp;rsquo;renəti/ 平静，宁静&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;than we have known or imagined； 不曾经历或无法想象&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readily / ˈrɛdɪlɪ / You also use readily to say that something can be done or obtained quickly and easily. For example, if you say that something can be readily understood, you mean that people can understand it quickly and easily. 容易地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all great art has this power of suggesting a world beyond is undeniable. In some moods, Nature shares it. There is no sky in June so blue that it does not point forward to a &lt;strong&gt;bluer&lt;/strong&gt;, no sunset so beautiful that it does not waken the vision of a greater beauty, a vision which passes before it is fully glimpsed, and in passing leaves an indefinable longing and regret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx is undeniable； 不可否认 既成事实的感觉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in some moods 在某种状态下&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;longing / ˈlɒŋɪŋ / If you feel longing or a longing for something, you have a rather sad feeling because you want it very much. 渴望&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;indefinable / ˌɪndɪˈfaɪnəbəl / An indefinable quality or feeling cannot easily be described. 难以形容的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, if this world is not merely a bad joke, life a &lt;strong&gt;vulgar&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;flare&lt;/strong&gt; amid the cool &lt;strong&gt;radiance&lt;/strong&gt; of the stars, and existence an empty laugh &lt;strong&gt;braying&lt;/strong&gt; across the mysteries; if these &lt;strong&gt;intimations&lt;/strong&gt; of a something behind and beyond are not evil humour born of indigestion, or &lt;strong&gt;whimsies&lt;/strong&gt; sent by the &lt;strong&gt;devil&lt;/strong&gt; to mock and madden us, if, in a word, beauty means something, yet we must not seek to interpret the meaning. If we glimpse the unutterable, it is unwise to try to utter it, nor should we seek to invest with significance that which we cannot grasp. Beauty in terms of our human meanings is meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bray  / breɪ / to make a similar sound, as in laughing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is not merely xx; 不只是&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vulgar  / ˈvʌlɡə / If you describe something as vulgar, you think it is in bad taste or of poor artistic quality. 粗俗的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radiance  / ˈreɪdɪəns / Radiance is a glowing light shining from something. 光辉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intimation /,ɪntɪ&amp;rsquo;meʃən/ 暗示 intimations of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humour  / ˈhjuːmə / If you are in a good humour, you feel cheerful and happy, and are pleasant to people. If you are in a bad humour, you feel bad tempered and unhappy, and are unpleasant to people. 心情&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yyy born of xxx; 由xxx引起的yyy怎么说&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whimsy  / ˈwɪmzɪ /  Whimsy is behaviour that is unusual, playful, and unpredictable, rather than having any serious reason or purpose behind it. 异想天开的行为&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unutterable  / ʌnˈʌtərəbəl / 无法用言语表达的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is unwise to xxxx, nor should we seek to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in terms of 按照xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》22~23</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5422~23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 21:02:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5422~23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;knowledge-and-progress&#34;&gt;Knowledge and progress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does the idea of progress &lt;strong&gt;loom&lt;/strong&gt; so large in the modern world ? Surely because progress of a particular kind is actually taking place around us and is becoming more and more &lt;strong&gt;manifest&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loom / luːm / If something looms over you, it appears as a large or unclear shape, often in a frightening way. 赫然出现;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manifest / ˈmænɪˌfɛst / If you say that something is manifest, you mean that it is clearly true and that nobody would disagree with it if they saw it or considered it. 明显的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although mankind has undergone no general improvement in intelligence or morality, it has made extraordinary progress the accumulation of knowledge. Knowledge began to increase as soon as the thoughts of one individual could be communicated to another by means of speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yyy began to zzz as soon as xxx; 一旦xxx yyy就zzz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by means of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the invention of writing, a great advance was made, for knowledge could then be not only communicated but also stored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for xxx could then be not only yyy but also zzz; xxx不仅能 yyy 而且能zzz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries made education possible, and education in its turn added to libraries: the growth of knowledge followed a kind of compound-interest law, which was greatly enhanced by the invention of printing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in its turn 反过来&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compound interest law 雪球增长的规律&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this was comparatively slow until, with the coming science, the tempo was suddenly raised. Then knowledge began to be accumulated according to a systematic plan. The &lt;strong&gt;trickle&lt;/strong&gt; became a stream; the stream has now become a &lt;strong&gt;torrent&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trickle  / ˈtrɪkəl / When a liquid trickles, or when you trickle it, it flows slowly in a thin stream. 使细流; 细流&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;torrent  / ˈtɒrənt / A torrent is a lot of water falling or flowing rapidly or violently. 急流&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, as soon as new knowledge is acquired, it is now turned to practical account. What is called &amp;lsquo;modern civilization&amp;rsquo; is not the result of a balanced development of all man&amp;rsquo;s nature, but of accumulated knowledge applied to practical life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a balanced development of xxx; xxx的平衡发展&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all man&amp;rsquo;s nature 人的天性&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem now facing humanity is: What is going to be done with all this knowledge ? As is so often pointed out, knowledge is a two-edged weapon which can be used equally for good or evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the problem now facing xxx is yyy; 现在xxx面临的问题是yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now being used indifferently for both. Could any &lt;strong&gt;spectacle&lt;/strong&gt;, for instance, be more grimly &lt;strong&gt;whimsical&lt;/strong&gt; than that of gunners using science to shatter men&amp;rsquo;s bodies while, close at hand, surgeons use it to restore them ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spectacle / ˈspɛktəkəl / A spectacle is a strange or interesting sight. 奇观&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whimsical  / ˈwɪmzɪkəl /  A whimsical person or idea is unusual, playful, and unpredictable, rather than serious and practical. 异想天开的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shatter / ˈʃætə / If something shatters or is shattered, it breaks into a lot of small pieces. 粉碎&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to ask ourselves very seriously what will happen if this twofold use of knowledge, with its ever-increasing
power, continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;twofold  / ˈtuːˌfəʊld / 双重的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ever-increasing 日益增长&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bird-flight&#34;&gt;Bird flight&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No two sorts of birds practise quite the same sort of flight; the varieties are infinite, but two classes may be roughly seen. Any ship that crosses the pacific is accompanied for many days by the smaller &lt;strong&gt;albatross&lt;/strong&gt;, which may keep company with the &lt;strong&gt;vessel&lt;/strong&gt; for an hour without visible or more than occasional movement of wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;albatross  / ˈælbəˌtrɒs / An albatross is a very large white seabird. 信天翁&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vessel  / ˈvɛsəl / A vessel is a ship or large boat. 船; 舰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The currents of air that the walls of the ship direct upwards, as well as in the line of its course are enough to give the great bird with its immense wings sufficient &lt;strong&gt;sustenance&lt;/strong&gt; and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sustenance / ˈsʌstənəns / Sustenance is food or drink which a person, animal, or plant needs to remain alive and healthy. 食物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;albatross&lt;/strong&gt; is the king of the &lt;strong&gt;gliders&lt;/strong&gt;, the class of fliers which &lt;strong&gt;harness&lt;/strong&gt; the air to their purpose, but must yield to its opposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;glider / ˈɡlaɪdə / A glider is an aircraft without an engine, which flies by floating on air currents. 滑翔机&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harness  / ˈhɑːnɪs / If you harness something such as an emotion or natural source of energy, you bring it under your control and use it. 利用&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yield  / jiːld /  If you yield to someone or something, you stop resisting them. 屈服&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the contrary school the duck is supreme. It comes nearer to the engines with which man has &amp;lsquo;conquered&amp;rsquo; the air, as he boasts. Duck, and like them the pigeons, are &lt;strong&gt;endowed&lt;/strong&gt; with steel-like muscles, that are a good part of the weight of the bird, and these will &lt;strong&gt;ply&lt;/strong&gt; the short wings with irresistible power that they can bore for long distances through an opposite &lt;strong&gt;gale&lt;/strong&gt; before exhaustion follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the contrary school 相对的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it comes nearer to xxx；它更近乎于xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;endow  / ɪnˈdaʊ / You say that someone is endowed with a particular desirable ability, characteristic, or possession when they have it by chance or by birth. 天生赋予&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ply  / plaɪ / If you ply someone with food or drink, you keep giving them more of it. 不断供给&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gale  / ɡeɪl / A gale is a very strong wind. 大风&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exhaustion  / ɪɡˈzɔːstʃən / Exhaustion is the state of being so tired that you have no energy left. 精疲力竭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;strong&gt;humbler&lt;/strong&gt; followers, such as partridges, have a like power of strong &lt;strong&gt;propulsion&lt;/strong&gt;, but soon tire. You may pick them up in utter exhaustion, if wind over the sea has driven them to a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;their humbler followers，such as yyy, zzz；次于他们的xxx，yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humble  / ˈhʌmbəl /  People with low social status are sometimes described as humble. (社会地位) 低下的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propulsion  / prəˈpʌlʃən /  Propulsion is the power that moves something, especially a vehicle, in a forward direction. 推进力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utter  / ˈʌtə / You use utter to emphasize that something is great in extent, degree, or amount. 完全的; 彻底的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;swallow&lt;/strong&gt; shares the virtues of both schools in highest measure. It tires not, nor does it boast of its power; but belongs to the air, travelling it may be six thousand miles to and from its northern nesting home, feeding its flown young as it flies and slipping through a medium that seems to help its passage
even when the wind is adverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;swallow / ˈswɒləʊ / A swallow is a kind of small bird with pointed wings and a forked tail. 燕子&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in highest measure 充分的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it xxx not, nor does it yyy； 既不xxx也不xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slip  / slɪp /&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passage  / ˈpæsɪdʒ /  旅程，行程&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such birds do us good, though we no longer take omens from their flight on this side and that, and even the most &lt;strong&gt;superstitious&lt;/strong&gt; villagers no longer take off their hats to the &lt;strong&gt;magpie&lt;/strong&gt; and wish it good-morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;omen  / ˈəʊmən /  If you say that something is an omen, you think it indicates what is likely to happen in the future and whether it will be good or bad. 预兆&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》21</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5421/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 20:44:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5421/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;william-s-hart-and-the-early-western-film&#34;&gt;William S. Hart and the early ‘Western’ film&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William S. Hart was, perhaps, the greatest of all Western stars, for unlike Gary Cooper and John Wayne he appeared in nothing but Westerns. From 1914 to 1924 he was supreme and unchallenged. It was Hart who created the basic formula of the Western film, and devised the protagonist he played in every film he made, the good-bad man, the accidental, noble-&lt;strong&gt;outlaw&lt;/strong&gt;, or the honest-but-framed cowboy, or the &lt;strong&gt;sheriff&lt;/strong&gt; made suspect by vicious gossip; in short, the individual in conflict with himself and his frontier environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protagonist / prəʊˈtæɡənɪst / A protagonist in a play, novel, or real event is one of the main people in it. (戏剧、小说或真实事件里的) 主人公&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outlaw / ˈaʊtˌlɔː /   An outlaw is a criminal who is hiding from the authorities. 逃犯u&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frame  / freɪm /  If someone frames an innocent person, they make other people think that that person is guilty of a crime, by lying or inventing evidence. 诬陷&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sheriff  / ˈʃɛrɪf /   In the United States, a sheriff is a person who is elected to make sure that the law is obeyed in a particular county. (美国的) 县治安官&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vicious  / ˈvɪʃəs / A vicious remark is cruel and intended to upset someone. 恶毒的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nothing but xxx 只在xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made suspect by xxx 被怀疑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike most of his &lt;strong&gt;contemporaries&lt;/strong&gt; in Hollywood, Hart actually knew something of the old West. He had lived in it as a child when it was already disappearing, and his hero was firmly rooted in his memories and experiences, and in both the history and the mythology of the vanished frontier. And although no period or place in American history has been more absurdly romanticized, myth and reality did join hands in at least one &lt;strong&gt;arena&lt;/strong&gt;, the conflict between the individual and &lt;strong&gt;encroaching&lt;/strong&gt; civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contemporary / kənˈtɛmprərɪ / Someone&amp;rsquo;s contemporary is a person who is or was alive at the same time as them. 同时代的人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mythology  / mɪˈθɒlədʒɪ / Mythology is a group of myths, especially all the myths from a particular country, religion, or culture. 神话&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arena  / əˈriːnə /    An arena is a place where sports, entertainments, and other public events take place. It has seats around it where people sit and watch. 竞技场&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encroach  / ɪnˈkrəʊtʃ / If one thing encroaches on another, the first thing spreads or becomes stronger, and slowly begins to restrict the power, range, or effectiveness of the second thing. 逐步侵犯&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;firmly rooted in xxx 深深地扎根&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men accustomed to struggling for survival against the elements and Indian were &lt;strong&gt;bewildered&lt;/strong&gt; by politicians, bankers and business-men, and &lt;strong&gt;unhorsed&lt;/strong&gt; by fences, laws and alien &lt;strong&gt;taboos&lt;/strong&gt;. Hart&amp;rsquo;s good-bad man was always an outsider, always one of the &lt;strong&gt;disinherited&lt;/strong&gt;, and if he found it necessary to shoot a sheriff or rob a bank along the way, his early audiences found it easy to understand and forgive, especially when it was Hart who, in the end, overcame the attacking Indians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bewilder / bɪˈwɪldə / If something bewilders you, it is so confusing or difficult that you cannot understand it. 使迷惑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unhorse  / ʌnˈhɔːs / to knock or throw from a horse 把人推(扔)下马&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taboo  / təˈbuː / A taboo against a subject or activity is a social custom to avoid doing that activity or talking about that subject, because people find them embarrassing or offensive. 禁忌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disinherit  / ˌdɪsɪnˈhɛrɪt / If you disinherit someone such as your son or daughter, you arrange that they will not become the owner of your money and property after your death, usually because they have done something that you do not approve of. 剥夺财产继承权&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audiences in the second decade of the twentieth century found it pleasant to escape to a time when life, though hard, was relatively simple. We still do; living in a world in which undeclared aggression, war, &lt;strong&gt;hypocrisy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;chicanery&lt;/strong&gt;, anarchy and &lt;strong&gt;impending&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;immolation&lt;/strong&gt; are part of our daily lives, we all want a code to live by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hypocrisy  / hɪˈpɒkrəsɪ / If you accuse someone of hypocrisy, you mean that they pretend to have qualities, beliefs, or feelings that they do not really have. 虚伪&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chicanery  / ʃɪˈkeɪnərɪ / Chicanery is using cleverness to cheat people. 耍花招对他人的哄骗&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impending  / ɪmˈpɛndɪŋ / An impending event is one that is going to happen very soon. 即将发生的 [正式]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》20</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5420/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 18:51:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5420/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;snake-poison&#34;&gt;Snake poison&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How it came about that snakes manufactured poison is a mystery. Over the periods their &lt;strong&gt;saliva&lt;/strong&gt;, a mild, digestive juice like our own, was converted into a poison that &lt;strong&gt;defies&lt;/strong&gt; analysis even today. It was not forced upon them by the survival competition; they could have caught and lived on &lt;strong&gt;prey&lt;/strong&gt; without using poison just as the thousands of non-poisonous snakes still do. Poison to a snake is merely a luxury; it enables it to get its food with very little effort, no more effort than one bite. And why only snakes ? Cats, for instance, would be greatly helped; no running fights with large, fierce rats or &lt;strong&gt;tussles&lt;/strong&gt; with grown rabbits- just a bite and no more effort needed. In fact it would be an assistance to all the carnivores&amp;ndash;though it would be a two-edged weapon -When they fought each other. But, of the &lt;strong&gt;vertebrates&lt;/strong&gt;, unpredictable Nature selected only snakes (and one lizard). One wonders also why Nature, with some snakes &lt;strong&gt;concocted&lt;/strong&gt; poison of such extreme &lt;strong&gt;potency&lt;/strong&gt;.
In the conversion of saliva into poison one might suppose that a fixed process took place. It did not; some snakes manufactured a poison different in every respect from that of others, as different as &lt;strong&gt;arsenic&lt;/strong&gt; is from &lt;strong&gt;strychnine&lt;/strong&gt;, and having different effects. One poison acts on the nerves, the other on the blood.
The makers of the nerve poison include the mambas (树眼镜蛇) and the cobras (眼镜蛇) and their &lt;strong&gt;venom&lt;/strong&gt; is called neurotoxic. Vipers (adders) and rattlesnakes (响尾蛇) manufacture the blood poison, which is known as haemolytic. Both poisons are unpleasant, but by far the more unpleasant is the blood poison. It is said that the nerve poison is the more &lt;strong&gt;primitive&lt;/strong&gt; of the two, that the blood poison is , so to speak, a newer product from an improved formula. Be that as it may, the nerve poison does its business with man far more quickly than the blood poison. This,however,means nothing. Snakes did not acquire their poison for use against man but for use against prey such as rats and mice, and the effects on these of &lt;strong&gt;viperine&lt;/strong&gt; poison is almost immediate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saliva / səˈlaɪvə / Saliva is the watery liquid that forms in your mouth and helps you to chew and digest food. 唾液&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defy  / dɪˈfaɪ /  If something defies description or understanding, it is so strange, extreme, or surprising that it is almost impossible to understand or explain. 使不可能 (理解或解释)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prey / preɪ / A creature&amp;rsquo;s prey are the creatures that it hunts and eats in order to live. 猎物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tussle  / ˈtʌsəl /   If one person tussles with another, or if they tussle, they get hold of each other and struggle or fight. 扭打&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carnivore 食肉类&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vertebrate  / ˈvɜːtɪˌbreɪt / A vertebrate is a creature that has a spine. Mammals, birds, reptiles, and fish are vertebrates. 脊椎动物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concoct  / kənˈkɒkt /  If you concoct something, especially something unusual, you make it by mixing several things together. 调制&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potency / ˈpəʊtənsɪ / The potency of a drug, poison, or other chemical is its strength. (毒品、药品等的) 效力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arsenic / ˈɑːsənɪk / Arsenic is a very strong poison that can kill people. 砒霜&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venom  / ˈvɛnəm / The venom of a creature such as a snake or spider is the poison that it puts into your body when it bites or stings you. (蛇或蜘蛛等分泌的) 毒液&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;viper / ˈvaɪpə / A viper is a small poisonous snake found mainly in Europe. 蝰蛇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;primitive  / ˈprɪmɪtɪv / Primitive means belonging to a very early period in the development of an animal or plant. 原始的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how it came about that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over the periods 经过漫长时间&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was converted into xxx 演化成xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx to a xxx is xxx  xxx对xxx来说&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it enables it to xxx 他使得xxx能够xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it would be an assistance to xxx 能够从中受益&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a two-edged weapon 双刃剑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be that as it may 不过&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx,however, xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》18~19</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5418~19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 17:11:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5418~19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;porpoises&#34;&gt;Porpoises&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has long been a &lt;strong&gt;superstition&lt;/strong&gt; among &lt;strong&gt;mariners&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;strong&gt;porpoises&lt;/strong&gt; will save &lt;strong&gt;drowning&lt;/strong&gt; men by pushing them to the surface, or protect them from sharks by surrounding them in defensive formation. Marine Studio biologists have pointed out that, however intelligent they may be, it is probably a mistake to credit dolphins with any motive of life-saving. On the occasions when they have pushed to shore an unconscious human being they have much more likely done it out of curiosity or for sport, as in riding the bow waves of a ship. In 1928 some porpoises were photographed working like &lt;strong&gt;beavers&lt;/strong&gt; to push ashore a waterlogged &lt;strong&gt;mattress&lt;/strong&gt;. If, as has been reported, they have protected humans from sharks, it may have been because curiosity attracted them and because the scent of a possible meal attracted the sharks. Porpoises and sharks are natural enemies. It is possible that upon such an occasion a battle ensued, with the sharks being driven away or killed.
Whether it be bird, fish or beast, the porpoise is &lt;strong&gt;intrigued&lt;/strong&gt; with anything that is alive. They are constantly after the &lt;strong&gt;turtles&lt;/strong&gt;, the Ferdinands of marine life, who peacefully submit to all sorts of &lt;strong&gt;indignities&lt;/strong&gt;. One young &lt;strong&gt;calf&lt;/strong&gt; especially enjoyed raising a &lt;strong&gt;turtle&lt;/strong&gt; to the surface with his &lt;strong&gt;snout&lt;/strong&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;shoving&lt;/strong&gt; him across the tank like an &lt;strong&gt;aquaplane&lt;/strong&gt;. Almost any day a young porpoise may be seen trying to turn a 300-pound sea turtle over by sticking his snout under the edge of his shell and pushing up for dear life. This is not easy, and may require two porpoises working together. In another game, as the turtle swims across the oceanarium, the first porpoise swoops down from above and &lt;strong&gt;butts&lt;/strong&gt; his shell with his belly. This knocks the turtle down several feet. He no sooner recovers his equilibrium than the next porpoise comes along and hits him another &lt;strong&gt;crack&lt;/strong&gt;. Eventually the turtle has been butted all the way down to the floor of the tank. He is now satisfied merely to try to stand up, but as soon as he does so a porpoise knocks him flat. The turtle at last gives up by pulling his feet under his shell and the game
is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;porpoise / ˈpɔːpəs /  A porpoise is a sea animal that looks like a dolphin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;superstition / ˌsuːpəˈstɪʃən / Superstition is belief in things that are not real or possible, for example magic. 迷信&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mariner / ˈmærɪnə /   A mariner is a sailor. 海员; 水手&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drowning / draʊn / If you say that a person or thing is drowning in something, you are emphasizing that they have a very large amount of it, or are completely covered in it. 淹没于&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beaver / ˈbiːvə /  A beaver is a furry animal with a big flat tail and large teeth. Beavers use their teeth to cut wood and build dams in rivers. 海狸&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ashore / əˈʃɔː / Someone or something that comes ashore comes from the sea onto the shore. 到岸上地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mattress / ˈmætrɪs / A mattress is the large, flat object which is put on a bed to make it comfortable to sleep on. 床垫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the scent of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intrigued / ɪˈntriːgd /   If you are intrigued by something, especially something strange, it interests you and you want to know more about it. 感兴趣的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turtle / ˈtɜːtəl /  A turtle is any reptile that has a thick shell around its body, for example a tortoise or terrapin, and can pull its whole body into its shell. 龟&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;indignity / ɪnˈdɪɡnɪtɪ / If you talk about the indignity of doing something, you mean that it makes you feel embarrassed or unimportant. 侮辱&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snout / snaʊt / he snout of an animal such as a pig is its long nose. (动物的)长鼻子&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shove / ʃʌv /  If you shove someone or something, you push them with a quick, violent movement. 猛推&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aquaplane / ˈækwəˌpleɪn /  a single board on which a person stands and is towed by a motorboat at high speed, as in water skiing (由快艇牵引的)滑水板&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oceanarium  / ˌəʊʃəˈnɛərɪəm / a large saltwater aquarium for marine life 大型水族馆&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;swoop / swuːp / If police or soldiers swoop on a place, they go there suddenly and quickly, usually in order to arrest someone or to attack the place. 突袭&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;butt / bʌt / If a person or animal butts you, they hit you with the top of their head. 用头撞&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;there has long been xxx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;xxx have pointed out that xxxx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;xxx for dear life&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-stuff-of-dreams&#34;&gt;The stuff of dreams&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is fairly clear that the sleeping period must have some function, and because there is so much of it the function would seem to be important. Speculations
about its nature have been going on for literally thousands of years, and one odd finding that makes the problem puzzling is that it looks very much as if sleeping is not simply a matter of giving the body a rest.&amp;rsquo; Rest &amp;lsquo;, in terms of muscle relaxation and so on, can be achieved by a brief period lying, or even sitting down. The body&amp;rsquo;s tissues are self-repairing and self-restoring to a degree, and function best when more or less continuously active. In fact a basic amount of movement occurs during sleep which is specifically concerned with preventing muscle inactivity.
If it is not a question of resting the body, then perhaps it is the brain that needs resting? This might be a &lt;strong&gt;plausible&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt; were it not for two factors. First the electroencephalograph (which is simply a device for recording the electrical activity of the brain by attaching electrodes to the &lt;strong&gt;scalp&lt;/strong&gt;) shows that while there is a change in the pattern of activity during sleep, there is no evidence that the total amount of activity is any less. The second factor is more interesting and more fundamental. In l960 an American psychiatrist named William Dement published experiments dealing with the recording of eye-movements during sleep. He showed that the average individual&amp;rsquo;s sleep cycle is &lt;strong&gt;punctuated&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;peculiar&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;bursts&lt;/strong&gt; of eye-movements, some &lt;strong&gt;drifting&lt;/strong&gt; and slow, others jerky and rapid. People woken during these periods of eye-movements generally reported that they had been dreaming. When woken at other times they reported no dreams. If one group of people were disturbed from their eye-movement sleep for several nights on end, and another group were disturbed for an equal period of time but when they were not exhibiting eye-movements, the first group began to show some personality disorders while the others seemed more or less unaffected. The implications of all this were that it was not the disturbance of sleep that mattered, but the disturbance of dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plausible / ˈplɔːzəbəl / An explanation or statement that is plausible seems likely to be true or valid. (解释或叙述) 看似合理的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hypothesis  / haɪˈpɒθɪsɪs / A hypothesis is an idea which is suggested as a possible explanation for a particular situation or condition, but which has not yet been proved to be correct. 假设&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scalp / skælp / Your scalp is the skin under the hair on your head. 头皮&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;punctuate / ˈpʌŋktjʊˌeɪt / If an activity or situation is punctuated by particular things, it is interrupted by them at intervals. 不时打断&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;peculiar  / pɪˈkjuːlɪə / If you describe someone or something as peculiar, you think that they are strange or unusual, sometimes in an unpleasant way. 不寻常的; 古怪的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bursts  / bɜːst / A burst of something is a sudden short period of it. (突然的) 一阵&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;jerky / ˈdʒɜːkɪ / Jerky movements are very sudden and quick, and do not flow smoothly. 急促而不流畅的&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;the stuff of xxx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;it is fairly clear that xxx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;not simply a matter of&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;it was not the xxx that mattered，but the xxx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》16~17</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5416~17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:22:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5416~17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-modern-city&#34;&gt;The modern city&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the organization of industrial life the influence of the factory upon the physiological and mental state of the workers has been completely neglected. Modern industry is based on the conception of the maximum production at lowest cost, in order that an individual or a group of individuals may earn as much money as possible. It has expanded without any idea of the true nature of the human beings who run the machines, and without giving any consideration to the effects produced on the individuals and on their descendants by the artificial mode of existence imposed by the factory. The great cities have been built with no regard for us. The shape and dimensions of the skyscrapers depend entirely on the necessity of obtaining the maximum income per square foot of ground, and of offering to the tenants offices and apartments that please them. This caused the construction of gigantic buildings where too large masses of human beings are crowded together. Civilized men like such a way of living. While they enjoy the comfort and *&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;banal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;* luxury of their dwelling, they do not realize that they are deprived of the necessities of life. The modern city consists of &lt;strong&gt;monstrous&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;edifices&lt;/strong&gt; and of dark, narrow streets full of petrol &lt;strong&gt;fumes&lt;/strong&gt;, coal dust, and toxic gases, &lt;strong&gt;torn&lt;/strong&gt; by the noise of the taxi-cabs, lorries and buses, and &lt;strong&gt;thronged&lt;/strong&gt; ceaselessly by great crowds. Obviously, it has no been planned for the good of its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx is based on the conception of yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zzz, in order that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;without any idea of the xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;without giving any consideration to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;depend entirely on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this caused xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;banal / bəˈnɑːl, -ˈnæl /  If you describe something as banal, you do not like it because you think it is so ordinary that it is not at all effective or interesting. 平庸乏味的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monstrous / ˈmɒnstrəs / If you describe an unpleasant thing as monstrous, you mean that it is extremely large in size or extent. (令人不悦的事物) 巨大的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edifice / ˈɛdɪfɪs /   An edifice is a large and impressive building. 大厦&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fume / fjuːm / Fumes are the unpleasant and often unhealthy smoke and gases that are produced by fires or by things such as chemicals, fuel, or cooking. (难闻且常有害的) 烟气&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lorry  / ˈlɒrɪ / A lorry is a large vehicle that is used to transport goods by road. 卡车&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;throng  / θrɒŋ /  When people throng somewhere, they go there in great numbers. (人群) 涌向&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ceaselessly 不停地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the good of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-man-made-disease&#34;&gt;A man-made disease&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of the settlement of Australia, enterprising settlers unwisely introduced the European rabbit. This rabbit had no natural enemies in the &lt;strong&gt;Antipodes&lt;/strong&gt;, so that it multiplied with that &lt;strong&gt;promiscuous&lt;/strong&gt; abandon characteristic of rabbits. It overran a whole continent. It caused devastation by &lt;strong&gt;burrowing&lt;/strong&gt; and by devouring the &lt;strong&gt;herbage&lt;/strong&gt; which might have maintained millions of sheep and cattle. Scientists discovered that this particular variety of rabbit (and apparently no other animal) was susceptible to a fatal virus disease, &lt;strong&gt;myxomatosis&lt;/strong&gt;. By infecting animals and letting them loose in the burrows, local epidemics of this disease could be created. Later it was found that there was a type of mosquito which acted as the carrier of this disease and passed it on to the rabbits. So while the rest of the world was trying to get rid of mosquitoes, Australia was encouraging this one. It effectively spread the disease all over the continent and drastically reduced the rabbit population. lt later became apparent that rabbits were developing a degree of resistance to this disease, so that the rabbit population was unlikely to be completely exterminated. There were hopes, however, that the problem of the rabbit would become manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ironically&lt;/strong&gt;, Europe, which had &lt;strong&gt;bequeathed&lt;/strong&gt; the rabbit as a pest to Australia acquired this man-made disease as a &lt;strong&gt;pestilence&lt;/strong&gt;. A French physician decided to get rid of the wild rabbits on his own estate and introduced &lt;strong&gt;myxomatosis&lt;/strong&gt;. It did not, however, remain within the confines of his estate. It spread through France where wild rabbits are not generally regarded as a pest but as a sport and a useful food supply, and it spread to Britain where wild rabbits are regarded as a pest but where domesticated rabbits, equally susceptible to the disease, are the basis of a profitable fur industry. The question became one of whether Man could control the disease he had invented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it overran xx 蔓延&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enterprising  / ˈɛntəˌpraɪzɪŋ /  An enterprising person is willing to try out new, unusual ways of doing or achieving something. 有开拓精神的; 有创新精神的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settler / ˈsɛtlə, ˈsɛtəl- / Settlers are people who go to live in a new country. 移民者&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;promiscuous / prəˈmɪskjʊəs /  Someone who is promiscuous has sex with many different people. 淫乱的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;burrow  / ˈbʌrəʊ / If an animal burrows into the ground or into a surface, it moves through it by making a tunnel or hole. 掘地洞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exterminate / ɪkˈstɜːmɪˌneɪt / To exterminate a group of people or animals means to kill all of them. 消灭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;herbage / ˈhɜːbɪdʒ /  草本的总称&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx discovered that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;later it was found that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it effectively 动词 xxxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is unlikely to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ironically / aɪˈrɒnɪkəlɪ /  You use ironically to draw attention to a situation that is odd or amusing because it involves a contrast. 具有讽刺意味的是&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bequeath / bɪˈkwiːð / If you bequeath your money or property to someone, you legally state that they should have it when you die. 遗赠&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pestilence  / ˈpɛstɪləns /  Pestilence is any disease that spreads quickly and kills large numbers of people. 瘟疫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;physician / fɪˈzɪʃən / A physician is a medical doctor. 内科医生&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;domesticate  / dəˈmɛstɪˌkeɪt / When people domesticate wild animals or plants, they bring them under control and use them to produce food or as pets. 驯养; 引种驯化&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》13~15</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5413~15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5413~15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-search-for-oil&#34;&gt;The search for oil&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deepest holes of all are made for oil, and they go down to as much as 25,000 feet. But we do not need to send men down to get the oil out, as we must with other mineral &lt;strong&gt;deposits&lt;/strong&gt;. The holes are only &lt;strong&gt;borings&lt;/strong&gt;, less than a foot in &lt;strong&gt;diameter&lt;/strong&gt;. My particular experience is largely in oil, and the search for oil has done more to improve deep drilling than any other mining activity. When it has been decided where we are going to drill, we &lt;strong&gt;put up&lt;/strong&gt; at the surface an oil &lt;strong&gt;derrick&lt;/strong&gt;. It has to be tall because it is like a giant block and tackle, and we have to lower into the ground and &lt;strong&gt;haul&lt;/strong&gt; out of the ground great lengths of drill pipe which are rotated by an engine at the top and are &lt;strong&gt;fitted&lt;/strong&gt; with a cutting &lt;strong&gt;bit&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The geologist needs to know what rocks the drill has reached, so &lt;strong&gt;every so often&lt;/strong&gt; a sample is obtained with a &lt;strong&gt;coring&lt;/strong&gt; bit. It cuts a clean &lt;strong&gt;cylinder&lt;/strong&gt; of rock, from which can be seen the &lt;strong&gt;strata&lt;/strong&gt; the drill has been cutting through. Once we get down to the oil, it usually flows to the surface because great pressure, either from gas or water, is pushing it. This pressure must be under control, and we control it &lt;strong&gt;by means of&lt;/strong&gt; the mud which we circulate down the drill pipe. We &lt;strong&gt;endeavour to&lt;/strong&gt; avoid the old, romantic idea of a &lt;strong&gt;gusher&lt;/strong&gt;, which wastes oil and gas. We want it to stay down the hole until we can lead it off &lt;strong&gt;in a&lt;/strong&gt; controlled &lt;strong&gt;manner&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deposit / dɪˈpɒzɪt / A deposit is an amount of a substance that has been left somewhere as a result of a chemical or geological process. 沉积物; 矿床&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boring / ˈbɔːrɪŋ / the act or process of making or enlarging a hole 钻孔; 扩洞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diameter / daɪˈæmɪtə / The diameter of a round object is the length of a straight line that can be drawn across it, passing through the middle of it. 直径&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put up: If people put up a wall, building, tent, or other structure, they construct it so that it is upright. 建造&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;derrick / ˈdɛrɪk / A derrick is a tower built over an oil well which is used to raise and lower the drill. 油井塔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;haul / hɔːl / If you haul something which is heavy or difficult to move, you move it using a lot of effort. (用力地) 拉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fitted: If you fit something somewhere, you attach it there, or put it there carefully and securely. 安装&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every so often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cylinder  / ˈsɪlɪndə / A cylinder is an object with flat circular ends and long straight sides. 圆柱&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strata /&amp;lsquo;strætɚ/ are different layers of rock. 岩层&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by means of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;endeavour / ɪnˈdɛvə / If you endeavour to do something, you try very hard to do it. 努力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gusher  / ˈɡʌʃə /  喷油井&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx has done more to improve zzz than any other yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-butterfly-effect&#34;&gt;The Butterfly Effect&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond two or three days, the world’s best weather forecasts are speculative, and beyond six or seven they are worthless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Butterfly Effect is the reason. For small pieces of weather—and to a global forecaster, small can mean thunderstorms and &lt;strong&gt;blizzards&lt;/strong&gt; – any prediction deteriorates rapidly. Errors and uncertainties multiply, cascading upward through a chain of &lt;strong&gt;turbulent&lt;/strong&gt; features, from dust devils and &lt;strong&gt;squalls&lt;/strong&gt; up to continent-size &lt;strong&gt;eddies&lt;/strong&gt; that only satellites can see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern weather models work with a grid of points of the order of sixty miles apart, and even so, some starting data has to be guessed, since ground stations and satellites cannot see everywhere. But suppose the earth could be covered with sensors spaced one foot apart, rising at one-foot intervals all the way to to top of the atmosphere. Suppose every sensor gives perfectly accurate readings of temperature, pressure, humidity, and any other quantity a &lt;strong&gt;meteorologist&lt;/strong&gt; would want. Precisely at noon an infinitely powerful computer takes all the data and calculates what will happen at each point at 12.01, then 12.02, then 12.03&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computer will still be unable to predict whether Princeton, New Jersey, will have sun or rain on a day one month away. At noon the spaces between the sensors will hide fluctuations that the computer will not know about, tiny deviations from the average. By 12.01, those fluctuations will already have created small errors one foot away. Soon the errors will have multiplied to the ten-foot scale, and so on up to the size of the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blizzard / ˈblɪzəd / A blizzard is a very bad snowstorm with strong winds. 暴风雪&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cascade / kæsˈkeɪd / If water cascades somewhere, it pours or flows downward very fast and in large quantities. 倾泻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turbulent  / ˈtɜːbjʊlənt /    Turbulent water or air contains strong currents which change direction suddenly. (水流或气体) 湍急的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dust devil: a strong miniature whirlwind that whips up dust, litter, leaves, etc into the air 尘暴&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squall / skwɔːl / A squall is a sudden strong wind which often causes a brief, violent rainstorm or snowstorm. 飑; 突起的狂风(常引起短暂暴雨或暴雪)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eddy /&amp;lsquo;ɛdi/ 漩涡&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meteorologist /ˌmitiəˈrɑlədʒɪst/ 气象学家&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of the order of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppose xxx could be xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;secrecy-in-industry&#34;&gt;Secrecy in industry&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two factors weigh heavily against the effectiveness of scientific in industry. One is the general atmosphere of secrecy in which it is carried out, the other the lack of freedom of the individual research worker. In so far as any inquiry is a secret one, it naturally limits all those engaged in carrying it out from effective contact with their fellow scientists either in other countries or in universities, or even , often enough , in other departments of the same firm. The degree of secrecy naturally &lt;strong&gt;varies considerably&lt;/strong&gt;. Some of the bigger firms are engaged in researches which are of such general and fundamental nature that it is a positive advantage to them not to keep them secret. Yet a great many processes depending on such research are sought for with complete secrecy until the stage at which patents can be taken out. Even more processes are never patented at all but kept as secret processes. This applies particularly to chemical industries, where chance discoveries play a much larger part than they do in physical and mechanical industries. Sometimes the secrecy goes to such an extent that the whole nature of the research cannot be mentioned. Many firms, for instance, have great difficulty in obtaining technical or scientific books from libraries because they are unwilling to have their names entered as having taken out such and such a book for fear the agents of other firms should be able to trace the kind of research they are likely to be undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx either in xxx or in xxx, or even in xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;event xxx are never yyy at all but&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this applies particularly to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes xxx goes to such a extent that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx, for instance, xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》10~12</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5410~12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 23:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5410~12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;silicon-valley&#34;&gt;Silicon valley&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology trends may push Silicon Valley &lt;strong&gt;back&lt;/strong&gt; to the future. Carver Mead, a pioneer in integrated circuits and a professor of computer science at the California Institute of Technology, notes there are now workstations that enable engineers to design, test and produce chips right on their desks, &lt;strong&gt;much the way&lt;/strong&gt; an editor creates a newsletter on a Macintosh. As the time and cost of making a chip &lt;strong&gt;drop&lt;/strong&gt; to a few days and a few hundred dollars, engineers may soon be free to let their imaginations soar without being penalized by expensive failures. Mead predicts that inventors will be able to perfect powerful customized chips over a weekend at the office—spawning a new generation of garage start-ups and &lt;strong&gt;giving&lt;/strong&gt; the U.S. &lt;strong&gt;a jump on its&lt;/strong&gt; foreign rivals in &lt;strong&gt;getting&lt;/strong&gt; new products &lt;strong&gt;to&lt;/strong&gt; market fast. ‘We’ve got more garages with smart people,’ Mead observes. ‘We really &lt;strong&gt;thrive&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;anarchy&lt;/strong&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on Asians. Already, orientals and Asian Americans &lt;strong&gt;constitute&lt;/strong&gt; the majority of the engineering staffs at many Valley firms. And Chinese, Korean, Filipino and Indian engineers are graduating in &lt;strong&gt;droves&lt;/strong&gt; from California’s colleges. As &lt;strong&gt;the heads of&lt;/strong&gt; next-generation start-ups, these Asian innovators can &lt;strong&gt;draw on&lt;/strong&gt; customs and languages to &lt;strong&gt;forge&lt;/strong&gt; tighter links with crucial Pacific &lt;strong&gt;Rim&lt;/strong&gt; market. For instance, Alex Au, a Stanford Ph.D. from Hong Kong, has set up a Taiwan factory to challenge Japan’s near &lt;strong&gt;lock on&lt;/strong&gt; the memory-chip market. India-born N. Damodar Reddy’s tiny California company reopened an AT&amp;amp;T chip plant in Kansas City last spring with financing from the state of Missouri. Before it becomes a retirement village, Silicon Valley may &lt;strong&gt;prove&lt;/strong&gt; a classroom for building a global business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;much the way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drop / drɒp / If a level or amount drops or if someone or something drops it, it quickly becomes less. 使迅速下降; 迅速下降&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thrive  / θraɪv / If you say that someone thrives on a particular situation, you mean that they enjoy it or that they can deal with it very well, especially when other people find it unpleasant or difficult. 喜欢; 从容应对 (尤指别人不喜欢或认为困难的事)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anarchy / ˈænəkɪ /  If you describe a situation as anarchy, you mean that nobody seems to be paying any attention to rules or laws. 无政府状态&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constitute / ˈkɒnstɪˌtjuːt / If something constitutes a particular thing, it can be regarded as being that thing. 构成&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drove  / drəʊv / a herd of livestock being driven together (被驱赶着一起前进的)畜群&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;draw on If you draw on or draw upon something such as your skill or experience, you make use of it in order to do something. 利用&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forge / fɔːdʒ /  If one person or institution forges an agreement or relationship with another, they create it with a lot of hard work, hoping that it will be strong or lasting. 努力地缔造&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rim  / rɪm / The rim of a circular object is its outside edge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lock on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prove  / pruːv / If something proves to be true or to have a particular quality, it becomes clear after a period of time that it is true or has that quality. 证明是&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-grow-old&#34;&gt;How to grow old&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some old people are &lt;strong&gt;oppressed&lt;/strong&gt; by the fear of death. In the young there is a justification for this feeling. Young men who have reason to fear that they will be killed in battle may &lt;strong&gt;justifiably&lt;/strong&gt; feel bitter in the thought that they have been cheated of the best things that life has to offer. But in an old man who has known human joys and sorrows, and has achieved whatever work it was in him to do, the fear of death is somewhat &lt;strong&gt;abject&lt;/strong&gt; and ignoble. The best way to overcome it-so at least it seems to me&amp;mdash;-is to make your interests gradually wider and more &lt;strong&gt;impersonal&lt;/strong&gt;, until bit by bit the walls of the &lt;strong&gt;ego&lt;/strong&gt; recede, and your life becomes increasingly merged in the universal life. An individual human &lt;strong&gt;existence&lt;/strong&gt; should be like a river&amp;ndash;small at first, narrowly contained within its banks, and rushing passionately past &lt;strong&gt;boulders&lt;/strong&gt; and over waterfalls. Gradually the river grows wider, the banks recede, the waters flow more quietly, and in the end, without any visible break, they become merged in the sea, and painlessly lose their individual being. The man who, in old age, can see his life in this way, will not suffer from the fear of death, since the things he cares for will continue. And it, with the decay of &lt;strong&gt;vitality&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;weariness&lt;/strong&gt; increases, the thought of rest will be not unwelcome. I should wish to die while still at work, knowing that others will carry on what I can no longer do, and content in the thought that what was possible has been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grow old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oppress / əˈprɛs / To oppress people means to treat them cruelly, or to prevent them from having the same opportunities, freedom, and benefits as others. 压迫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;justification / ˌdʒʌstɪfɪˈkeɪʃən / A justification for something is an acceptable reason or explanation for it. 正当的理由&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abject  / ˈæbdʒɛkt /  You use abject to emphasize that a situation or quality is extremely bad. 糟糕透顶的 [强调]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impersonal  / ɪmˈpɜːsənəl /  If you describe someone&amp;rsquo;s behaviour as impersonal, you mean that they do not show any emotion about the person they are dealing with. 不受个人感情影响的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ego  / ˈiːɡəʊ, ˈɛgəʊ / Someone&amp;rsquo;s ego is their sense of their own worth. For example, if someone has a large ego, they think they are very important and valuable. 自我价值感&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vitality / vaɪˈtælɪtɪ /   If you say that someone or something has vitality, you mean that they have great energy and liveliness. 活力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;weariness /&amp;lsquo;wɪrɪnɪs/ temporary loss of strength and energy resulting from hard physical or mental work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boulder  / ˈbəʊldə /  A boulder is a large rounded rock. 圆形巨石&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content / ˈkɒntɛnt / If you are content, you are fairly happy or satisfied. 满意的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;banks-and-their-customers&#34;&gt;Banks and their customers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When anyone opens a current account at a bank, he is lending the bank money, repayment of which he may demand at any time, either in cash or by &lt;strong&gt;drawing a cheque&lt;/strong&gt; in favour of another person. Primarily, the banker-customer relationship is that of debtor and creditor&amp;ndash;who is which depending on whether the customer&amp;rsquo;s account is &lt;strong&gt;in credit&lt;/strong&gt; or is overdrawn. But, in addition to that basically simple concept, the bank and its customer owe a large number of obligations to one another. Many of these obligations can give rise to problems and complications but a bank customer, unlike, say, a buyer of goods, cannot complain that the law is &lt;strong&gt;loaded against&lt;/strong&gt; him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank must obey its customer&amp;rsquo;s instructions, and not those of anyone else. When, for example, a customer first opens an account, he instructs the bank to debit his account only in respect of cheques drawn by himself. He gives the bank &lt;strong&gt;specimens&lt;/strong&gt; of his signature, and there is a very firm rule that the bank has no right or authority to pay out a customer&amp;rsquo;s money on a cheque on which its customer&amp;rsquo;s signature has been forged. It makes no difference that the &lt;strong&gt;forgery&lt;/strong&gt; may have been a very skilful one: the bank must recognize its customer&amp;rsquo;s signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason there is no risk to the customer in the modern practice, adopted by some banks, of printing the customer&amp;rsquo;s name on his cheques. If this facilitates forgery it is the bank which will lose, not the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repayment  / rɪˈpeɪmənt / The repayment of money is the act or process of paying it back to the person you owe it to. 偿还&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in favour of 受益人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;primarily / ˈpraɪmərəlɪ / You use primarily to say what is mainly true in a particular situation. 主要地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in credit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;debit  / ˈdɛbɪt / A debit is a record of the money taken from your bank account, for example, when you write a cheque. 借方&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loaded / ˈləʊdɪd / If you say that something is loaded in favour of someone, you mean it works unfairly to their advantage. If you say it is loaded against them, you mean it works unfairly to their disadvantage. 有偏向的 [表不满]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in respect of concerning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;specimen / ˈspɛsɪmɪn / A specimen of something is an example of it which gives an idea of what the whole of it is like. 样本&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forge / fɔːdʒ / If someone forges something such as paper money, a document, or a painting, they copy it or make it so that it looks genuine, in order to deceive people. 伪造 (纸币、文件或画作等)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the practice of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complication  / ˌkɒmplɪˈkeɪʃən / A complication is a problem or difficulty that makes a situation harder to deal with. 使情况复杂化的因素&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》7~9</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B547~9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 19:12:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B547~9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;bats&#34;&gt;Bats&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all sounds made by animals &lt;strong&gt;serve as&lt;/strong&gt; language, and we have only to turn to that extraordinary discovery of echo-location in bats to see a case in which the voice plays a strictly &lt;strong&gt;utilitarian&lt;/strong&gt; role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a full appreciation of what this means we must turn first to some recent human inventions. Everyone knows that if he shouts in the &lt;strong&gt;vicinity&lt;/strong&gt; of a wall or a mountainside, an echo will come back. The further off this solid &lt;strong&gt;obstruction&lt;/strong&gt; the longer time will &lt;strong&gt;elapse&lt;/strong&gt; for the return of the echo. A sound made by tapping on the &lt;strong&gt;hull&lt;/strong&gt; of a ship will be reflected from the sea bottom, and by measuring the time interval between the taps and the receipt of the echoes the depth of the sea at that point can be calculated. So was born the echo-sounding &lt;strong&gt;apparatus&lt;/strong&gt;, now in general use in ships. Every solid object will reflect a sound, varying according to the size and nature of the object. A &lt;strong&gt;shoal&lt;/strong&gt; of fish will do this. So it is a &lt;strong&gt;comparatively&lt;/strong&gt; simple step from locating the sea bottom to locating a shoal of fish. With experience, and with improved apparatus, it is now possible not only to locate a shoal but to tell if it is &lt;strong&gt;herring&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cod&lt;/strong&gt;, or other well-known fish, by the pattern of its echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago it was found that certain bats &lt;strong&gt;emit&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;squeaks&lt;/strong&gt; and by receiving the echoes they could locate and &lt;strong&gt;steer&lt;/strong&gt; clear of obstacles&amp;ndash;or locate flying insects on which they feed. This echo-location in bats is often compared with radar, the principle of which is similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utilitarian  / juːˌtɪlɪˈtɛərɪən / objects and buildings are designed to be useful rather than attractive. (物体、建筑等) 实用的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vicinity / vɪˈsɪnɪtɪ / If something is in the vicinity of a particular place, it is near it. (在…) 附近&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elapse / ɪˈlæps /  When time elapses, it passes. (时间) 流逝&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tap / tæp / If you tap something, you hit it with a quick light blow or a series of quick light blows. 轻敲&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apparatus / ˌæpəˈreɪtəs / the equipment, such as tools and machines, which is used to do a particular job or activity. 设备&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shoal / ʃəʊl / A shoal of fish is a large group of them swimming together. 鱼群&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;herring  / ˈhɛrɪŋ /  A herring is a long silver-coloured fish. Herring live in large groups in the ocean. 鲱 (鱼)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cod / kɒd / Cod are a type of large edible fish. 鳕鱼&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emit  / ɪˈmɪt / To emit a sound or noise means to produce it. 发出 (声音或噪音)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squeak / skwiːk / If something or someone squeaks, they make a short, high-pitched sound. 发出短而尖的声音&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;steer / stɪə / If you steer clear of someone or something, you deliberately avoid them. 有意避开某人/某物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;trading-standards&#34;&gt;Trading standards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chickens &lt;strong&gt;slaughtered&lt;/strong&gt; in the United States, claim officials in Brussels, are not fit to &lt;strong&gt;grace&lt;/strong&gt; European tables. No, say the Americans: our &lt;strong&gt;fowl&lt;/strong&gt; are fine, we simply clean them in a different way. These days, it is differences in national regulations, far more than tariffs, that put sand in the wheels of trade between rich countries. It is not just farmers who are complaining . An electric &lt;strong&gt;razor&lt;/strong&gt; that meets the European Union’s safety standards must be approved by American testers before it can be sold in the United States, and an American-made &lt;strong&gt;dialysis&lt;/strong&gt; machine needs the EU’s okay before it &lt;strong&gt;hits&lt;/strong&gt; the market in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, a razor that is safe in Europe is unlikely to &lt;strong&gt;electrocute&lt;/strong&gt; Americans. So, ask businesses on both sides of the Atlantic, why have two lots of tests where one would do? Politicians agree, in principle, so America and the EU have been trying to reach a deal which would eliminate the need to double-test many products. They hope to finish in time for a trade summit between America and EU on May 28th. Although negotiators are optimistic, the details are complex enough that they may be &lt;strong&gt;hard-pressed&lt;/strong&gt; to get a deal at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? One difficulty is to construct the agreements. The Americans would happily reach one accord on standards for medical devices and then &lt;strong&gt;hammer&lt;/strong&gt; out different pacts covering, say, electronic goods and drug manufacturing. The EU-following fine &lt;strong&gt;continental&lt;/strong&gt; traditions—wants agreement on general principles, which could be applied to many types of products and have extended to other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slaughter / ˈslɔːtə / If large numbers of people or animals are slaughtered, they are killed in a way that is cruel or unnecessary. 屠杀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grace / ɡreɪs / If you say that something graces a place or a person, you mean that it makes them more attractive. 使优美&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fowl  / faʊl / A fowl is a bird, especially one that can be eaten as food, such as a duck or a chicken. 家禽&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;razor / ˈreɪzə / A razor is a tool that people use for shaving. 剃刀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dialysis / daɪˈælɪsɪs /   Dialysis or kidney dialysis is a method of treating kidney failure by using a machine to remove waste material from the kidneys. (肾的)透析&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;electrocute  / ɪˈlɛktrəˌkjuːt /  If someone is electrocuted, they are accidentally killed or badly injured when they touch something connected to a source of electricity. 使…触电 (死亡或受伤)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hammer If people hammer out an agreement or treaty, they succeed in producing it after a long or difficult discussion. (经过长时间或艰难的讨论) 制定出&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continental  / ˌkɒntɪˈnɛntəl / Continental is used to refer to something that belongs to or relates to a continent. 大陆的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;royal-espionage&#34;&gt;Royal &lt;strong&gt;espionage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfred the Great acted as his own spy, visiting Danish camps disguised as a &lt;strong&gt;minstrel&lt;/strong&gt;. In those days wandering minstrels were welcome everywhere. They were not fighting men, and their &lt;strong&gt;harp&lt;/strong&gt; was their passport. Alfred had learned many of their &lt;strong&gt;ballads&lt;/strong&gt; in his youth, and could vary his programme with &lt;strong&gt;acrobatic&lt;/strong&gt; tricks and simple &lt;strong&gt;conjuring&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Alfred&amp;rsquo;s little army slowly began to gather at Athelney, the king himself set out to &lt;strong&gt;penetrate&lt;/strong&gt; the camp of Guthrum, the commander of the Danish invaders. These had &lt;strong&gt;settled down&lt;/strong&gt; for the winter at Chippenham: &lt;strong&gt;thither&lt;/strong&gt; Alfred went. He noticed at once that discipline was slack: the Danes had the self-confidence of &lt;strong&gt;conquerors&lt;/strong&gt;, and their security precautions were casual. They lived well, on the &lt;strong&gt;proceeds&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;raids&lt;/strong&gt; on neighbouring regions. There they collected women as well as food and drink, and &lt;strong&gt;a life of ease&lt;/strong&gt; had made them soft. Alfred stayed in the camp a week before he returned to Athelney. The force there assembled was trivial compared with the Danish &lt;strong&gt;horde&lt;/strong&gt;. But Alfred had deduced that the Danes were no longer fit for prolonged battle : and that their &lt;strong&gt;commissariat&lt;/strong&gt; had no organization, but depended on irregular raids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, faced with the Danish &lt;strong&gt;advance&lt;/strong&gt;, Alfred did not risk open battle but &lt;strong&gt;harried&lt;/strong&gt; the enemy. He was constantly on the move, drawing the Danes after him. His &lt;strong&gt;patrols&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;halted&lt;/strong&gt; the raiding parties: hunger &lt;strong&gt;assailed&lt;/strong&gt; the Danish army. Now Alfred began a long series of &lt;strong&gt;skirmishes&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;and within a month the Danes had surrendered. The episode could reasonably serve as a unique &lt;strong&gt;epic&lt;/strong&gt; of royal espionage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;espionage / ˈɛspɪəˌnɑːʒ /  Espionage is the activity of finding out the political, military, or industrial secrets of your enemies or rivals by using spies. 间谍活动&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minstrel / ˈmɪnstrəl /  a minstrel was a singer and musician who travelled around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harp / hɑːp / You play the harp by plucking the strings with your fingers. 竖琴&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ballad / ˈbæləd / A ballad is a long song or poem which tells a story in simple language. 叙事歌; 民间叙事诗&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acrobatic / ˈækrəˌbætɪk / An acrobatic movement or display involves difficult physical acts such as jumping and balancing, especially in a circus. 杂技的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conjuring  / ˈkʌndʒərɪŋ /  the performance of tricks that appear to defy natural laws 魔术&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;penetrate / ˈpɛnɪˌtreɪt / If something or someone penetrates a physical object or an area, they succeed in getting into it or passing through it. 进入; 穿透&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proceeds /&amp;lsquo;prosidz/ The proceeds of an event or activity are the money that has been obtained from it. (某事件或活动带来的) 收入&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;raid / reɪd / When soldiers raid a place, they make a sudden armed attack against it, with the aim of causing damage rather than occupying any of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s land. 突袭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;horde / hɔːd / If you describe a crowd of people as a horde, you mean that the crowd is very large and excited and, often, rather frightening or unpleasant. (通常指熙攘纷扰的) 一大群人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commissariat  / ˌkɒmɪˈsɛərɪət / a government department before 1946 (前苏联)1946年前的政府部门 (Now called ministry)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harry / ˈhærɪ / If someone harries you, they keep bothering you or trying to get something from you. (不断)骚扰; 纠缠&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patrol / pəˈtrəʊl / When soldiers, police, or guards patrol an area or building, they move around it in order to make sure that there is no trouble there. 在…巡逻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;halt / hɔːlt /  When a person or a vehicle halts or when something halts them, they stop moving in the direction they were going and stand still. 使停住; 停住&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assail  / əˈseɪl / If someone assails you, they attack you violently. 攻击&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skirmish  / ˈskɜːmɪʃ / A skirmish is a minor battle. 小规模战斗; 小冲突&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;epic / ˈɛpɪk / An epic is a long book, poem, or film whose story extends over a long period of time or tells of great events. 史诗; 史诗般的作品&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》4~6</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B544~6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 22:45:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B544~6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lesson-4-seeing-hands&#34;&gt;Lesson 4 Seeing hands&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Soviet Union several cases have been reported recently of people who can read and detect colours with their fingers, and even &lt;strong&gt;see through&lt;/strong&gt; solid doors and walls. One case &lt;strong&gt;concerns&lt;/strong&gt; an &amp;lsquo;eleven-year-old schoolgirl, Vera Petrova, who has normal vision but who can also &lt;strong&gt;perceive&lt;/strong&gt; things with different parts of her skin, and through solid walls. This ability was first noticed by her father. One day she came into his office and &lt;strong&gt;happened&lt;/strong&gt; to put her hands on the door of a locked safe. Suddenly she asked her father why he kept so many old newspapers locked away there, and even described the way they were &lt;strong&gt;done up&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;bundles&lt;/strong&gt;. Vera&amp;rsquo;s curious talent was brought to the notice of a scientific research institute in the town of UIyanovsk, near where she lives, and in April she was given a series of tests by a special &lt;strong&gt;commission&lt;/strong&gt; of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federal Republic. During these tests she was able to read a newspaper through an opaque screen and, stranger still, by moving her elbow over a child&amp;rsquo;s game of Lotto she was able to describe the figures and colours printed on it; and, in another instance, wearing stockings and slippers, to &lt;strong&gt;make out&lt;/strong&gt; with her foot the outlines and colours of a picture hidden under a &lt;strong&gt;carpet&lt;/strong&gt;. Other experiments showed that her knees and shoulders had a similar sensitivity. During all these tests Vera was &lt;strong&gt;blindfold&lt;/strong&gt;; and, indeed, except when blindfold she lacked the ability to perceive things with her skin. lt was also found that although she could perceive things with her fingers this ability ceased the moment her hands were wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concern: /kənˈsɚn/ to relate to (something or someone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perceive /pɚˈsiːv/ to notice or become aware of (something)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;happen: /ˈhæpən/ to do or be something by chance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do up:  to wrap (something).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bundle: /ˈbʌndəl/ a group of things that are fastened, tied, or wrapped together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commission: /kəˈmɪʃən/ a group of people who have been given the official job of finding information about something or controlling something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make out: to see and identify (something)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carpet: /ˈkɑɚpət/ a thick covering : a thick layer of something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blindfold: /ˈblaɪndˌfoʊld/ cover the eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;lesson-5-youth&#34;&gt;Lesson 5 Youth&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are always talking about &amp;lsquo;the problem of youth&amp;rsquo;. If there is one&amp;ndash;which I take leave to doubt&amp;ndash;then it is older people who create it, not the young themselves. Let us &lt;strong&gt;get down to&lt;/strong&gt; fundamentals and agree that the young are after all human beings&amp;ndash;people just like their elders. There is only one difference between an old man and a young one: the young man has a glorious future before him and the old one has a splendid future behind him: and maybe that is where the &lt;strong&gt;rub&lt;/strong&gt; is.
When I was a teenager, I felt that I was just young and uncertain&amp;ndash;that I was a new boy in a huge school, and I would have been very pleased to be regarded as something so interesting as a problem. For one thing, being a problem gives you a certain identity, and that is one of the things the young are busily engaged in seeking.
I find young people exciting. They have an air of freedom, and they have not a &lt;strong&gt;dreary&lt;/strong&gt; commitment to mean ambitions or love of comfort. They are not anxious social climbers, and they have &lt;strong&gt;no devotion to&lt;/strong&gt; material things. All this seems to me to link them with life, and the origins of things. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they were in some sense cosmic beings in &lt;strong&gt;violent&lt;/strong&gt; and lovely contrast with us &lt;strong&gt;suburban&lt;/strong&gt; creatures. All that is in my mind when I meet a young person. He may be &lt;strong&gt;conceited&lt;/strong&gt;, ill-mannered, &lt;strong&gt;presumptuous&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;fatuous&lt;/strong&gt;, but I do not turn for protection to &lt;strong&gt;dreary&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;clichés&lt;/strong&gt; about respect for elders&amp;ndash;as if mere age were a reason for respect. I accept that we are equals, and I will argue with him, as an equal, if I think he is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get down to: to start doing something that is difficult or needs a lot of time or energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rub: /ˈrʌb/ something that causes a difficulty or problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dreary: /ˈdriri/ dull and making you feel sad or bored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;violent: /ˈvajələnt/ very forceful or intense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;suburban: /səˈbɚbən/ boring and typical of people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conceited: /kənˈsiːtəd/ having or showing too much pride in your own worth or goodness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;presumptuous: /prɪˈzʌmptʃuəs/ doing something that you have no right to do and that seems rude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fatuous: /ˈfætʃuəs/ very silly or stupid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clichés: an idea or phrase that has been used so much that it is not effective or does not have any meaning any longer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;lesson-6-the-sporting-spirit&#34;&gt;Lesson 6 The sporting spirit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am always amazed when I hear people saying that sport creates &lt;strong&gt;goodwill&lt;/strong&gt; between the nations, and that if only the common peoples of the world could meet one another at football or cricket, they would have no &lt;strong&gt;inclination&lt;/strong&gt; to meet on the battlefield. Even if one didn&amp;rsquo;t know from concrete examples (the 1936 Olympic Games, for instance) that international sporting contests lead to &lt;strong&gt;orgies&lt;/strong&gt; of hatred, one could &lt;strong&gt;deduce&lt;/strong&gt; it from general principles. Nearly all the sports practised nowadays are competitive. You play to win, and the game has little meaning unless you do your utmost to win. On the village green, where you &lt;strong&gt;pick up sides&lt;/strong&gt; and no feeling of local &lt;strong&gt;patriotism&lt;/strong&gt; is involved, it is possible to play simply for the fun and exercise: but as soon as the question of &lt;strong&gt;prestige&lt;/strong&gt; arises, as soon as you feel that you and some larger unit will be &lt;strong&gt;disgraced&lt;/strong&gt; if you lose, the most &lt;strong&gt;savage&lt;/strong&gt; combative instincts are &lt;strong&gt;aroused&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyone who has played even in a school football match knows this. At the international level sport is frankly mimic &lt;strong&gt;warfare&lt;/strong&gt;. But the significant thing is not the behaviour of the players but the attitude of the &lt;strong&gt;spectators&lt;/strong&gt;: and, behind the spectators, of the nations who work themselves into &lt;strong&gt;furies&lt;/strong&gt; over these &lt;strong&gt;absurd&lt;/strong&gt; contests, and seriously believe&amp;ndash;&lt;strong&gt;at any rate&lt;/strong&gt; for short periods&amp;ndash;that running, jumping and kicking a ball are tests of national &lt;strong&gt;virtue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goodwill: /ˌgʊdˈwɪl/ a kind, helpful, or friendly feeling or attitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inclination: /ˌɪnkləˈneɪʃən/  a feeling of wanting to do something : a tendency to do something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;orgy: /ˈoɚʤi/ something that is done too much and in a wild way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deduce: /dɪˈduːs/ to use logic or reason to form (a conclusion or opinion about something)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;side: a sports team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prestige: /prɛˈstiːʒ/ the respect and admiration that someone or something gets for being successful or important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disgrace: /dɪˈskreɪs/ to cause (someone) to feel ashamed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;savage: /ˈsævɪʤ/ very cruel or violent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arouse: /əˈraʊz/ to cause (an emotional or mental state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;warfare: /ˈwoɚˌfeɚ/ military fighting in a war&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spectator: someone who is watching an event or game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fury: /ˈfjuri/ violent anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;absurd: /əbˈsɚd/ extremely silly, foolish, or unreasonable : completely ridiculous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at any rate: anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;virtue: /ˈvɚtʃu/ morally good behavior or character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》1~3</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B541~3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 18:44:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B541~3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;finding-fossil-man&#34;&gt;Finding Fossil man&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can &lt;strong&gt;read of&lt;/strong&gt; things that happened 5,000 years ago in the Near East, where people first learned to write. But there are some parts of the world where even now people cannot write. The only way that they can preserve their history is to &lt;strong&gt;recount&lt;/strong&gt; it as sagas&amp;ndash;legends &lt;strong&gt;handed down&lt;/strong&gt; from one generation of story-tellers to another. These legends are useful because they can tell us something about migrations of people who lived long ago, but none could write down what they did. &lt;strong&gt;Anthropologists&lt;/strong&gt; wondered where the remote ancestors of the Polynesian (波利尼西亚人) peoples now living in the Pacific Islands (太平洋群岛) came from. The sagas of these people explain that some of them came from Indonesia (印度尼西亚) about 2,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the first people who were like ourselves lived so long ago that even their sagas, if they had any, are forgotten. So &lt;strong&gt;archaeologists&lt;/strong&gt; have neither history nor legends to help them to find out where the first &amp;lsquo;modern men&amp;rsquo; came from. Fortunately, however, ancient men made tools of stone, especially &lt;strong&gt;flint&lt;/strong&gt;, because this is easier to shape than other kinds. They may also have used wood and skins, but these have &lt;strong&gt;rotted away&lt;/strong&gt;. Stone does not decay, and so the tools of long ago have remained when even the bones of the men who made them have disappeared without trace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recount: /rɪˈkaʊnt/ to tell someone about (something that happened).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saga: /ˈsɑːgə/ a long and complicated story with many details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hand down: to pass (something) from a person who is older (such as a parent) to a person who is younger (such as a child).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anthropologist: /ˌænθrəˈpɑːləʤi/ the study of human races, origins, societies, and cultures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;archaeologist: /ˌɑɚkiˈɑːləʤi/  a science that deals with past human life and activities by studying the bones, tools, etc., of ancient people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flint: /ˈflɪnt/ a hard type of rock that produces a small piece of burning material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;句型&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way that &amp;hellip; is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These &amp;hellip; are useful because &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sth explain that &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spare-that-spider&#34;&gt;Spare that spider&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, you may wonder, should spiders be our friends ? Because they destroy so many insects, and insects include some of the greatest enemies of the human race. Insects would make it impossible for us to live in the world; they would &lt;strong&gt;devour&lt;/strong&gt; all our crops and kill our flocks and herds, if it were not for the protection we get from insect-eating animals. We owe a lot to the birds and beasts who eat insects but all of them put together kill only &lt;strong&gt;a fraction of&lt;/strong&gt; the number destroyed by spiders. Moreover, unlike some of the other insect eaters, spiders never do the least harm to us or our belongings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiders are not insects, as many people think, nor even nearly related to them. One can tell the difference almost at a glance for a spider always has eight legs and an insect never more than six.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many spiders &lt;strong&gt;are engaged in&lt;/strong&gt; this work on our behalf ? One authority on spiders made a census of the spiders in a grass field in the south of England, and he estimated that there were more than 2,250,000 in one &lt;strong&gt;acre&lt;/strong&gt;, that is something like 6,000,000 spiders of different kinds on a football &lt;strong&gt;pitch&lt;/strong&gt;. Spiders are busy for at least half the year in killing insects. It is impossible to make more than the wildest guess at how many they kill, but they are hungry creatures, not content with only three meals a day. It has been estimated that the weight of all the insects destroyed by spiders in Britain in one year would be greater than the total weight of all the human beings in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spare: /ˈspeɚ/ to not destroy or harm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;devour: /dɪˈvawɚ/  to destroy (something) completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a fraction of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be engaged in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pitch: /ˈpɪtʃ/ an area that is used for playing sports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;句型&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has been estimated that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;matterhorn-马特洪峰-man&#34;&gt;Matterhorn (马特洪峰) man&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern &lt;strong&gt;alpinists&lt;/strong&gt; try to climb mountains by a route which will give them good sport, and the more difficult it is, the more highly it is regarded. In the pioneering days, however, this was not the case at all. The early climbers were looking for the easiest way to the top because the summit was the prize they sought, especially if it had never been attained before. It is true that during their explorations they often faced difficulties and dangers of the most perilous nature, equipped in a manner which would make a modern climber &lt;strong&gt;shudder&lt;/strong&gt; at the thought, but they did not go out of their way to court such excitement. They had a single aim, a solitary goal&amp;ndash;the top!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard for us to realize nowadays how difficult it was for the pioneers. &lt;strong&gt;Except for&lt;/strong&gt; one or two places such as Zermatt (策马特) and Chamonix (夏蒙尼), which had rapidly become popular, Alpine (阿尔卑斯山的) villages tended to be &lt;strong&gt;impoverished settlements&lt;/strong&gt; cut off from civilization by the high mountains. Such &lt;strong&gt;inns&lt;/strong&gt; as there were were generally dirty and &lt;strong&gt;flea-ridden&lt;/strong&gt;; the food simply local cheese accompanied by bread often twelve months old, all washed down with coarse wine. Often a valley boasted no inn at all, and climbers found shelter wherever they could&amp;ndash;sometimes with the local priest (who was usually as poor as his parishioners), sometimes with shepherds or cheesemakers. Invariably the background was the same: dirt and poverty, and very uncomfortable. For men accustomed to eating seven-course dinners and sleeping between fine &lt;strong&gt;linen&lt;/strong&gt; sheets at home, the change to the Alps must have been very hard indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alpinist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shudder: /ˈʃʌdɚ/ to shake because of fear, cold, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;except for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impoverish: /ɪmˈpɑːvərɪʃ/ poor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settlement: /ˈsɛtl̟mənt/ a place where people have come to live and where few or no people lived before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cut off + from: to be separate or alone: They are cut off from (contact with) the outside world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flea: /ˈfliː/ a very small insect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ridden: /ˈrɪdn̩/ filled with or containing something unpleasant or unwanted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boast: /ˈboʊst/ to have (something that is impressive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;linen: /ˈlɪnən/ a smooth, strong cloth made from flax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》塔尔火山喷发</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E5%A1%94%E5%B0%94%E7%81%AB%E5%B1%B1%E5%96%B7%E5%8F%91/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 23:56:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E5%A1%94%E5%B0%94%E7%81%AB%E5%B1%B1%E5%96%B7%E5%8F%91/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly two weeks after Taal volcano’s first eruption in over 40 years, the Philippines Institute of Volcanology and Seismology has lowered its threat assessment a &lt;strong&gt;notch&lt;/strong&gt;(等级), and local residents have begun to &lt;strong&gt;stream&lt;/strong&gt;(流动) back to their homes in &lt;strong&gt;jeepneys&lt;/strong&gt;(吉普车), pickups and on the backs of motorcycles. When Taal &lt;strong&gt;roared&lt;/strong&gt;(咆哮) to life on January 12th, the &lt;strong&gt;plume&lt;/strong&gt;(飘升之物) of steam and ash it sent 32,000 feet into the air was so vast it generated its own weather system, with thunder and lightning. As the falling &lt;strong&gt;cinders&lt;/strong&gt;(煤渣) turned day to night, tens of thousands of evacuees &lt;strong&gt;fled for&lt;/strong&gt; hastily created evacuation centres a safe distance from Taal’s &lt;strong&gt;spite&lt;/strong&gt;(怨恨).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, Taal is a draw. The volcano has made its own island in the middle of Taal lake, which occupies the &lt;strong&gt;caldera&lt;/strong&gt;(火山喷口) of a much bigger volcano which exploded &lt;strong&gt;aeons&lt;/strong&gt;(极漫长的时期) ago. The surrounding slopes are forested. Papayas and vegetables thrive on village plots by the shore. The lake itself provides livelihoods to those farming tilapia fish. More jobs come from catering to visitors from Manila who &lt;strong&gt;flock&lt;/strong&gt;(聚集) to the lake, or to the resort town of Tagatay on an overlooking ridge, for the fresh air, sweeping views and grilled fish. The country’s capital is just two hours’ drive to the north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet these times are hardly usual. The eruption seems to have caused a lot of the lake’s water to &lt;strong&gt;evaporate&lt;/strong&gt;(蒸发). One part of the lake, though, is now a metre deeper, since the whole &lt;strong&gt;caldera&lt;/strong&gt; has tilted sharply. Taal’s ash has turned a vast area a &lt;strong&gt;monotone&lt;/strong&gt;(单调的) grey. Rain following the eruption has hardened the ash to concrete. The tin roofs of villagers’ houses have &lt;strong&gt;buckled&lt;/strong&gt;(使弯曲变形), trees have lost their main branches and the tomatoes and &lt;strong&gt;aubergines&lt;/strong&gt;(茄子) in Rosa’s garden have &lt;strong&gt;shrivelled&lt;/strong&gt;(枯萎) to nothing. But life is nothing if not, well, &lt;strong&gt;pigheaded&lt;/strong&gt;(顽固的). Rosa says she and her husband, a retired soldier, had no choice but to stay, despite the loss of electricity and water: Biggie, their sow, was about to &lt;strong&gt;farrow&lt;/strong&gt;(一窝小猪). Fourteen &lt;strong&gt;piglets&lt;/strong&gt; now &lt;strong&gt;snuffle&lt;/strong&gt;(抽鼻子) around their mother. Girlie, from one of the worst-hit villages on the west side of the lake, cries with joy to find that the food she left out for her family’s dog and kitten have sustained them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repair teams from the electricity board, villagers &lt;strong&gt;chipping&lt;/strong&gt; the ash off roofs and even young scientists returning to their lakeside observatory in Talisay to get the solar panels for their sensors working again—life has a &lt;strong&gt;yen&lt;/strong&gt;(渴望) for normality, too. Not the volcano, however. The earthquakes following the eruption have fallen in number and &lt;strong&gt;severity&lt;/strong&gt;(严重), and an alarming build-up of &lt;strong&gt;magma&lt;/strong&gt;(岩浆) appears to have diminished. But that, says Paolo Reniva, a geologist, says little about how the volcano will behave in future. He expects Taal’s current cycle of activity to last months or years. At the back of all the geologists’ minds is the eruption of 1754. That blast had the force of a nuclear bomb, and the &lt;strong&gt;jargon&lt;/strong&gt;(术语) they use to describe it is similar: “ballistic projectiles” fell over seven kilometres away; the “base surge”, a mixture of gas and fragments moving at up to 100m a second, reached up to 20km away. No one died from the direct effects of the eruption on January 12th; a 1754-style explosion, in contrast, would be catastrophic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not what those trying to resume their lives want to hear. The current threat assessment of 3 on a scale of 0 to 5 risks being viewed as normal by locals. And just as President Donald Trump &lt;strong&gt;downplays&lt;/strong&gt;(轻视) climate change, so populist Filipino politicians downplay nature’s forces. President Rodrigo Duterte promised evacuees he would “pee on that damned volcano”. The vice-mayor of Talisay, Charlie Natanauan, a local businessman who is campaigning to &lt;strong&gt;unseat&lt;/strong&gt;(剥夺…的席位) the mayor (his brother, as it happens), goes further by urging locals not to believe the “idiot” scientists. Taal is not going to explode again, he insists, because he knows its history; if he’s wrong, he adds, then throw him into the &lt;strong&gt;crater&lt;/strong&gt;. What’s more, the scientists’ warnings about poisoned &lt;strong&gt;tilapia&lt;/strong&gt;(罗非鱼) are off-the-mark too, and he will eat as many fish as needed to prove it. It &lt;strong&gt;goes down&lt;/strong&gt; a storm with locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting on a &lt;strong&gt;veranda&lt;/strong&gt;(走廊) by the lake, next to a gold-painted statue of himself &lt;strong&gt;toting&lt;/strong&gt;(携带) a &lt;strong&gt;rifle&lt;/strong&gt;(步枪) and &lt;strong&gt;pistol&lt;/strong&gt;(手枪), Mr Natanauan lays out his plans. They include a &lt;strong&gt;canal&lt;/strong&gt;(运河) cutting through to the sea so that luxury yachts can travel up it; modernist glass resorts; and firework shows to put any eruption to shame. How, Banyan asks, do his ideas fit with the volcano’s even more sweeping and &lt;strong&gt;whimsical&lt;/strong&gt;(古怪的) plans? Pah, Mr Natanauan says &lt;strong&gt;dismissively&lt;/strong&gt;(轻蔑), the next time Taal causes trouble, we’ll all be dead. Behind him, dozens of dead tilapia float &lt;strong&gt;upside down&lt;/strong&gt;(倒置地), slapping against his &lt;strong&gt;jetty&lt;/strong&gt;(码头). Just beyond, the volcano gently steams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notch: /ˈnɑːtʃ/ a slightly higher or lower level in a series of levels that measure something. e.g., Turn the radio up/down a notch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stream: /ˈstriːm/ a continuous flow of people or things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;roar: /ˈroɚ/ to make a long, loud sound. e.g., The fans were roaring [=yelling and cheering loudly] after their team scored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plume: /ˈpluːm/ something (such as smoke, steam, or water) that rises into the air in a tall, thin shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spite: /ˈspaɪt/ a desire to harm, anger, or defeat another person especially because you feel that you have been treated wrongly in some way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cinder: /ˈsɪndɚ/ a very small piece of burned material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flock: /ˈflɑːk/  to gather or move in a crowd. e.g., Thousands of people flocked to the beach each weekend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evaporate: /ɪˈvæpəˌreɪt/ to change from a liquid into a gas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monotone: /ˈmɑːnəˌtoʊn/ a way of talking or singing without raising or lowering the sound of your voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buckle: /ˈbʌkəl/ to cause (something) to bend or collapse. e.g., Heat buckled the pavement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pigheaded: /ˈpɪgˌhɛdəd/ very stubborn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snuffle: /ˈsnʌfəl/ to breathe loudly because you have a cold or have been crying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chipping: /ˈtʃɪp/ to break off a small piece from (something).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yen: /ˈjɛn/ a strong desire for something or to do something. e.g., I had a yen [=craving] for spicy food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jargon: /ˈʤɑɚgən/ the language used for a particular activity or by a particular group of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;downplay: /ˈdaʊnˌpleɪ/ to make (something) seem smaller or less important. e.g., She downplayed [=played down] her role in the research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unseat: /ˌʌnˈsiːt/ to remove (someone or something) from a position of power or authority. e.g., He unseated an incumbent senator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;crater: /ˈkreɪtɚ/ the area on top of a volcano that is shaped like a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;veranda: /vəˈrændə/ a long, open structure on the outside of a building that has a roof.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rifle: /ˈraɪfəl/ a gun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tote: /ˈtoʊt/ to carry (something). e.g., She&amp;rsquo;s been toting that bag all day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pistol: /ˈpɪstl̟/ a small gun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;canal: /kəˈnæl/ a long narrow place that is filled with water and was created by people so that boats could pass through it or to supply fields, crops, etc., with water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whimsical: /ˈwɪmzɪkəl/ unusual in a playful or amusing way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dismissive: /dɪsˈmɪsɪv/ showing that you do not think something or someone is worth thinking about or considering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jetty: /ˈʤɛti/ a long structure that is built out into water and used as a place to get on, get off, or tie up a boat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upside down: /ˈʌpˌsaɪdˈdaʊn/ with the top at the bottom and the bottom at the top : placed so that the end that should be at the top is at the bottom. e.g., You hung the picture upside down!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》印度东北部的和平发展</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E5%8D%B0%E5%BA%A6%E4%B8%9C%E5%8C%97%E9%83%A8%E7%9A%84%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B3%E5%8F%91%E5%B1%95/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 11:13:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E5%8D%B0%E5%BA%A6%E4%B8%9C%E5%8C%97%E9%83%A8%E7%9A%84%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B3%E5%8F%91%E5%B1%95/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-restive-难驾驭的-corner-of-india-is-becoming-more-peaceful&#34;&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;restive&lt;/strong&gt;(难驾驭的) corner of India is becoming more peaceful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But for every group that is &lt;strong&gt;placated&lt;/strong&gt;(抚慰) there are new &lt;strong&gt;malcontents&lt;/strong&gt;(不满者)”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to divide India into administrative units is a question that has &lt;strong&gt;vexed&lt;/strong&gt;(使烦恼) all its governments. For a time the main focus was to rationalise, as hundreds of &lt;strong&gt;feudal&lt;/strong&gt;(封建制度的) “princely” states were &lt;strong&gt;swept into&lt;/strong&gt; the bigger provinces of the Indian republic. But since 1960 the number of states and territories has been rising, as different groups have successfully lobbied for their own unit, on the basis of language, &lt;strong&gt;ethnicity&lt;/strong&gt;(种族划分) or administrative convenience. There were 20 in 1956; now there are 36.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few areas have seen as much &lt;strong&gt;upheaval&lt;/strong&gt;(动乱) as the north-east, an ethnically mixed region of 50m people that was almost cut off from the rest of the country by the creation of East Pakistan (now Bangladesh) in 1947. It began as a single state, Assam, plus two &lt;strong&gt;principalities&lt;/strong&gt;(侯国), Manipur and Tripura. It has since &lt;strong&gt;splintered&lt;/strong&gt;(分裂) into seven states, as Arunachal Pradesh, Meghalaya, Mizoram and Nagaland have been &lt;strong&gt;hived&lt;/strong&gt; off(脱离) Assam (see map). The region is still &lt;strong&gt;replete&lt;/strong&gt;(充满的) with &lt;strong&gt;disgruntled&lt;/strong&gt;(不满的) factions(派别), however: it has spawned more than 125 &lt;strong&gt;insurgencies&lt;/strong&gt;(叛乱) since the 1950s. Their varied struggles for statehood, independence or simply to &lt;strong&gt;clobber&lt;/strong&gt;(击倒) rival groups—many of these micro-conflicts have &lt;strong&gt;pitted&lt;/strong&gt;(使竞争) “natives” against migrants—have left perhaps 40,000 dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only recently have years of patient &lt;strong&gt;carrot&lt;/strong&gt;-and-stick efforts by the central government, helped by better intelligence, tougher military tactics and stronger co-operation from neighbouring Bangladesh and Myanmar, begun to pay off. &lt;strong&gt;Casualties&lt;/strong&gt;(意外事故) have declined steeply, from a high of almost 1,700 deaths in 2000 to just 17 last year. That has allowed the government to exempt some states from a controversial law that protects soldiers from prosecution for human-rights offences, and prompted the army to begin shifting resources away from internal security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underpinning all this has been a series of peace agreements with assorted &lt;strong&gt;rebel&lt;/strong&gt; groups. Ongoing talks with insurgents in Nagaland have made significant progress, with at least one of the state’s main &lt;strong&gt;guerrilla&lt;/strong&gt;(游击战) factions agreeing to lay down arms. In Assam some 644 fighters from various groups recently surrendered their guns. And in January alone Mr Modi’s government &lt;strong&gt;inked&lt;/strong&gt;(签署) two important deals. One, in Tripura, allows for the resettlement in the state of some 34,000 ethnic Bru refugees from neighbouring Mizoram. This should end a 23-year stand-off, as the &lt;strong&gt;destitute&lt;/strong&gt;(穷困的) Brus had rejected efforts to send them back to areas from which they had been violently expelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of bigger import is a deal signed on January 27th with several factions of the National Democratic Front of Bodoland. For Bodos, who speak a language related to Tibetan and Burmese and who number some 1.3m, the terms look generous. In exchange for some 1,500 rebels laying down arms, the Bodos will get a &lt;strong&gt;sweeping&lt;/strong&gt;(规模大的) &lt;strong&gt;amnesty&lt;/strong&gt;(大赦), an extra $225m in government funding, more schools, colleges and sports facilities, and a much fuller form of autonomy within their homeland in the western part of Assam, along India’s border with Bhutan. What is more, the boundaries of Bodoland will be redrawn, village by village, to ensure Bodos form a majority within it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deal is also good for Mr Modi. Government sources reckon the Bodo insurgency has left some 4,000 dead since 1987, including 88 killed in a series of bomb blasts in the state capital, Guwahati, in 2008. The violence also rendered tens of thousands of non-Bodos homeless as waves of refugees fled repeated &lt;strong&gt;massacres&lt;/strong&gt;(大屠杀) that targeted Bengali-speaking Muslim farmers in the &lt;strong&gt;floodplains&lt;/strong&gt; of the Brahmaputra River and rival &lt;strong&gt;tribal&lt;/strong&gt;(部落的) groups in the hills. Aside from putting a stop to such &lt;strong&gt;mayhem&lt;/strong&gt;(骚乱), the deal will almost certainly prompt a large vote swing among the small but influential Bodo community towards Mr Modi’s Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP). Its hold in Assam has weakened in recent months due to protests against a controversial new citizenship law. With state elections looming in 2021, the BJP is resorting to “vote-bank” politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the Bodoland deal is clearly not so good for non-Bodos who, despite the insurgents’ efforts at ethnic cleansing, constitute up to two-thirds of the population of the Bodoland region as currently defined. Naba Kumar Sarania, who represents the region in the national parliament, told the Hindu newspaper: “We are not against the peace process, but this &lt;strong&gt;accord&lt;/strong&gt;(协议) has ignored the interests of the other ethnic communities in the area.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restive: feeling bored or impatient while waiting for something to happen or change. e.g., a restive audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;placate: to cause (someone) to feel less angry about something. e.g., The angry customer was not placated by the clerk&amp;rsquo;s apology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vex: to annoy or worry (someone). e.g., We were vexed by the delay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sweep into: to move something into something or some place by sweeping. e.g., He swept the crumbs into the dish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upheaval: a major change or period of change that causes a lot of conflict, confusion, anger, etc. e.g., a period of cultural and social upheavals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;splinter: to break (something) into small pieces or splinters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hive off: to separate (someone or something) from a group. e.g., They hived off the youngest campers into another room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;replete: having much or plenty of something : filled with something. e.g., he book is replete with photographs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;insurgency: a usually violent attempt to take control of a government : a rebellion or uprising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clobber: to hit (someone) very hard. e.g., Some guy was clobbering [=beating] him in the parking lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pit against: to cause (someone or something) to fight or compete against (another person or thing). e.g., Tonight&amp;rsquo;s game will pit Smith against Johnson for the championship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casualty: a person who is hurt or killed during an accident, war, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ink: to sign (a document). e.g., They just inked a new partnership agreement/deal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;destitute: extremely poor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sweeping: including or involving many things : wide in range or amount. e.g., sweeping changes/reforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;massacre: the violent killing of many people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;accord: a formal or official agreement. e.g., a peace accord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mayhem: a scene or situation that involves a lot of violence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》泰国的儿童拳击应该被禁止吗</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%B3%B0%E5%9B%BD%E7%9A%84%E5%84%BF%E7%AB%A5%E6%8B%B3%E5%87%BB%E5%BA%94%E8%AF%A5%E8%A2%AB%E7%A6%81%E6%AD%A2%E5%90%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 10:02:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%B3%B0%E5%9B%BD%E7%9A%84%E5%84%BF%E7%AB%A5%E6%8B%B3%E5%87%BB%E5%BA%94%E8%AF%A5%E8%A2%AB%E7%A6%81%E6%AD%A2%E5%90%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;despite-a-tragedy-the-authorities-allow-children-to-compete-in-a-violent-sport&#34;&gt;Despite a tragedy, the authorities allow children to compete in a violent sport&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The death of Anucha Thasako was supposed to change everything. After several sharp &lt;strong&gt;blows&lt;/strong&gt;(猛击) to the head during a Thai boxing &lt;strong&gt;bout&lt;/strong&gt;(回合) in 2018, the &lt;strong&gt;scrawny&lt;/strong&gt;(骨瘦如柴的) 13-year-old fell to the floor, unconscious. The referee rushed to his side, to no &lt;strong&gt;avail&lt;/strong&gt;(效用). There was no doctor in attendance. Anucha died soon afterwards from a brain &lt;strong&gt;haemorrhage&lt;/strong&gt;(出血). He had been boxing since the age of eight, and had taken part in around 170 fights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;footage&lt;/strong&gt;(影片) of the deadly bout, which circulated widely on social media, stirred &lt;strong&gt;uproar&lt;/strong&gt;(骚动). The government, which had anyway been considering restrictions on child boxing, pledged to rush through a bill to ban children under 12 from participating in formal competitions and to &lt;strong&gt;oblige&lt;/strong&gt;(迫使) those between 12 and 15 to wear protective headgear. But the plan quickly &lt;strong&gt;lost steam&lt;/strong&gt;(夭折).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants and fans protested loudly, arguing that the only way to prepare for a career in Thai boxing or muay thai, which dates to at least the 18th century, is to start young. Eliminate child boxing, they argued, and the whole sport would &lt;strong&gt;atrophy&lt;/strong&gt;(萎缩). The government no longer talks of tightening the rules for young boxers. Gongsak Yodmani, the head of the Sports Authority of Thailand, describes child boxing as standard practice. The authority’s official &lt;strong&gt;tally&lt;/strong&gt;(记录) shows only 635 boxers below the age of 15, although others put the number of children who train and compete informally as high as 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some children, boxing is a route out of poverty. Those participating in public fights earn 300-500 baht ($10-16) a bout when they are starting out, says Samart Payakaroon of the Muay Thai Naiyhanomtom Association, a lobby group. Professional boxers can earn thousands of dollars a match. Muay thai “is a very honourable way to escape poverty”, says Chatri Sityodtong, the founder of One Championship, a martial-arts promoter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But doctors say that blows to the head from “the art of eight &lt;strong&gt;limbs&lt;/strong&gt;(四肢)”, which involves punching, kicking, kneeing and elbowing, may &lt;strong&gt;stunt&lt;/strong&gt;(阻碍…的正常生长或发展) children’s development and increase the risk of Parkinson’s and Alzheimer’s. A study from Mahidol University found that boxers under the age of 15 had lower IQs than average; those who had been fighting the longest were furthest behind. The study’s lead author, Jiraporn Laothamatas, considers putting children in the &lt;strong&gt;ring&lt;/strong&gt;(环形竞技场) a form of child abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One force helping sustain the sport, underage bouts included, is tourism. The Tourism Authority of Thailand energetically promotes muay thai. Foreigners tend to &lt;strong&gt;snap&lt;/strong&gt; up(抢购) the most expensive seats in the biggest stadiums, looking for a slice of Thai life. Many may not realise how young some of the fighters they are watching are—although the weight categories should give them an &lt;strong&gt;inkling&lt;/strong&gt;(暗示). Anucha was competing in the under-41kg division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blow: a hard hit using a part of the body or an object. e.g., The two boxers exchanged blows. [=hit each other].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bout: a wrestling or boxing contest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrawny: very thin in a way that is not attractive or healthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avail: help toward reaching a goal. e.g., Our best efforts were of no avail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;footage: scenes or action recorded on film or video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uproar: a situation in which many people are upset, angry, or disturbed by something. e.g., The proposal caused an uproar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oblige: to force or require (someone or something) to do something. e.g., Her job obliges her to work overtime and on weekends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lose steam: to lose strength, force, or energy : to slow down. e.g., Sales have lost steam in recent weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;atrophy: to become weak from lack of use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tally: a recorded count of scores, votes, etc. e.g., What is the final tally?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limb:  a leg or arm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stunt: to stop (someone or something) from growing or developing. e.g., Too many restrictions have stunted the economy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ring: an area that is used for shows and contests and is usually surrounded by ropes or a fence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snap up: to buy or take (something or someone) quickly or eagerly. e.g., Shoppers came to the store to snap up bargains after the holidays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inkling: a slight, uncertain idea about something. e.g., Nothing gave me any inkling that it would happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》东南亚经济特区为中国创造了财富</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E4%BA%9A%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E7%89%B9%E5%8C%BA%E4%B8%BA%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%9B%E9%80%A0%E4%BA%86%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:07:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E4%BA%9A%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E7%89%B9%E5%8C%BA%E4%B8%BA%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%9B%E9%80%A0%E4%BA%86%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-influx-of-investment-and-workers-is-creating-chinese-enclaves&#34;&gt;An influx of investment and workers is creating Chinese enclaves&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a remote part of northern Laos, the bamboo forest gives way to cranes. A city is being carved out of jungle: tower blocks &lt;strong&gt;cloaked&lt;/strong&gt;(遮掩) in &lt;strong&gt;scaffolding&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;loom&lt;/strong&gt;(赫然耸现) over restaurants, &lt;strong&gt;karaoke&lt;/strong&gt;卡拉OK bars and massage &lt;strong&gt;parlours&lt;/strong&gt;(客厅). The beating heart of Golden Triangle Special Economic Zone (so called because it sits at the point where Laos, Myanmar and Thailand converge) is the &lt;strong&gt;casino&lt;/strong&gt;(赌场), a &lt;strong&gt;palatial&lt;/strong&gt;(宏伟的) &lt;strong&gt;confection&lt;/strong&gt;(糖果) featuring faux-Roman statuary and &lt;strong&gt;ceilings&lt;/strong&gt;(天花板) covered in &lt;strong&gt;frescoes&lt;/strong&gt;(壁画). “Laos Vegas” does not cater to Laotians, however. Croupiers accept only Chinese yuan or Thai baht. Street signs are in Chinese and English. The city’s clocks are set to Chinese time, an hour ahead of the rest of Laos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, China has become one of the biggest investors in South-East Asian countries: in 2018 it was the source of nearly $80\%$ of foreign direct investment in Laos. Some of this capital is flowing along well-worn routes to places like Mandalay, a city in Myanmar where there is a long-established Chinese community. But much of it is flooding into “special economic zones” (SEZs) to take advantage of &lt;strong&gt;assorted&lt;/strong&gt;(各种各样的) incentives such as faster permitting, reduced tax or duties and looser controls on the movements of goods and capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese businesses don’t need much convincing. The Chinese government began encouraging them to invest abroad in the 2000s. The Belt and Road Initiative, China’s giant scheme to develop infrastructure abroad, has accelerated the trend. In addition to railways, highways and pipelines, it promotes SEZs, which “are now a preferred mode of economic expansion for China”, says Brian Eyler of the Stimson Centre, an American think-tank. Under the &lt;strong&gt;banner&lt;/strong&gt;(标语) of belt and road, 160 Chinese companies have poured more than $\$1.5$bn into SEZs in Laos, according to Land Watch Thai, a watchdog. Between 2016 and 2018 China invested $\$1$bn in one SEZ alone: Sihanoukville, a city on Cambodia’s coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where Chinese capital goes, labour follows. In Mandalay the Chinese have swelled from $1\%$ of the population in 1983 to $30\%-50\%$ today. In places with SEZs the shift has been even sharper. In 2019 the governor of the surrounding province told the Straits Times newspaper that the number of Chinese in Sihanoukville had soared over the previous two years to almost a third of the population. The economic &lt;strong&gt;clout&lt;/strong&gt;(影响力) of Chinese migrants grows with their numbers. In Mandalay $80\%$ of hotels, more than $70\%$ of restaurants and $45\%$ of jewellery shops are owned and operated by ethnic Chinese, according to market research conducted in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;influx&lt;/strong&gt;(流入) of migrants has fuelled anti-Chinese sentiment across the region. But poor South-East Asian governments court(设法获得) Chinese investors anyway because they hope Chinese money will kick-start their economies. In some respects the investment has &lt;strong&gt;borne&lt;/strong&gt;(结果实) fruit. In Laos foreign investment has contributed to &lt;strong&gt;effervescent&lt;/strong&gt;(冒泡的) GDP growth, which averaged $7.7\%$ a year over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in a study of SEZs in 2017 Focus on the Global South, a think-tank headquartered in Bangkok, concluded that the “legislative and governance structures” &lt;strong&gt;underpinning&lt;/strong&gt;(支撑 ) SEZs in Cambodia and Myanmar “have been &lt;strong&gt;skewed&lt;/strong&gt;(偏离) toward the interests of investors and against those of locals and the environment”. Alfredo Perdiguero of the Asian Development Bank agrees that SEZs in Laos, Cambodia and Myanmar “have not yet been able to spread the benefits” to the broader economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part this is because Chinese companies tend not to hire locals. By 2018 Laotian workers had secured just $34\%$ of the jobs created by all 11 SEZs in Laos—a far cry from the $90\%$ the government had promised. Chinese firms argue that local workers lack skills, but civil society groups in Myanmar respond by pointing to a technical college near Kyaukpyu, a Chinese-inspired SEZ and port; nobody from the college has been hired to work there, according to a report published last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is little local sourcing of other inputs, either. The &lt;strong&gt;garment&lt;/strong&gt;(衣服) factories of Sihanoukville SEZ, for instance, import their cloth, buttons and thread. The Chinese workers and visitors in South-East Asia’s SEZs often &lt;strong&gt;patronise&lt;/strong&gt;(光顾) Chinese-owned shops and restaurants, and circumvent sales taxes by paying for goods and services via Chinese apps like Alipay. “The money doesn’t even leave China essentially,” says Sebastian Strangio, author of a forthcoming book on China’s growing influence in South-East Asia. That, along with the tax breaks, mean there is little benefit for host governments: in 2017 the Laotian &lt;strong&gt;exchequer&lt;/strong&gt;(国库) raised just $\$20$m from its SEZs—less than $1\%$ of its revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterritorial-不受管辖的-and-unreasonable&#34;&gt;Extraterritorial(不受管辖的) and unreasonable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is common with big developments in the poorer countries of South-East Asia, locals are seldom consulted about the construction of SEZs. Golden Triangle SEZ was built over the rice &lt;strong&gt;paddies&lt;/strong&gt;(稻田) of Ban Kwan village; over 100 households were forced to relocate against their will. And then there is the question of law enforcement within the SEZs, whose light regulation can be as attractive to criminals as to legitimate businesses. In 2018 American authorities declared that the Golden Triangle SEZ was a &lt;strong&gt;hotbed&lt;/strong&gt;(温床) of “drug &lt;strong&gt;trafficking&lt;/strong&gt;(贸易), human trafficking, money laundering, bribery and wildlife trafficking”. They called the company that operates the SEZ a “transnational criminal organisation” and placed &lt;strong&gt;sanction:&lt;/strong&gt;(处罚) on its chairman, Zhao Wei. He denied the accusations, calling the move “unilateral, extraterritorial, unreasonable and &lt;strong&gt;hegemonic&lt;/strong&gt;(霸权的)”. Many South-East Asians might say something similar about the way the region’s SEZs are run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cloak: to cover (someone or something). e.g., a field cloaked in snow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loom: to appear in an impressively large or great form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parlour: a place where people pay to be given a massage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;palatial: very large and impressive : like a palace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;confection: a very sweet food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fresco: the art of painting on wet plaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assorted: including several kinds. e.g., assorted colors/flavors/sizes/styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;banner: words printed in large letters at the top of a newspaper&amp;rsquo;s front page under the name of the newspaper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clout: the power to influence or control situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;influx: the arrival of a large number of people. e.g., The city is preparing for a large influx of tourists this summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bear: to produce (something). e.g., trees that bear fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;underpinning: to strengthen or support (something) from below. e.g., a report underpinned by ample research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skew: to change (something) so that it is not true or accurate. e.g., They were accused of skewing the facts to fit their theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garment: a piece of clothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patronise: to be a frequent or regular customer or user of (a place). e.g., I patronize the library regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exchequer: a department of the British government which manages the money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paddy: a wet field where rice is grown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trafficking: the act or business of illegally buying something and selling it especially in another country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sanction: to penalize the doer for doing it. / official permission or approval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》脱欧后的英美关系</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E8%84%B1%E6%AC%A7%E5%90%8E%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E7%BE%8E%E5%85%B3%E7%B3%BB/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 11:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E8%84%B1%E6%AC%A7%E5%90%8E%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E7%BE%8E%E5%85%B3%E7%B3%BB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-weaker-post-brexit-britain-looks-to-america&#34;&gt;A weaker post-Brexit Britain looks to America&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-with-that&#34;&gt;Good luck with that&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;titans&lt;/strong&gt; of Brexit have a tendency to &lt;strong&gt;gush&lt;/strong&gt; over(滔滔不绝地说) Britain’s bond with America. Before the &lt;strong&gt;referendum&lt;/strong&gt;(公民投票) in 2016, Boris Johnson—now prime minister, then mayor of London—predicted that, outside the European Union, the thriving British would be “even better and more valuable allies of the United States”. Britain’s relationship with America had long been “special”, &lt;strong&gt;enthused&lt;/strong&gt;(使热心) Liam Fox as trade secretary in 2018. But Brexit provided a “&lt;strong&gt;once-in-a-generation&lt;/strong&gt;千载难逢 opportunity to raise it to a new level”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in the week that Britain actually leaves the EU it finds itself at &lt;strong&gt;loggerheads&lt;/strong&gt;(对立) with America on tax, trade and technology. If the British government persists with plans for a digital-services tax that would hit tech giants, America has said it will &lt;strong&gt;retaliate&lt;/strong&gt;(报复) with &lt;strong&gt;punitive&lt;/strong&gt;(惩罚性的) tariffs on British car exports. And despite heavy American lobbying and suggestions that the countries’ intelligence-sharing could be at risk, Mr Johnson decided on January 28th to allow Britain to buy 5G telecoms kit from Huawei of China. Mike Pompeo, America’s secretary of state, had warned against letting China “control the internet of the future”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision on Huawei came two days before Mr Pompeo was due to join his British counterpart, Dominic Raab, in London for a public conversation on “the future of the special relationship”. At first glance, and despite the &lt;strong&gt;croonings&lt;/strong&gt;(低吟) of Brexiteers, that relationship appears to be in poor shape. Thomas Wright of the Brookings Institution, a Washington think-tank, describes it as “in its worst state since the Suez crisis” in 1956.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Wright has catalogued many ways in which President Donald Trump “&lt;strong&gt;tormented&lt;/strong&gt;(折磨)” the previous government, under Theresa May. Although Mr Trump has a better &lt;strong&gt;rapport&lt;/strong&gt;(密切关系) with Mr Johnson than he had with Mrs May, tensions have not disappeared. Meanwhile, competition for America’s attention has been growing. Under the energetic Emmanuel Macron, France emphasises that it is the “oldest ally” of the United States. China’s rise is also &lt;strong&gt;tugging&lt;/strong&gt;(用力拖) America away from Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this adds to a sense of uncertainty, post-Brexit, about Britain’s status and role in the world. The so-called special relationship has always been &lt;strong&gt;lopsided&lt;/strong&gt;(不平衡的): Helmut Schmidt, a German chancellor, once quipped that it was so special only one side knew it existed. But for nearly half a century, membership of the European club allowed the British to stop &lt;strong&gt;fretting&lt;/strong&gt;(使烦恼) too much about their influence in the world. They were “the bridge between the US and Europe”, as Tony Blair, one of the most enthusiastic &lt;strong&gt;proponents&lt;/strong&gt;(支持者) of the special relationship (and an ardent(热情的) Remainer), put it as prime minister in 1997. Britain could wield influence on both sides of the Atlantic. Now that the bridge is breaking, questions about Britain’s power are back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-have-come-to-a-pretty-pass&#34;&gt;Things have come to a pretty pass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the second world war Britain struggled to find its place in America’s shadow. Winston Churchill &lt;strong&gt;envisaged&lt;/strong&gt;(设想) Britain as part of three great circles among the democracies: the Commonwealth, the English-speaking sphere and a united Europe. In 1946, in a speech in Fulton, Missouri, he had proposed a “special relationship” with the United States, a “&lt;strong&gt;fraternal&lt;/strong&gt;(兄弟般的) association” of English-speaking peoples involving not only &lt;strong&gt;kindred&lt;/strong&gt;(相似) societies but military &lt;strong&gt;collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;(合作). Another prime minister, Harold Macmillan, &lt;strong&gt;patronisingly&lt;/strong&gt; positioned Britain as playing Athens to America’s Rome, teaching a “&lt;strong&gt;vulgar&lt;/strong&gt;(粗俗), &lt;strong&gt;bustling&lt;/strong&gt;(忙乱的)” people how to run a rising empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this proved convincing. In 1962 Dean Acheson, a former American secretary of state, concluded that Britain had lost an empire but not found a role. Its attempt to find one away from
Europe, based on a “special relationship” with America and on being the head of a Commonwealth, he said, was “about played out”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining what was then the European Economic Community in 1973 offered something of a solution. As Ray Seitz, an American ambassador to London, noted in a &lt;strong&gt;valedictory&lt;/strong&gt;(告别的) speech in 1994: “If Britain’s voice is less influential in Paris or [Berlin], it is likely to be less influential in Washington.” In Mr Blair’s formulation: “Strong in Europe and strong with the US&amp;hellip;There is no choice between the two. Stronger with one means stronger with the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-romance-is-growing-flat&#34;&gt;Our romance is growing flat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special or not, the relationship has often been &lt;strong&gt;fraught&lt;/strong&gt;(担心的). Apart from the Suez debacle, &lt;strong&gt;friction&lt;/strong&gt; arose between Harold Wilson and Lyndon Johnson over Wilson’s refusal to support the war in Vietnam. Even Margaret Thatcher and Ronald Reagan, who were so &lt;strong&gt;chummy&lt;/strong&gt;(亲密的) that Reagan’s successor, George H.W. Bush, said “he was just &lt;strong&gt;smitten&lt;/strong&gt;(打) by her”, fell out over America’s &lt;strong&gt;invasion&lt;/strong&gt;(入侵) of Grenada in 1983.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet over the years, in several different spheres, America and Britain have grown closer. Some 28 “Nobel prizes have been awarded jointly to people from the two countries. British actors, such as Daniel Craig, are as likely to play an American detective in Hollywood movies as American ones, such as Renée Zellweger, are to put on plummy British accents to play characters such as Bridget Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economic ties are especially deep. New York and London, the world’s top two financial centres, are rivals but they are also intertwined. Nearly a fifth of Britain’s exports go to America, more than double the share going to Germany, the next-biggest partner. America accounts for 15% of Britain’s total trade. American investment in Britain supports an estimated 1.5m jobs, and 1.3m vice versa. Britain attracts more than 10% of American foreign R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as anything, though, it is shared values and habits of co-operation that have bound Britain and America together. Britain, says Nicholas Burns, a former American ambassador to NATO, is “the country we trusted the most, and worked most closely with.” At the State Department, where British diplomats enjoy a level of access afforded no other country, Britain was “the most like-minded country” with America, and “the first port of entry” with the EU on many issues, according to Amanda Sloat, a Europe specialist who served there under the Obama administration. In an Emerson poll from October 2019, 40% of Americans saw Britain as their country’s most valuable ally and strategic partner, far ahead of next-placed Canada on just 22%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This closeness has often been evident at the top, starting with the wartime partnership between Churchill and Franklin Roosevelt. Whether it was the free-market freedom-championing of Thatcher and Reagan or the war-fighting of Mr Blair and George W. Bush, British and American leaders have tended to act in &lt;strong&gt;tandem&lt;/strong&gt;(前一后地).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the questions facing the special relationship today is whether or not the same will apply for Mr Johnson and Mr Trump. They have a lot in common; perhaps unsurprisingly, they openly express &lt;strong&gt;admiration&lt;/strong&gt;(钦佩) for one another. Yet other leaders, including Mr Macron, have learnt that it is unwise to place high hopes in a “&lt;strong&gt;bromance&lt;/strong&gt;(兄弟情)” with Mr Trump. And if Mr Trump expects that Mr Johnson will go along with his wishes on issues such as the Iran nuclear deal or relations with China he is likely to find himself disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Johnson’s own instincts may even lean towards European positions on many issues, from climate change to Ukraine. As long as the Trump administration remains in place, “we appear to be more aligned with the Europeans on values and interests than with the United States,” suggests Sir Peter Westmacott, a former British ambassador to Washington. Federica Mogherini, until recently the EU’s foreign-affairs representative, expects &lt;strong&gt;continuity&lt;/strong&gt;(连续性), too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huawei provided a first test of Britain’s post-Brexit policy. Now two other areas will come to the &lt;strong&gt;fore&lt;/strong&gt;(前部): defence and trade. Traditionally, the Anglo-American relationship has been deepest in military, nuclear and intelligence matters. Britain’s armed forces have fought alongside their ally in every major campaign of the past three decades. “The way we fight is nearly &lt;strong&gt;indistinguishable&lt;/strong&gt;(不能区别的),” says Philip Breedlove, a retired American general who served as NATO’s Supreme Allied Commander Europe from 2013 to 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partly this is down to an unparalleled level of integration. Every major in the British Army goes through a course in America, and more than 1,000 British military and civilian defence staff are based across 29 American states. Some military assets are held virtually in common, while British defence firms are more closely involved than those of any other country in building the F-35 warplane. Britain also depends on America to build, sustain and &lt;strong&gt;defray&lt;/strong&gt;(支出) the costs of its nuclear &lt;strong&gt;arsenal&lt;/strong&gt;(兵工厂).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-like-tomato-and-i-like-tomahto&#34;&gt;You like tomato and I like tomahto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;strong&gt;spooks&lt;/strong&gt;(鬼) lean heavily on one another, too. Britain’s signals-intelligence agency, GCHQ, and its American counterpart, the NSA, are bound by the Five Eyes pact, which includes Australia, Canada and New Zealand. Documents leaked by Edward Snowden, a former NSA contractor(承包人), showed that Britain had a sweet deal: America paid at least £100m to GCHQ in 2009-12 and 60% of Britain’s high-value intelligence was derived from the NSA. But the benefits are not one-sided. Michael Hayden, an ex-NSA director, once told his British counterpart that if Fort Meade, the NSA’s Maryland headquarters, was to suffer a catastrophe, he planned to entrust the machinery of American electronic &lt;strong&gt;espionage&lt;/strong&gt;(间谍) to Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strategic &lt;strong&gt;intimacy&lt;/strong&gt;(亲密) dates to the second world war. However, it is not &lt;strong&gt;immutable&lt;/strong&gt;(不变的). Kori Schake of the American Enterprise Institute (AEI), a think-tank, warns that “Britain is perilously close to becoming just like any other Western military rather than the preferred partner of the US any time rules need enforcing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years the sorest point has been British defence cuts. In 2015 Barack Obama demanded, in terms that would &lt;strong&gt;foreshadow&lt;/strong&gt;(预示) Mr Trump’s &lt;strong&gt;rhetoric&lt;/strong&gt;(花言巧语), that David Cameron, then prime minister, pay his “fair share”. General Ray Odierno, then head of the US Army, said that he was “very concerned” by the belt-tightening, which amounted to an 18% fall in real-terms spending over the previous five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those warnings helped trigger a spending boost, but three years later James Mattis, then Mr Trump’s defence secretary, fired another shot across the bow of his British counterpart. “France and the US have concluded that now is the time to significantly increase our investment in defence,” he warned in a letter, adding &lt;strong&gt;ominously&lt;/strong&gt;(恶兆地): “It is in the best interest of both our nations for the UK to remain the US partner of choice.” That prompted another hurried injection of cash, but Britain has struggled to keep up. The size of its armed forces has fallen for nine consecutive years. Brexit might lead to further reductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, American diplomatic and military insiders tend to &lt;strong&gt;pooh&lt;/strong&gt;-pooh(藐视) the idea that the relationship is in crisis, or that France could &lt;strong&gt;supplant&lt;/strong&gt;(代替) Britain. “The UK is still our most capable partner militarily, and our most valuable partner politically,” says Rachel Ellehuus, who handled European and NATO policy at the Pentagon(五角大楼) until 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However there are some signs of wavering in Britain. On January 12th Ben Wallace, Britain’s defence secretary, questioned America’s reliability as a partner. Britain was “very dependent” on American &lt;strong&gt;surveillance&lt;/strong&gt;(监督) and air cover, warned Mr Wallace. “We need to diversify our assets,” he added. British spending on American kit is already &lt;strong&gt;slated&lt;/strong&gt;(计划) to run to $32bn over the next decade, around 7% of the defence budget each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the options for diversification are limited. Brexit has left Britain cut out of a new European defence fund and a project to build a European satellite-navigation system. Going it alone is pricey: a proposed British-built alternative constellation would cost around £5bn. So Britain will have a lot to wrestle with as it conducts a comprehensive review of security, defence and foreign policy. Mr Johnson has promised it will be the most &lt;strong&gt;radical&lt;/strong&gt;(激进的) assessment since the end of the cold war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-oh-if-we-call-the-whole-thing-off&#34;&gt;But oh, if we call the whole thing off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other test of the special relationship, on trade, is likely to be similarly fraught; all the more so given the &lt;strong&gt;rancour&lt;/strong&gt;(深仇) in Congress over the Huawei decision. Tom Cotton, a Republican on the US Senate’s Armed Services Committee, tweeted that “I fear London has freed itself from Brussels only to &lt;strong&gt;cede&lt;/strong&gt;(放弃) &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;/strong&gt;(主权) to Beijing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the desire for a deal is not in doubt. Both sides are aiming for a comprehensive free-trade agreement, which could &lt;strong&gt;dismantle&lt;/strong&gt;(拆除) non-tariff barriers. Negotiators share an interest in strong intellectual-property protection, recognition for each other’s professional qualifications and maintaining the free flow of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Britain really wanted, it could probably get a deal in relatively short order. America has a template trade deal that it tries to push on all of its negotiating partners. David Henig of the European Centre for International Political Economy, a think-tank, reckons Britain could sign up to most of the text on tariff reductions and services without a &lt;strong&gt;hitch&lt;/strong&gt;(麻烦). As a gesture, the Americans could offer some special access to their public-&lt;strong&gt;procurement&lt;/strong&gt;(采购) market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, American officials have been helping to bring their British counterparts up to speed, in some cases informing them of stumbling-blocks in negotiations with the EU. The warmth stems only partly from a genuine wish to strengthen their relationship. It also reflects a desire to &lt;strong&gt;thumb American noses&lt;/strong&gt;(嗤之以鼻) at the EU—and pull Britain away from its regulatory orbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some crucial areas, Britain is going to have to choose between the American system of regulation and the European one. Take the issue of food standards, often simplified to a debate about &lt;strong&gt;chlorinated&lt;/strong&gt; chicken(氯化鸡). The EU bans its import on the basis of the precautionary principle, which says that there must be scientific evidence proving something is safe for it to be allowed. America &lt;strong&gt;flips&lt;/strong&gt;(掷) that burden of proof; in order for a product to be banned there must be scientific evidence proving it is unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American negotiators &lt;strong&gt;scoff&lt;/strong&gt;(嘲笑 that the EU’S approach is “unscientific”. Regardless, if Britons opt for the American way, they may quickly find themselves &lt;strong&gt;embroiled&lt;/strong&gt;(使卷入) in the EU’s non-tariff barriers for their “own products. The EU has made it clear that any future free-trade deal with Britain will have to include provisions to prevent any “unfair competitive advantage” that Britain could get by &lt;strong&gt;undercutting&lt;/strong&gt; its environmental and regulatory measures. To put it another way: if Britain wants to diverge from the EU’s standards and follow an American model instead, its market access to its biggest and closest neighbour will suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If negotiators get &lt;strong&gt;bogged&lt;/strong&gt;(陷于泥沼的) down, as they probably will, then they could aim instead for a quick and shallow deal, delivering political wins on both sides of the pond. Such a deal could &lt;strong&gt;defuse&lt;/strong&gt;(平息) the dispute over digital-services taxes, or perhaps America’s complaints over Britain’s subsidies for Airbus, a European aircraft manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these potential &lt;strong&gt;hurdles&lt;/strong&gt;(障碍), leaving the EU does not mean Britain has lost all its leverage with the country Iran dubbed “the Great Satan” to Britain’s “little Satan”. Britain can still draw on a depth of diplomatic capital that offers it &lt;strong&gt;clout&lt;/strong&gt;(影响力). It remains in the G7 and the G20 and plays a big role in NATO. Britain has a wide network through the Commonwealth and earns influence as a major player in development aid. Not least, it retains one of the five permanent seats on the UN Security Council. As the country emerges from &lt;strong&gt;agonising&lt;/strong&gt;(烦恼的) over the Brexit negotiations, it can start to devote more energy to working out how to make the most of these assets under its new, semi-connected status with the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, whatever the intrinsic merits of the Huawei decision—the British view was that security risks could be managed and that the alternative suppliers were not yet up to scratch—it dispels(驱散) the idea that a weakened Britain leaving the EU will always bend to America’s will. When Britain &lt;strong&gt;ingratiates&lt;/strong&gt;(使迎合) itself with America, things do not necessarily end well, as Mr Blair’s enthusiasm for the war in Iraq showed. A clear-headed view of the country’s national interests (which in the Huawei case include Britain’s wish for strong trade relations with China) serves it best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the constraints of the EU, Britain could have some scope to be more &lt;strong&gt;agile&lt;/strong&gt;(敏捷的). Take sanctions. It is true that Britain is losing the ability to champion these through the EU. But it also no longer has to be bound by the need to &lt;strong&gt;thrash&lt;/strong&gt; out(解决) lowest-common-denominator agreement. It could, potentially, take the initiative on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;then-that-may-break-my-heart&#34;&gt;Then that may break my heart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some would like to see Britain take the lead in areas where, for now, America seems to have lost interest, such as championing democracy. (Though that would mean standing up to China.) Because Britain knows America so well it has “a huge opportunity to help countries trying to deal with [it]&amp;hellip;do it more &lt;strong&gt;nimbly&lt;/strong&gt;(敏捷地) and more strategically,” says Ms Schake of the AEI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britain could remain in the bridge business. The two countries may never regain the first-name closeness shared by “Ron” and Margaret or even George and Tony. But a different American administration could both &lt;strong&gt;rekindle&lt;/strong&gt;(重新点燃) something of that romance, as well as help its ally remain closely connected with the continent. For now, however, Mr Trump seems to favour a divide-and-conquer approach. And that threatens the &lt;strong&gt;ardour&lt;/strong&gt;(激情) between Boris and Donald.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;titan: a very strong or important person SYN giant. e.g., a titan of the Hollywood film industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gush: to speak in an extremely enthusiastic way. e.g., Everyone has been gushing over/about the baby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;referendum: when people vote in order to make a decision about a particular subject, rather than voting for a person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enthuse: to talk about something in a very interested or excited way. e.g., Rick was there, enthusing about life in Australia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loggerheads: be at loggerheads (with somebody).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;retaliate: to do something bad to someone because they have done something bad to you → hit back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;torment: severe mental or physical suffering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rapport: friendly agreement and understanding between people. e.g., He had an excellent rapport with his patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tug: to pull with one or more short, quick pulls. e.g., The woman gently tugged his arm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lopsided: unequal or uneven, especially in an unfair way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fret: to worry about something, especially when there is no need. e.g., She’s always fretting about the children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proponent: someone who supports something or persuades people to do something. e.g., Steinem has always been a strong proponent of women’s rights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;envisage: to think that something is likely to happen in the future. e.g., I don’t envisage working with him again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fraternal: showing a special friendliness to other people because you share interests or ideas with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vulgar: not behaving politely in social situations. e.g., vulgar behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bustle: to move around quickly, looking very busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;valedictory: a speech or statement in which you say goodbye when you are leaving a school, job etc, especially on a formal occasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fraught: full of anxiety or worry. e.g., a fraught situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;friction:  disagreement, angry feelings, or unfriendliness between people SYN tension. e.g., Having my mother living with us causes friction at home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chummy: informal friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smite: to hit something with a lot of force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tandem: a group of two people or things that work together or are associated with each other. e.g., The two products can be used alone or in tandem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defray: to pay for (something). e.g., This will defray the costs/expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arsenal: a collection of weapons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spook: spy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;espionage: the activity of spying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intimacy: an intimate quality or state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;immutable: unable to be changed. e.g., the immutable laws of nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foreshadow: to give a suggestion of (something that has not yet happened). e.g., Her early interest in airplanes foreshadowed her later career as a pilot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rhetoric: language that is intended to influence people and that may not be honest or reasonable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ominously: suggesting that something bad is going to happen in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pooh: used to show that you think an idea, suggestion, etc., is not very good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supplant: to take the place of. e.g., DVDs have supplanted videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slate: to arrange or plan for something to happen. e.g., She is slated to become the company&amp;rsquo;s next president.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rancour: an angry feeling of hatred or dislike for someone who has treated you unfairly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cede: to give control of (something) to another person. e.g., The state had to cede part of their territory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sovereignty: a country&amp;rsquo;s independent authority and the right to govern itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dismantle: to destroy (something) in an orderly way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hitch: a hidden problem that makes something more complicated or difficult to do. e.g., The plan went off without a hitch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;procurement: to get (something) by some action or effort. e.g., Birth certificates are needed for procurement of a marriage license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scoff: to laugh at and talk about someone or something in a way that shows disapproval and a lack of respect. e.g., He scoffed at the idea/notion/suggestion of her becoming an actress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embroil: to involve (someone or something) in conflict or difficulties. e.g., They were embroiled in a complicated lawsuit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undercut: to make (something) weaker or less effective. e.g., Her behavior undercuts her own credibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bog down: to cause (something) to sink in wet ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defuse: to make (something) less serious, difficult, or tense. e.g., Skilled negotiators helped defuse the crisis/situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hurdle: something that makes an achievement difficult. e.g., The company faces severe financial hurdles this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clout: the power to influence or control situations. e.g., She used her political clout to have another school built.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agonising: very mentally or physically painful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ingratiate: to gain favor or approval for (yourself) by doing or saying things that people like. e.g., She has tried to ingratiate herself with voters by promising a tax cut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agile: able to move quickly and easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thrash: to produce (something, such as an agreement or plan) by a lot of discussion. e.g., thrash out a plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nimbly: able to move quickly, easily, and lightly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rekindle: to cause (something, such as a feeling) to be strong or active again. e.g., The movie has rekindled public interest in the trial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ardour: a strong feeling of energy or eagerness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》青春期真的能抑制吗</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E9%9D%92%E6%98%A5%E6%9C%9F%E7%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E8%83%BD%E6%8A%91%E5%88%B6%E5%90%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 11:03:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E9%9D%92%E6%98%A5%E6%9C%9F%E7%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E8%83%BD%E6%8A%91%E5%88%B6%E5%90%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-to-do-about-puberty-blockers&#34;&gt;What to do about puberty blockers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;drugs-offered-to-transgender-children-need-to-be-used-more-cautiously&#34;&gt;Drugs offered to transgender children need to be used more cautiously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arising number of girls wish to be boys and boys wish to be girls and a rising number of them are taking drugs to block &lt;strong&gt;puberty&lt;/strong&gt;(青春期). In Britain cases of children being treated for gender &lt;strong&gt;dysphoria&lt;/strong&gt;(烦躁不安) by the National Health Service remain rare, but in the past decade they have climbed at a rate of $5\%$ year on year (see chart). In America the number of gender &lt;strong&gt;clinics&lt;/strong&gt;(诊所) treating children has increased from just one in 2007 to perhaps 50 today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has bothered lawmakers. In America several states want to ban giving puberty-blocking drugs to children (see United States section). In Britain the high court is considering the judicial review of a clinic which complainants believe has been handing out puberty blockers too freely (see Britain section).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of such drugs raises &lt;strong&gt;thorny&lt;/strong&gt;(多刺的) questions about who decides what can happen to a child’s body and why. Put aside the culture wars, if you can. This debate should be settled in the interests of the child. Yet those can be very hard to &lt;strong&gt;discern&lt;/strong&gt;(识别).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puberty blockers prevent adolescents from developing secondary sexual characteristics like breasts or a beard. They almost always set off a cascade of interventions that involve “cross-sex” hormones and later may also include gender-reassignment surgery. The main purpose of puberty blockers is to bring comfort to people with gender dysphoria, by &lt;strong&gt;sparing&lt;/strong&gt;(使&amp;hellip;免遭) them the experience of, say, becoming more like a woman if they are a girl who wishes to be a boy. They also make most future surgery less severe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the combination of puberty blockers and cross-sex hormones also leads to irreversible changes which, if they start early in puberty, include &lt;strong&gt;sterility&lt;/strong&gt;(不育). About a dozen studies of gender-dysphoric children who did not take puberty blockers have found that most of them, if supported by counselling, are happy with their sex once they emerge from puberty. The share often cited is $85\%$ and many of them turn out to be gay. One sign that something is wrong is that more people are “detransitioning”—re-identifying with their biological sex. Most of them are girls who wanted to be boys when they were in their teens. If they took puberty blockers and then cross-sex hormones early they would be sterile for life, even if they did not have &lt;strong&gt;hysterectomies&lt;/strong&gt;(子宫切除).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, there is no way to distinguish the $15\%$ or so of children who will transition successfully from the $85\%$ who might have been happy with the gender of their birth if they had received &lt;strong&gt;counselling&lt;/strong&gt;(辅导) alone. Some claim that withholding puberty blockers adds to the burden on vulnerable children with gender-dysphoria and may lead to higher rates of suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing whom to treat is a judgment of Solomon. The decision to intervene is made harder by a &lt;strong&gt;reckless&lt;/strong&gt;(鲁莽的) &lt;strong&gt;disregard&lt;/strong&gt;(忽视) for data. The academic studies &lt;strong&gt;purporting&lt;/strong&gt;(声称) to show the higher suicide risk among trans children are &lt;strong&gt;unconvincing&lt;/strong&gt;(令人难以信服的). Clinics do not publish enough studies on the effects of various treatments on their patients. Too little research compares children who have had treatment with those who have not. The field needs a better understanding of the long-term effects of puberty blockers and cross-sex hormones. Every child who is treated should be enrolled in a long-term follow-up study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be with their informed consent. But so should the treatment itself. Today children and parents are not always fully informed about the potentially grave consequences of starting on puberty blockers. Their effects are often described as largely reversible—and the effects of cross-sex hormones that are almost always taken with them are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ban puberty blockers in all circumstances would be unjustified. Not only would it be harsh on some children, but it would also leave the issue permanently obscured for lack of new research. However, today’s rush into treatment &lt;strong&gt;smacks&lt;/strong&gt;(打) of a &lt;strong&gt;fad&lt;/strong&gt;(时尚). Many adolescents feel unhappy with the way they were made. Transitioning will be &lt;strong&gt;solace&lt;/strong&gt;(安慰) for some. But for others it will be a dreadful mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;puberty: the stage in people&amp;rsquo;s lives when they develop from a child into an adult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dysphoria: severe unhappiness, especially a person&amp;rsquo;s feeling of being very uncomfortable in their body or of being in the wrong body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thorny: A thorny problem or subject is difficult to deal with. e.g., the thorny issue of taxation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discern: to notice or understand something by thinking about it carefully. e.g., Officials were keen to discern how much public support there was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spare: to prevent someone from having to experience something unpleasant. e.g., Luckily, I was spared the embarrassment of having to sing in front of everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;counselling: the job or process of listening to someone and giving that person advice about their problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reckless: doing something dangerous and not worrying about the risks and the possible results. e.g., He was found guilty of reckless driving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disregard: the fact of showing no care or respect for something. e.h., What amazes me is her complete disregard for anyone else&amp;rsquo;s opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;purport: to pretend to be or to do something, especially in a way that is not easy to believe. e.g., The study purports to show an increase in the incidence of the disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smack: to hit something hard. e.g., I never smack my children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fad: a style, activity, or interest that is very popular for a short period of time. e.g., There was a fad for wearing ripped jeans a few years ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solace: help and comfort when you are feeling sad or worried. e.g., Music was a great solace to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》川普的和平计划</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%9D%E6%99%AE%E7%9A%84%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B3%E8%AE%A1%E5%88%92/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 21:20:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%9D%E6%99%AE%E7%9A%84%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B3%E8%AE%A1%E5%88%92/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dead-on-arrival&#34;&gt;Dead on arrival&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one-sided deal highlights the need for new leadership on all sides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE &lt;strong&gt;PROSPECT&lt;/strong&gt;(前景) of peace between Israel and the Palestinians has grown so &lt;strong&gt;dim&lt;/strong&gt;(暗淡的), it is easy to forget that President Donald Trump’s efforts to end the conflict began with much promise. The dealmaker-in-chief vowed to bring fresh thinking to the decades-old &lt;strong&gt;feud&lt;/strong&gt;(不和). “As with any successful negotiation, both sides will have to make compromises,” he told Binyamin Netanyahu, Israel(以色列)’s prime minister, in 2017. Mr Trump’s meeting with Mahmoud Abbas, a few months later, ended with the Palestinian(巴勒斯坦的) president &lt;strong&gt;gushing&lt;/strong&gt;(涌出): “With you we have hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What followed, though, was neither bold thinking nor any demand for sacrifices on both sides. Rather, Mr Trump showered Mr Netanyahu, a fellow populist(平民党党员), with political gifts. He recognised the disputed &lt;strong&gt;holy&lt;/strong&gt; city of Jerusalem耶路撒冷(以色列首都) as Israel’s capital. His State Department declared that Israeli settlements in the West Bank are lawful. (Few legal scholars agree.) Mr Trump cut aid to the Palestinians, even for health and education, and closed their diplomatic mission in Washington. All this delighted his pro-Israel supporters back home, but enraged Palestinians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such is the context for Mr Trump’s unveiling of his long-awaited peace plan with Mr Netanyahu on January 28th (see article). It will not bring peace. But it may &lt;strong&gt;spell&lt;/strong&gt;(导致) the end of the two-state solution—the idea that a Palestinian state and a Jewish one might agree to co-exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a different time, under a different president, the proposal might have been the starting-point for more talks. Not an &lt;strong&gt;evenhanded&lt;/strong&gt;(公平的) starting-point, mind. The plan favours Israeli hardliners as no previous American plan has done. It lets Israel formally &lt;strong&gt;annex&lt;/strong&gt;(获得) the settlements, hang on to the Jordan valley, maintain control of holy sites and reject Palestinian refugees. For the Palestinians, there are conditional promises of something like a state at some point in the future, with a capital on the &lt;strong&gt;outskirts&lt;/strong&gt;(市郊) of Jerusalem, plus billions of dollars of investment and an Israeli promise to freeze some settlement-building. If they negotiate, they might get a better deal, suggests the Trump administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Palestinians do not believe it. If Mr Trump were serious about &lt;strong&gt;peacemaking&lt;/strong&gt;(调解), why did he try to &lt;strong&gt;woo&lt;/strong&gt;(追求) only one side? No Palestinian leader could have accepted the deal, let alone one as weak as Mr Abbas. Mr Trump did not even invite him to the unveiling, which anyway seemed designed to distract Americans from &lt;strong&gt;impeachment&lt;/strong&gt;(怀疑) (see article), and Israelis from corruption charges against Mr Netanyahu. The prime minister appears eager to end the Palestinian dream of statehood. He has already asked his cabinet to vote on annexing parts of the West Bank, and is &lt;strong&gt;whipping&lt;/strong&gt;(鞭打) up &lt;strong&gt;hawkish&lt;/strong&gt;(强硬派的) voters ahead of a tough election on March 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should Mr Netanyahu win another term, he will undoubtedly move ahead with annexation(合并). His main challenger, Benny Gantz, will face pressure to do the same if he is &lt;strong&gt;victorious&lt;/strong&gt;. Far from easing the conflict, Mr Trump has pushed it down a &lt;strong&gt;perilous&lt;/strong&gt;(危险的) path. He has given Israel a green light to take so much territory that a coherent Palestinian state is all but impossible. And he offers no viable alternative to the two-state solution. That may soon leave Israel with a choice: give the Palestinians equal rights and watch as they multiply and outvote Jews, or treat them as second-class citizens and formally become an &lt;strong&gt;apartheid&lt;/strong&gt;(种族隔离) state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best that can be said of the Trump plan is that it acknowledges the Oslo peace process is &lt;strong&gt;moribund&lt;/strong&gt;(停滞不前的) and a new approach is needed. But a successful peace deal means not only discarding what has not worked, but also coming up with what will: a plan that demands &lt;strong&gt;concessions&lt;/strong&gt;(让步) from both sides as well as fair-minded leaders to implement it. This is not that plan. And Mr Trump, Mr Netanyahu and Mr Abbas are not those leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》武汉新型肺炎</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%AD%A6%E6%B1%89%E6%96%B0%E5%9E%8B%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 20:39:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%AD%A6%E6%B1%89%E6%96%B0%E5%9E%8B%E8%82%BA%E7%82%8E/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will the Wuhan virus become a pandemic?
Probably. But public health services can help determine how severe it turns out to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pandemic: a disease that affects people over a very large area or the whole world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-1&#34;&gt;Paragraph 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things explain why a new infectious disease is so alarming. One is that, at first, it spreads exponentially. As tens of cases become hundreds and hundreds become thousands, the mathematics run away with you, conjuring speculation about a health-care collapse, social and economic upheaval and a deadly pandemic. The other is profound uncertainty. Sparse data and conflicting reports mean that scientists can not rule out the worst case—and that lets bad information thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conjure: to make something appear or happen in a way which is not expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speculation: when you guess about the possible causes or effects of something without knowing all the facts. 例：There is speculation that the president is ill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upheaval: a very big change that often causes problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-2&#34;&gt;Paragraph 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is with a new coronavirus, known as2019-nCoV, which has struck in China. The number of reported cases grew from 282 on January 20th to almost 7,800 just nine days later. In that time four reported cases outside mainland China have multiplied to 105 in 19 territories. Doubt clouds fundamental properties of the disease, including how it is passed on and what share of infected people die. Amid the uncertainty, a simulation of a coronavirus outbreak by Johns Hopkins University in October, in which 65m people lost their lives, was put about as a prediction. It is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strike: 类似于hit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud: 云延伸出来就是“使模糊”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-3&#34;&gt;Paragraph 3&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the right questions, though: will the new virus become a global disease? And how deadly will it be? A definite answer is weeks or months away, but public-health authorities have to plan today. The best guess is that the disease has taken hold in China and there is a high risk that it spreads around the world—it may even become a recurrent seasonal infection. It may turn out to be no more lethal than seasonal influenza, but that would still count as serious. In the short term that would hit the world economy and, depending on how the outbreak is handled, it could also have political effects in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take hold: to start to have a definite effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lethal: causing death, or able to cause death&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-4&#34;&gt;Paragraph 4&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outbreak began in December. The repeated mingling of people and animals in China means that viral mutations that infect humans are likely to arise there; and mass migration to cities means that they are likely to spread between people. This virus probably originated in bats and passed through mammals, such as palm civets (果子狸) or ferret badgers (鼬獾), ending up in Wuhan’s wet market, where wild animals were on sale. Symptoms resemble flu, but can include pneumonia, which may be fatal. About 20\% of reported cases are severe, and need hospital care; about 2\% of them have been fatal. As yet, there is no vaccine or antiviral treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mingling: if two feelings, sounds, smells etc mingle, they mix together with each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wet market: 指的是传统市场，卖生鲜的这种&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pneumonia: 肺炎&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaccine: 疫苗&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antiviral: 复合词的结构，抗病毒&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-5&#34;&gt;Paragraph 5&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest uncertainty is how many cases have gone unrecorded. Primary health care is rudimentary in China and some of the ill either avoided or were turned away from busy hospitals. Many more may have such mild symptoms that they do not realise they have the disease. Modelling by academics in Hong Kong suggests that, as of January 25th, tens of thousands of people have already been infected and that the epidemic will peak in a few months’ time. If so, the virus is more widespread than thought, and hence will be harder to contain within China. But it will also prove less lethal, because the number of deaths should be measured against a much larger base of infections. As with flu, a lot of people could die nonetheless. In 2017-18 a bad flu season saw symptoms in 45m Americans, and 61,000 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rudimentary: simple and basic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-6&#34;&gt;Paragraph 6&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists have started work on vaccines and on treatments to make infections less severe. These are six to 12 months away, so the world must fall back on public-health measures. In China that has led to the biggest quarantine in history, as Wuhan and the rest of Hubei province have been sealed off. The impact of such draconian measures has rippled throughout China. The spring holiday has been extended, keeping schools and businesses closed. The economy is running on the home-delivery of food and goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quarantine: a period of time when a person or animal is kept apart from others in case they are carrying a disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draconian: very strict and cruel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ripple: to pass from one person to another like a wave. 例：Panic rippled through Hollywood as the murders were discovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-7&#34;&gt;Paragraph 7&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many experts praise China’s efforts. Certainly, its scientists have coped better with the Wuhan virus than they did with SARS in 2003, rapidly detecting it, sequencing its genome (基因测序), licensing diagnostic kits (诊断试剂) and informing international bodies. China’s politicians come off less well. They left alone the cramped markets filled with wild animals that spawned SARS. With the new virus, local officials in Wuhan first played down the science and then, when the disease had taken hold, enacted the draconian quarantine fully eight hours after announcing it, allowing perhaps 1m potentially infectious people to leave the city first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cramped: not have enough space. 例：The kitchen was small and cramped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spawn: to make a series of things happen or start to exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enact: to make a proposal into a law. 例：Congress refused to enact the bill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-8&#34;&gt;Paragraph 8&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That may have undermined a measure which is taking a substantial toll. China’s growth in the first quarter could fall to as little as 2\%, from 6\% before the outbreak. As China accounts for almost a fifth of world output, there will probably be a noticeable dent on global growth. Though the economy will bounce back when the virus fades, the reputation of the Communist Party and even of Xi Jinping may be more lastingly affected. The party claims that, armed with science, it is more efficient at governing than democracies. The heavy-handed failure to contain the virus suggests otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Substantial: large in amount or number; considerable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dent: a reduction in the amount of something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contain: to stop something from spreading or escaping. 例：Doctors are struggling to contain the epidemic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-9&#34;&gt;Paragraph 9&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside China such quarantines are unthinkable. The medical and economic cost will depend on governments slowing the disease’s spread. The way to do this is by isolating cases as soon as they crop up and tracing and quarantining people that victims have been in contact with—indeed, if the disease burns out in China, that might yet stop the pandemic altogether. If, by contrast, that proves inadequate, they could shut schools, discourage travel and urge the cancellation of public events. Buying time in this way has advantages even if it does not completely stop the disease. Health-care systems would have a greater chance to prepare for the onslaught, and to empty beds that are now full of people with seasonal flu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crop up: if a problem crops up, it happens or appears suddenly and in an unexpected way; arise. 例：if anything crops up, give me a call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-10&#34;&gt;Paragraph 10&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all those efforts the epidemic could still be severe. Some health systems, in Africa and the slums of Asia’s vast cities, will not be able to isolate patients and trace contacts. Much depends on whether people are infectious when their symptoms are mild (or before they show any at all, as some reports suggest), because such people are hard to spot. And also on whether the virus mutates to become more transmissible or lethal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slum: an area that is in bad condition, where very poor people live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spot: to notice someone or something, especially when they are difficult to see or recognize. 例：I spotted a police car behind us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutate: a change in genetic structure. 例：Simple organisms like bacteria mutate rapidly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;paragraph-11&#34;&gt;Paragraph 11&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has never responded as rapidly to a disease as it has to 2019-nCoV. Even so, the virus may still do great harm. As humans encroach on new habitats, farm more animals, gather in cities, travel and warm the planet, new diseases will become more common. One estimate puts their cost at $60bn a year. SARS, MERS, Nipah, Zika, Mexican swine flu: the fever from Wuhan is the latest of a bad bunch. It will not be the last.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>美音发音技巧——末尾s的发音</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BE%8E%E9%9F%B3%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3%E6%8A%80%E5%B7%A7%E6%9C%AB%E5%B0%BEs%E7%9A%84%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 09:44:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BE%8E%E9%9F%B3%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3%E6%8A%80%E5%B7%A7%E6%9C%AB%E5%B0%BEs%E7%9A%84%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;不知道你会不会傻傻分不清楚&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;likes  /s/ 还是 /z/？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lives /s/ 还是 /z/？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;首先说说 /s/ 和 /z/ 的发音，需要注意的是这个 /z/ 的发音其实和 /s/ 是一样的！只是在 /s/ 的基础上加上了声带的震动， &lt;strong&gt;不是中文拼音里的 z，是中文拼音里的 z，是中文拼音里的 z&lt;/strong&gt;！！！ 重要的事情说三遍，很多小伙伴很可能都是按照拼音的 ‘zi’ 来发音(包括我之前也是)那就要好好改改咯。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;知道了怎么发音我们再来看几个单词，你试着读读看？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set 1: likes/books/laughs/mats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set 2: lives/feels/cares&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set 3: is/has/was/these/because&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;答案揭晓：&lt;strong&gt;第一组都发 /s/，第二组都发 /z/，第三组都发 /z/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不知道你发对了没有还是 /s/ 和 /z/ 胡乱发一通，搞不清楚也没关系，我们先来找找规律，第一组 s 前都是什么？对！是以&lt;strong&gt;清辅音&lt;/strong&gt; 结尾的；第二组呢？是以&lt;strong&gt;浊辅音&lt;/strong&gt;结尾的，第三组则是&lt;strong&gt;元音&lt;/strong&gt;结尾的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那你就记住：&lt;strong&gt;/s/ 是清辅音，那就接在清辅音后面，/z/ 是浊辅音那就接在浊辅音后面，元音后面通常跟 /z/&lt;/strong&gt;，OK，再试试把上面三组单词读一遍感受一下。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;问题又来了，有的小伙伴会问什么是清辅音，什么是浊辅音，这个很好判断，你摸着你的声带，发音时感受到声带的就是浊辅音，比如/b/,/d/,/g/,/v/,/z/，不震动的就是清辅音，比如/p/,/t/,/k/,/f/,/s/。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;还有一个关于浊辅音和清辅音的技巧就是：&lt;strong&gt;浊辅音前的元音发音更“长”一点&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不信你对比一下以下几组单词： back 和 bag; safe 和save; pick 和 pig; lock 和 log; cup 和 cub&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;是不是发音每组单词中后面那个单词的元音都拉得比较长呢，那就对了！&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>美音中t的发音</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BE%8E%E9%9F%B3%E4%B8%ADt%E7%9A%84%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 18:33:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BE%8E%E9%9F%B3%E4%B8%ADt%E7%9A%84%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天做高铁回家路上刚好看了Jason的视频，总结一下美音中 t 的发音技巧，同时感谢一下Jason哥。
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://minghaochen.github.io/images/post/%e7%be%8e%e9%9f%b3%e4%b8%adt%e7%9a%84%e5%8f%91%e9%9f%b3/%e7%be%8e%e9%9f%b3%e4%b8%adt%e7%9a%84%e5%90%84%e7%a7%8d%e5%8f%91%e9%9f%b3.svg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这里的说法可能跟网上的一些说法不太一致，这里的 held t就是网上说的 stop t，简单理解就是 t 做出口形舌形但不发音，但是需要停顿一下而不是直接省略，达到所谓的 held 住或者 stop 的效果；这里的发音成 fast d 就是网上说的 flap t，弹舌音，简单理解就是舌头快速弹一下发出 d 的音，也就是发音现象中的浊化。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>美音发音技巧——连读</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BE%8E%E9%9F%B3%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3%E6%8A%80%E5%B7%A7%E8%BF%9E%E8%AF%BB/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 19:58:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BE%8E%E9%9F%B3%E5%8F%91%E9%9F%B3%E6%8A%80%E5%B7%A7%E8%BF%9E%E8%AF%BB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;连读主要有三种情况：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;辅元连读&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;辅辅连读&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. 发音相同，只发后一个音&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. 发音点相同，(t和d，b和p等)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;元元连读&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. 第一个元音以 i (包括/oi/,/ai/,/ei/)结尾，后面加上 y 的音：see (y) it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b.  第一个元音以u (包括/ou/)结尾，后面加上 w 的音：who (w) is&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>