<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>经济学人 on MH&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/categories/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 经济学人 on MH&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 10:02:33 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://minghaochen.github.io/categories/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》泰国的儿童拳击应该被禁止吗</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%B3%B0%E5%9B%BD%E7%9A%84%E5%84%BF%E7%AB%A5%E6%8B%B3%E5%87%BB%E5%BA%94%E8%AF%A5%E8%A2%AB%E7%A6%81%E6%AD%A2%E5%90%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 10:02:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E6%B3%B0%E5%9B%BD%E7%9A%84%E5%84%BF%E7%AB%A5%E6%8B%B3%E5%87%BB%E5%BA%94%E8%AF%A5%E8%A2%AB%E7%A6%81%E6%AD%A2%E5%90%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;despite-a-tragedy-the-authorities-allow-children-to-compete-in-a-violent-sport&#34;&gt;Despite a tragedy, the authorities allow children to compete in a violent sport&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The death of Anucha Thasako was supposed to change everything. After several sharp &lt;strong&gt;blows&lt;/strong&gt;(猛击) to the head during a Thai boxing &lt;strong&gt;bout&lt;/strong&gt;(回合) in 2018, the &lt;strong&gt;scrawny&lt;/strong&gt;(骨瘦如柴的) 13-year-old fell to the floor, unconscious. The referee rushed to his side, to no &lt;strong&gt;avail&lt;/strong&gt;(效用). There was no doctor in attendance. Anucha died soon afterwards from a brain &lt;strong&gt;haemorrhage&lt;/strong&gt;(出血). He had been boxing since the age of eight, and had taken part in around 170 fights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;footage&lt;/strong&gt;(影片) of the deadly bout, which circulated widely on social media, stirred &lt;strong&gt;uproar&lt;/strong&gt;(骚动). The government, which had anyway been considering restrictions on child boxing, pledged to rush through a bill to ban children under 12 from participating in formal competitions and to &lt;strong&gt;oblige&lt;/strong&gt;(迫使) those between 12 and 15 to wear protective headgear. But the plan quickly &lt;strong&gt;lost steam&lt;/strong&gt;(夭折).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants and fans protested loudly, arguing that the only way to prepare for a career in Thai boxing or muay thai, which dates to at least the 18th century, is to start young. Eliminate child boxing, they argued, and the whole sport would &lt;strong&gt;atrophy&lt;/strong&gt;(萎缩). The government no longer talks of tightening the rules for young boxers. Gongsak Yodmani, the head of the Sports Authority of Thailand, describes child boxing as standard practice. The authority’s official &lt;strong&gt;tally&lt;/strong&gt;(记录) shows only 635 boxers below the age of 15, although others put the number of children who train and compete informally as high as 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some children, boxing is a route out of poverty. Those participating in public fights earn 300-500 baht ($10-16) a bout when they are starting out, says Samart Payakaroon of the Muay Thai Naiyhanomtom Association, a lobby group. Professional boxers can earn thousands of dollars a match. Muay thai “is a very honourable way to escape poverty”, says Chatri Sityodtong, the founder of One Championship, a martial-arts promoter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But doctors say that blows to the head from “the art of eight &lt;strong&gt;limbs&lt;/strong&gt;(四肢)”, which involves punching, kicking, kneeing and elbowing, may &lt;strong&gt;stunt&lt;/strong&gt;(阻碍…的正常生长或发展) children’s development and increase the risk of Parkinson’s and Alzheimer’s. A study from Mahidol University found that boxers under the age of 15 had lower IQs than average; those who had been fighting the longest were furthest behind. The study’s lead author, Jiraporn Laothamatas, considers putting children in the &lt;strong&gt;ring&lt;/strong&gt;(环形竞技场) a form of child abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One force helping sustain the sport, underage bouts included, is tourism. The Tourism Authority of Thailand energetically promotes muay thai. Foreigners tend to &lt;strong&gt;snap&lt;/strong&gt; up(抢购) the most expensive seats in the biggest stadiums, looking for a slice of Thai life. Many may not realise how young some of the fighters they are watching are—although the weight categories should give them an &lt;strong&gt;inkling&lt;/strong&gt;(暗示). Anucha was competing in the under-41kg division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blow: a hard hit using a part of the body or an object. e.g., The two boxers exchanged blows. [=hit each other].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bout: a wrestling or boxing contest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrawny: very thin in a way that is not attractive or healthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avail: help toward reaching a goal. e.g., Our best efforts were of no avail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;footage: scenes or action recorded on film or video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uproar: a situation in which many people are upset, angry, or disturbed by something. e.g., The proposal caused an uproar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oblige: to force or require (someone or something) to do something. e.g., Her job obliges her to work overtime and on weekends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lose steam: to lose strength, force, or energy : to slow down. e.g., Sales have lost steam in recent weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;atrophy: to become weak from lack of use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tally: a recorded count of scores, votes, etc. e.g., What is the final tally?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limb:  a leg or arm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stunt: to stop (someone or something) from growing or developing. e.g., Too many restrictions have stunted the economy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ring: an area that is used for shows and contests and is usually surrounded by ropes or a fence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;snap up: to buy or take (something or someone) quickly or eagerly. e.g., Shoppers came to the store to snap up bargains after the holidays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inkling: a slight, uncertain idea about something. e.g., Nothing gave me any inkling that it would happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》东南亚经济特区为中国创造了财富</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E4%BA%9A%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E7%89%B9%E5%8C%BA%E4%B8%BA%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%9B%E9%80%A0%E4%BA%86%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:07:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E4%BA%9A%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E7%89%B9%E5%8C%BA%E4%B8%BA%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%9B%E9%80%A0%E4%BA%86%E8%B4%A2%E5%AF%8C/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-influx-of-investment-and-workers-is-creating-chinese-enclaves&#34;&gt;An influx of investment and workers is creating Chinese enclaves&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a remote part of northern Laos, the bamboo forest gives way to cranes. A city is being carved out of jungle: tower blocks &lt;strong&gt;cloaked&lt;/strong&gt;(遮掩) in &lt;strong&gt;scaffolding&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;loom&lt;/strong&gt;(赫然耸现) over restaurants, &lt;strong&gt;karaoke&lt;/strong&gt;卡拉OK bars and massage &lt;strong&gt;parlours&lt;/strong&gt;(客厅). The beating heart of Golden Triangle Special Economic Zone (so called because it sits at the point where Laos, Myanmar and Thailand converge) is the &lt;strong&gt;casino&lt;/strong&gt;(赌场), a &lt;strong&gt;palatial&lt;/strong&gt;(宏伟的) &lt;strong&gt;confection&lt;/strong&gt;(糖果) featuring faux-Roman statuary and &lt;strong&gt;ceilings&lt;/strong&gt;(天花板) covered in &lt;strong&gt;frescoes&lt;/strong&gt;(壁画). “Laos Vegas” does not cater to Laotians, however. Croupiers accept only Chinese yuan or Thai baht. Street signs are in Chinese and English. The city’s clocks are set to Chinese time, an hour ahead of the rest of Laos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, China has become one of the biggest investors in South-East Asian countries: in 2018 it was the source of nearly $80\%$ of foreign direct investment in Laos. Some of this capital is flowing along well-worn routes to places like Mandalay, a city in Myanmar where there is a long-established Chinese community. But much of it is flooding into “special economic zones” (SEZs) to take advantage of &lt;strong&gt;assorted&lt;/strong&gt;(各种各样的) incentives such as faster permitting, reduced tax or duties and looser controls on the movements of goods and capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese businesses don’t need much convincing. The Chinese government began encouraging them to invest abroad in the 2000s. The Belt and Road Initiative, China’s giant scheme to develop infrastructure abroad, has accelerated the trend. In addition to railways, highways and pipelines, it promotes SEZs, which “are now a preferred mode of economic expansion for China”, says Brian Eyler of the Stimson Centre, an American think-tank. Under the &lt;strong&gt;banner&lt;/strong&gt;(标语) of belt and road, 160 Chinese companies have poured more than $\$1.5$bn into SEZs in Laos, according to Land Watch Thai, a watchdog. Between 2016 and 2018 China invested $\$1$bn in one SEZ alone: Sihanoukville, a city on Cambodia’s coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where Chinese capital goes, labour follows. In Mandalay the Chinese have swelled from $1\%$ of the population in 1983 to $30\%-50\%$ today. In places with SEZs the shift has been even sharper. In 2019 the governor of the surrounding province told the Straits Times newspaper that the number of Chinese in Sihanoukville had soared over the previous two years to almost a third of the population. The economic &lt;strong&gt;clout&lt;/strong&gt;(影响力) of Chinese migrants grows with their numbers. In Mandalay $80\%$ of hotels, more than $70\%$ of restaurants and $45\%$ of jewellery shops are owned and operated by ethnic Chinese, according to market research conducted in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;influx&lt;/strong&gt;(流入) of migrants has fuelled anti-Chinese sentiment across the region. But poor South-East Asian governments court(设法获得) Chinese investors anyway because they hope Chinese money will kick-start their economies. In some respects the investment has &lt;strong&gt;borne&lt;/strong&gt;(结果实) fruit. In Laos foreign investment has contributed to &lt;strong&gt;effervescent&lt;/strong&gt;(冒泡的) GDP growth, which averaged $7.7\%$ a year over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in a study of SEZs in 2017 Focus on the Global South, a think-tank headquartered in Bangkok, concluded that the “legislative and governance structures” &lt;strong&gt;underpinning&lt;/strong&gt;(支撑 ) SEZs in Cambodia and Myanmar “have been &lt;strong&gt;skewed&lt;/strong&gt;(偏离) toward the interests of investors and against those of locals and the environment”. Alfredo Perdiguero of the Asian Development Bank agrees that SEZs in Laos, Cambodia and Myanmar “have not yet been able to spread the benefits” to the broader economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part this is because Chinese companies tend not to hire locals. By 2018 Laotian workers had secured just $34\%$ of the jobs created by all 11 SEZs in Laos—a far cry from the $90\%$ the government had promised. Chinese firms argue that local workers lack skills, but civil society groups in Myanmar respond by pointing to a technical college near Kyaukpyu, a Chinese-inspired SEZ and port; nobody from the college has been hired to work there, according to a report published last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is little local sourcing of other inputs, either. The &lt;strong&gt;garment&lt;/strong&gt;(衣服) factories of Sihanoukville SEZ, for instance, import their cloth, buttons and thread. The Chinese workers and visitors in South-East Asia’s SEZs often &lt;strong&gt;patronise&lt;/strong&gt;(光顾) Chinese-owned shops and restaurants, and circumvent sales taxes by paying for goods and services via Chinese apps like Alipay. “The money doesn’t even leave China essentially,” says Sebastian Strangio, author of a forthcoming book on China’s growing influence in South-East Asia. That, along with the tax breaks, mean there is little benefit for host governments: in 2017 the Laotian &lt;strong&gt;exchequer&lt;/strong&gt;(国库) raised just $\$20$m from its SEZs—less than $1\%$ of its revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;extraterritorial-不受管辖的-and-unreasonable&#34;&gt;Extraterritorial(不受管辖的) and unreasonable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is common with big developments in the poorer countries of South-East Asia, locals are seldom consulted about the construction of SEZs. Golden Triangle SEZ was built over the rice &lt;strong&gt;paddies&lt;/strong&gt;(稻田) of Ban Kwan village; over 100 households were forced to relocate against their will. And then there is the question of law enforcement within the SEZs, whose light regulation can be as attractive to criminals as to legitimate businesses. In 2018 American authorities declared that the Golden Triangle SEZ was a &lt;strong&gt;hotbed&lt;/strong&gt;(温床) of “drug &lt;strong&gt;trafficking&lt;/strong&gt;(贸易), human trafficking, money laundering, bribery and wildlife trafficking”. They called the company that operates the SEZ a “transnational criminal organisation” and placed &lt;strong&gt;sanction:&lt;/strong&gt;(处罚) on its chairman, Zhao Wei. He denied the accusations, calling the move “unilateral, extraterritorial, unreasonable and &lt;strong&gt;hegemonic&lt;/strong&gt;(霸权的)”. Many South-East Asians might say something similar about the way the region’s SEZs are run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cloak: to cover (someone or something). e.g., a field cloaked in snow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loom: to appear in an impressively large or great form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parlour: a place where people pay to be given a massage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;palatial: very large and impressive : like a palace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;confection: a very sweet food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fresco: the art of painting on wet plaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assorted: including several kinds. e.g., assorted colors/flavors/sizes/styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;banner: words printed in large letters at the top of a newspaper&amp;rsquo;s front page under the name of the newspaper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clout: the power to influence or control situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;influx: the arrival of a large number of people. e.g., The city is preparing for a large influx of tourists this summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bear: to produce (something). e.g., trees that bear fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;underpinning: to strengthen or support (something) from below. e.g., a report underpinned by ample research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skew: to change (something) so that it is not true or accurate. e.g., They were accused of skewing the facts to fit their theory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;garment: a piece of clothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patronise: to be a frequent or regular customer or user of (a place). e.g., I patronize the library regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exchequer: a department of the British government which manages the money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paddy: a wet field where rice is grown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trafficking: the act or business of illegally buying something and selling it especially in another country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sanction: to penalize the doer for doing it. / official permission or approval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》脱欧后的英美关系</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E8%84%B1%E6%AC%A7%E5%90%8E%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E7%BE%8E%E5%85%B3%E7%B3%BB/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 11:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E8%84%B1%E6%AC%A7%E5%90%8E%E7%9A%84%E8%8B%B1%E7%BE%8E%E5%85%B3%E7%B3%BB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-weaker-post-brexit-britain-looks-to-america&#34;&gt;A weaker post-Brexit Britain looks to America&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-with-that&#34;&gt;Good luck with that&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;titans&lt;/strong&gt; of Brexit have a tendency to &lt;strong&gt;gush&lt;/strong&gt; over(滔滔不绝地说) Britain’s bond with America. Before the &lt;strong&gt;referendum&lt;/strong&gt;(公民投票) in 2016, Boris Johnson—now prime minister, then mayor of London—predicted that, outside the European Union, the thriving British would be “even better and more valuable allies of the United States”. Britain’s relationship with America had long been “special”, &lt;strong&gt;enthused&lt;/strong&gt;(使热心) Liam Fox as trade secretary in 2018. But Brexit provided a “&lt;strong&gt;once-in-a-generation&lt;/strong&gt;千载难逢 opportunity to raise it to a new level”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in the week that Britain actually leaves the EU it finds itself at &lt;strong&gt;loggerheads&lt;/strong&gt;(对立) with America on tax, trade and technology. If the British government persists with plans for a digital-services tax that would hit tech giants, America has said it will &lt;strong&gt;retaliate&lt;/strong&gt;(报复) with &lt;strong&gt;punitive&lt;/strong&gt;(惩罚性的) tariffs on British car exports. And despite heavy American lobbying and suggestions that the countries’ intelligence-sharing could be at risk, Mr Johnson decided on January 28th to allow Britain to buy 5G telecoms kit from Huawei of China. Mike Pompeo, America’s secretary of state, had warned against letting China “control the internet of the future”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision on Huawei came two days before Mr Pompeo was due to join his British counterpart, Dominic Raab, in London for a public conversation on “the future of the special relationship”. At first glance, and despite the &lt;strong&gt;croonings&lt;/strong&gt;(低吟) of Brexiteers, that relationship appears to be in poor shape. Thomas Wright of the Brookings Institution, a Washington think-tank, describes it as “in its worst state since the Suez crisis” in 1956.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Wright has catalogued many ways in which President Donald Trump “&lt;strong&gt;tormented&lt;/strong&gt;(折磨)” the previous government, under Theresa May. Although Mr Trump has a better &lt;strong&gt;rapport&lt;/strong&gt;(密切关系) with Mr Johnson than he had with Mrs May, tensions have not disappeared. Meanwhile, competition for America’s attention has been growing. Under the energetic Emmanuel Macron, France emphasises that it is the “oldest ally” of the United States. China’s rise is also &lt;strong&gt;tugging&lt;/strong&gt;(用力拖) America away from Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this adds to a sense of uncertainty, post-Brexit, about Britain’s status and role in the world. The so-called special relationship has always been &lt;strong&gt;lopsided&lt;/strong&gt;(不平衡的): Helmut Schmidt, a German chancellor, once quipped that it was so special only one side knew it existed. But for nearly half a century, membership of the European club allowed the British to stop &lt;strong&gt;fretting&lt;/strong&gt;(使烦恼) too much about their influence in the world. They were “the bridge between the US and Europe”, as Tony Blair, one of the most enthusiastic &lt;strong&gt;proponents&lt;/strong&gt;(支持者) of the special relationship (and an ardent(热情的) Remainer), put it as prime minister in 1997. Britain could wield influence on both sides of the Atlantic. Now that the bridge is breaking, questions about Britain’s power are back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-have-come-to-a-pretty-pass&#34;&gt;Things have come to a pretty pass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the second world war Britain struggled to find its place in America’s shadow. Winston Churchill &lt;strong&gt;envisaged&lt;/strong&gt;(设想) Britain as part of three great circles among the democracies: the Commonwealth, the English-speaking sphere and a united Europe. In 1946, in a speech in Fulton, Missouri, he had proposed a “special relationship” with the United States, a “&lt;strong&gt;fraternal&lt;/strong&gt;(兄弟般的) association” of English-speaking peoples involving not only &lt;strong&gt;kindred&lt;/strong&gt;(相似) societies but military &lt;strong&gt;collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;(合作). Another prime minister, Harold Macmillan, &lt;strong&gt;patronisingly&lt;/strong&gt; positioned Britain as playing Athens to America’s Rome, teaching a “&lt;strong&gt;vulgar&lt;/strong&gt;(粗俗), &lt;strong&gt;bustling&lt;/strong&gt;(忙乱的)” people how to run a rising empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this proved convincing. In 1962 Dean Acheson, a former American secretary of state, concluded that Britain had lost an empire but not found a role. Its attempt to find one away from
Europe, based on a “special relationship” with America and on being the head of a Commonwealth, he said, was “about played out”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining what was then the European Economic Community in 1973 offered something of a solution. As Ray Seitz, an American ambassador to London, noted in a &lt;strong&gt;valedictory&lt;/strong&gt;(告别的) speech in 1994: “If Britain’s voice is less influential in Paris or [Berlin], it is likely to be less influential in Washington.” In Mr Blair’s formulation: “Strong in Europe and strong with the US&amp;hellip;There is no choice between the two. Stronger with one means stronger with the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-romance-is-growing-flat&#34;&gt;Our romance is growing flat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special or not, the relationship has often been &lt;strong&gt;fraught&lt;/strong&gt;(担心的). Apart from the Suez debacle, &lt;strong&gt;friction&lt;/strong&gt; arose between Harold Wilson and Lyndon Johnson over Wilson’s refusal to support the war in Vietnam. Even Margaret Thatcher and Ronald Reagan, who were so &lt;strong&gt;chummy&lt;/strong&gt;(亲密的) that Reagan’s successor, George H.W. Bush, said “he was just &lt;strong&gt;smitten&lt;/strong&gt;(打) by her”, fell out over America’s &lt;strong&gt;invasion&lt;/strong&gt;(入侵) of Grenada in 1983.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet over the years, in several different spheres, America and Britain have grown closer. Some 28 “Nobel prizes have been awarded jointly to people from the two countries. British actors, such as Daniel Craig, are as likely to play an American detective in Hollywood movies as American ones, such as Renée Zellweger, are to put on plummy British accents to play characters such as Bridget Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economic ties are especially deep. New York and London, the world’s top two financial centres, are rivals but they are also intertwined. Nearly a fifth of Britain’s exports go to America, more than double the share going to Germany, the next-biggest partner. America accounts for 15% of Britain’s total trade. American investment in Britain supports an estimated 1.5m jobs, and 1.3m vice versa. Britain attracts more than 10% of American foreign R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as anything, though, it is shared values and habits of co-operation that have bound Britain and America together. Britain, says Nicholas Burns, a former American ambassador to NATO, is “the country we trusted the most, and worked most closely with.” At the State Department, where British diplomats enjoy a level of access afforded no other country, Britain was “the most like-minded country” with America, and “the first port of entry” with the EU on many issues, according to Amanda Sloat, a Europe specialist who served there under the Obama administration. In an Emerson poll from October 2019, 40% of Americans saw Britain as their country’s most valuable ally and strategic partner, far ahead of next-placed Canada on just 22%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This closeness has often been evident at the top, starting with the wartime partnership between Churchill and Franklin Roosevelt. Whether it was the free-market freedom-championing of Thatcher and Reagan or the war-fighting of Mr Blair and George W. Bush, British and American leaders have tended to act in &lt;strong&gt;tandem&lt;/strong&gt;(前一后地).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the questions facing the special relationship today is whether or not the same will apply for Mr Johnson and Mr Trump. They have a lot in common; perhaps unsurprisingly, they openly express &lt;strong&gt;admiration&lt;/strong&gt;(钦佩) for one another. Yet other leaders, including Mr Macron, have learnt that it is unwise to place high hopes in a “&lt;strong&gt;bromance&lt;/strong&gt;(兄弟情)” with Mr Trump. And if Mr Trump expects that Mr Johnson will go along with his wishes on issues such as the Iran nuclear deal or relations with China he is likely to find himself disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Johnson’s own instincts may even lean towards European positions on many issues, from climate change to Ukraine. As long as the Trump administration remains in place, “we appear to be more aligned with the Europeans on values and interests than with the United States,” suggests Sir Peter Westmacott, a former British ambassador to Washington. Federica Mogherini, until recently the EU’s foreign-affairs representative, expects &lt;strong&gt;continuity&lt;/strong&gt;(连续性), too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huawei provided a first test of Britain’s post-Brexit policy. Now two other areas will come to the &lt;strong&gt;fore&lt;/strong&gt;(前部): defence and trade. Traditionally, the Anglo-American relationship has been deepest in military, nuclear and intelligence matters. Britain’s armed forces have fought alongside their ally in every major campaign of the past three decades. “The way we fight is nearly &lt;strong&gt;indistinguishable&lt;/strong&gt;(不能区别的),” says Philip Breedlove, a retired American general who served as NATO’s Supreme Allied Commander Europe from 2013 to 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partly this is down to an unparalleled level of integration. Every major in the British Army goes through a course in America, and more than 1,000 British military and civilian defence staff are based across 29 American states. Some military assets are held virtually in common, while British defence firms are more closely involved than those of any other country in building the F-35 warplane. Britain also depends on America to build, sustain and &lt;strong&gt;defray&lt;/strong&gt;(支出) the costs of its nuclear &lt;strong&gt;arsenal&lt;/strong&gt;(兵工厂).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-like-tomato-and-i-like-tomahto&#34;&gt;You like tomato and I like tomahto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;strong&gt;spooks&lt;/strong&gt;(鬼) lean heavily on one another, too. Britain’s signals-intelligence agency, GCHQ, and its American counterpart, the NSA, are bound by the Five Eyes pact, which includes Australia, Canada and New Zealand. Documents leaked by Edward Snowden, a former NSA contractor(承包人), showed that Britain had a sweet deal: America paid at least £100m to GCHQ in 2009-12 and 60% of Britain’s high-value intelligence was derived from the NSA. But the benefits are not one-sided. Michael Hayden, an ex-NSA director, once told his British counterpart that if Fort Meade, the NSA’s Maryland headquarters, was to suffer a catastrophe, he planned to entrust the machinery of American electronic &lt;strong&gt;espionage&lt;/strong&gt;(间谍) to Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strategic &lt;strong&gt;intimacy&lt;/strong&gt;(亲密) dates to the second world war. However, it is not &lt;strong&gt;immutable&lt;/strong&gt;(不变的). Kori Schake of the American Enterprise Institute (AEI), a think-tank, warns that “Britain is perilously close to becoming just like any other Western military rather than the preferred partner of the US any time rules need enforcing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years the sorest point has been British defence cuts. In 2015 Barack Obama demanded, in terms that would &lt;strong&gt;foreshadow&lt;/strong&gt;(预示) Mr Trump’s &lt;strong&gt;rhetoric&lt;/strong&gt;(花言巧语), that David Cameron, then prime minister, pay his “fair share”. General Ray Odierno, then head of the US Army, said that he was “very concerned” by the belt-tightening, which amounted to an 18% fall in real-terms spending over the previous five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those warnings helped trigger a spending boost, but three years later James Mattis, then Mr Trump’s defence secretary, fired another shot across the bow of his British counterpart. “France and the US have concluded that now is the time to significantly increase our investment in defence,” he warned in a letter, adding &lt;strong&gt;ominously&lt;/strong&gt;(恶兆地): “It is in the best interest of both our nations for the UK to remain the US partner of choice.” That prompted another hurried injection of cash, but Britain has struggled to keep up. The size of its armed forces has fallen for nine consecutive years. Brexit might lead to further reductions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, American diplomatic and military insiders tend to &lt;strong&gt;pooh&lt;/strong&gt;-pooh(藐视) the idea that the relationship is in crisis, or that France could &lt;strong&gt;supplant&lt;/strong&gt;(代替) Britain. “The UK is still our most capable partner militarily, and our most valuable partner politically,” says Rachel Ellehuus, who handled European and NATO policy at the Pentagon(五角大楼) until 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However there are some signs of wavering in Britain. On January 12th Ben Wallace, Britain’s defence secretary, questioned America’s reliability as a partner. Britain was “very dependent” on American &lt;strong&gt;surveillance&lt;/strong&gt;(监督) and air cover, warned Mr Wallace. “We need to diversify our assets,” he added. British spending on American kit is already &lt;strong&gt;slated&lt;/strong&gt;(计划) to run to $32bn over the next decade, around 7% of the defence budget each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the options for diversification are limited. Brexit has left Britain cut out of a new European defence fund and a project to build a European satellite-navigation system. Going it alone is pricey: a proposed British-built alternative constellation would cost around £5bn. So Britain will have a lot to wrestle with as it conducts a comprehensive review of security, defence and foreign policy. Mr Johnson has promised it will be the most &lt;strong&gt;radical&lt;/strong&gt;(激进的) assessment since the end of the cold war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-oh-if-we-call-the-whole-thing-off&#34;&gt;But oh, if we call the whole thing off&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other test of the special relationship, on trade, is likely to be similarly fraught; all the more so given the &lt;strong&gt;rancour&lt;/strong&gt;(深仇) in Congress over the Huawei decision. Tom Cotton, a Republican on the US Senate’s Armed Services Committee, tweeted that “I fear London has freed itself from Brussels only to &lt;strong&gt;cede&lt;/strong&gt;(放弃) &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;/strong&gt;(主权) to Beijing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the desire for a deal is not in doubt. Both sides are aiming for a comprehensive free-trade agreement, which could &lt;strong&gt;dismantle&lt;/strong&gt;(拆除) non-tariff barriers. Negotiators share an interest in strong intellectual-property protection, recognition for each other’s professional qualifications and maintaining the free flow of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Britain really wanted, it could probably get a deal in relatively short order. America has a template trade deal that it tries to push on all of its negotiating partners. David Henig of the European Centre for International Political Economy, a think-tank, reckons Britain could sign up to most of the text on tariff reductions and services without a &lt;strong&gt;hitch&lt;/strong&gt;(麻烦). As a gesture, the Americans could offer some special access to their public-&lt;strong&gt;procurement&lt;/strong&gt;(采购) market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, American officials have been helping to bring their British counterparts up to speed, in some cases informing them of stumbling-blocks in negotiations with the EU. The warmth stems only partly from a genuine wish to strengthen their relationship. It also reflects a desire to &lt;strong&gt;thumb American noses&lt;/strong&gt;(嗤之以鼻) at the EU—and pull Britain away from its regulatory orbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some crucial areas, Britain is going to have to choose between the American system of regulation and the European one. Take the issue of food standards, often simplified to a debate about &lt;strong&gt;chlorinated&lt;/strong&gt; chicken(氯化鸡). The EU bans its import on the basis of the precautionary principle, which says that there must be scientific evidence proving something is safe for it to be allowed. America &lt;strong&gt;flips&lt;/strong&gt;(掷) that burden of proof; in order for a product to be banned there must be scientific evidence proving it is unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American negotiators &lt;strong&gt;scoff&lt;/strong&gt;(嘲笑 that the EU’S approach is “unscientific”. Regardless, if Britons opt for the American way, they may quickly find themselves &lt;strong&gt;embroiled&lt;/strong&gt;(使卷入) in the EU’s non-tariff barriers for their “own products. The EU has made it clear that any future free-trade deal with Britain will have to include provisions to prevent any “unfair competitive advantage” that Britain could get by &lt;strong&gt;undercutting&lt;/strong&gt; its environmental and regulatory measures. To put it another way: if Britain wants to diverge from the EU’s standards and follow an American model instead, its market access to its biggest and closest neighbour will suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If negotiators get &lt;strong&gt;bogged&lt;/strong&gt;(陷于泥沼的) down, as they probably will, then they could aim instead for a quick and shallow deal, delivering political wins on both sides of the pond. Such a deal could &lt;strong&gt;defuse&lt;/strong&gt;(平息) the dispute over digital-services taxes, or perhaps America’s complaints over Britain’s subsidies for Airbus, a European aircraft manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these potential &lt;strong&gt;hurdles&lt;/strong&gt;(障碍), leaving the EU does not mean Britain has lost all its leverage with the country Iran dubbed “the Great Satan” to Britain’s “little Satan”. Britain can still draw on a depth of diplomatic capital that offers it &lt;strong&gt;clout&lt;/strong&gt;(影响力). It remains in the G7 and the G20 and plays a big role in NATO. Britain has a wide network through the Commonwealth and earns influence as a major player in development aid. Not least, it retains one of the five permanent seats on the UN Security Council. As the country emerges from &lt;strong&gt;agonising&lt;/strong&gt;(烦恼的) over the Brexit negotiations, it can start to devote more energy to working out how to make the most of these assets under its new, semi-connected status with the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, whatever the intrinsic merits of the Huawei decision—the British view was that security risks could be managed and that the alternative suppliers were not yet up to scratch—it dispels(驱散) the idea that a weakened Britain leaving the EU will always bend to America’s will. When Britain &lt;strong&gt;ingratiates&lt;/strong&gt;(使迎合) itself with America, things do not necessarily end well, as Mr Blair’s enthusiasm for the war in Iraq showed. A clear-headed view of the country’s national interests (which in the Huawei case include Britain’s wish for strong trade relations with China) serves it best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the constraints of the EU, Britain could have some scope to be more &lt;strong&gt;agile&lt;/strong&gt;(敏捷的). Take sanctions. It is true that Britain is losing the ability to champion these through the EU. But it also no longer has to be bound by the need to &lt;strong&gt;thrash&lt;/strong&gt; out(解决) lowest-common-denominator agreement. It could, potentially, take the initiative on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;then-that-may-break-my-heart&#34;&gt;Then that may break my heart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some would like to see Britain take the lead in areas where, for now, America seems to have lost interest, such as championing democracy. (Though that would mean standing up to China.) Because Britain knows America so well it has “a huge opportunity to help countries trying to deal with [it]&amp;hellip;do it more &lt;strong&gt;nimbly&lt;/strong&gt;(敏捷地) and more strategically,” says Ms Schake of the AEI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Britain could remain in the bridge business. The two countries may never regain the first-name closeness shared by “Ron” and Margaret or even George and Tony. But a different American administration could both &lt;strong&gt;rekindle&lt;/strong&gt;(重新点燃) something of that romance, as well as help its ally remain closely connected with the continent. For now, however, Mr Trump seems to favour a divide-and-conquer approach. And that threatens the &lt;strong&gt;ardour&lt;/strong&gt;(激情) between Boris and Donald.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;titan: a very strong or important person SYN giant. e.g., a titan of the Hollywood film industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gush: to speak in an extremely enthusiastic way. e.g., Everyone has been gushing over/about the baby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;referendum: when people vote in order to make a decision about a particular subject, rather than voting for a person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enthuse: to talk about something in a very interested or excited way. e.g., Rick was there, enthusing about life in Australia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loggerheads: be at loggerheads (with somebody).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;retaliate: to do something bad to someone because they have done something bad to you → hit back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;torment: severe mental or physical suffering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rapport: friendly agreement and understanding between people. e.g., He had an excellent rapport with his patients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tug: to pull with one or more short, quick pulls. e.g., The woman gently tugged his arm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lopsided: unequal or uneven, especially in an unfair way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fret: to worry about something, especially when there is no need. e.g., She’s always fretting about the children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proponent: someone who supports something or persuades people to do something. e.g., Steinem has always been a strong proponent of women’s rights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;envisage: to think that something is likely to happen in the future. e.g., I don’t envisage working with him again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fraternal: showing a special friendliness to other people because you share interests or ideas with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vulgar: not behaving politely in social situations. e.g., vulgar behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bustle: to move around quickly, looking very busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;valedictory: a speech or statement in which you say goodbye when you are leaving a school, job etc, especially on a formal occasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fraught: full of anxiety or worry. e.g., a fraught situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;friction:  disagreement, angry feelings, or unfriendliness between people SYN tension. e.g., Having my mother living with us causes friction at home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chummy: informal friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smite: to hit something with a lot of force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tandem: a group of two people or things that work together or are associated with each other. e.g., The two products can be used alone or in tandem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defray: to pay for (something). e.g., This will defray the costs/expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arsenal: a collection of weapons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spook: spy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;espionage: the activity of spying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intimacy: an intimate quality or state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;immutable: unable to be changed. e.g., the immutable laws of nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foreshadow: to give a suggestion of (something that has not yet happened). e.g., Her early interest in airplanes foreshadowed her later career as a pilot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rhetoric: language that is intended to influence people and that may not be honest or reasonable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ominously: suggesting that something bad is going to happen in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pooh: used to show that you think an idea, suggestion, etc., is not very good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supplant: to take the place of. e.g., DVDs have supplanted videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slate: to arrange or plan for something to happen. e.g., She is slated to become the company&amp;rsquo;s next president.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rancour: an angry feeling of hatred or dislike for someone who has treated you unfairly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cede: to give control of (something) to another person. e.g., The state had to cede part of their territory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sovereignty: a country&amp;rsquo;s independent authority and the right to govern itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dismantle: to destroy (something) in an orderly way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hitch: a hidden problem that makes something more complicated or difficult to do. e.g., The plan went off without a hitch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;procurement: to get (something) by some action or effort. e.g., Birth certificates are needed for procurement of a marriage license.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scoff: to laugh at and talk about someone or something in a way that shows disapproval and a lack of respect. e.g., He scoffed at the idea/notion/suggestion of her becoming an actress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embroil: to involve (someone or something) in conflict or difficulties. e.g., They were embroiled in a complicated lawsuit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undercut: to make (something) weaker or less effective. e.g., Her behavior undercuts her own credibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bog down: to cause (something) to sink in wet ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defuse: to make (something) less serious, difficult, or tense. e.g., Skilled negotiators helped defuse the crisis/situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hurdle: something that makes an achievement difficult. e.g., The company faces severe financial hurdles this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clout: the power to influence or control situations. e.g., She used her political clout to have another school built.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agonising: very mentally or physically painful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ingratiate: to gain favor or approval for (yourself) by doing or saying things that people like. e.g., She has tried to ingratiate herself with voters by promising a tax cut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agile: able to move quickly and easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thrash: to produce (something, such as an agreement or plan) by a lot of discussion. e.g., thrash out a plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nimbly: able to move quickly, easily, and lightly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rekindle: to cause (something, such as a feeling) to be strong or active again. e.g., The movie has rekindled public interest in the trial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ardour: a strong feeling of energy or eagerness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《经济学人》青春期真的能抑制吗</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E9%9D%92%E6%98%A5%E6%9C%9F%E7%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E8%83%BD%E6%8A%91%E5%88%B6%E5%90%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 11:03:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6%E4%BA%BA%E9%9D%92%E6%98%A5%E6%9C%9F%E7%9C%9F%E7%9A%84%E8%83%BD%E6%8A%91%E5%88%B6%E5%90%97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-to-do-about-puberty-blockers&#34;&gt;What to do about puberty blockers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;drugs-offered-to-transgender-children-need-to-be-used-more-cautiously&#34;&gt;Drugs offered to transgender children need to be used more cautiously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arising number of girls wish to be boys and boys wish to be girls and a rising number of them are taking drugs to block &lt;strong&gt;puberty&lt;/strong&gt;(青春期). In Britain cases of children being treated for gender &lt;strong&gt;dysphoria&lt;/strong&gt;(烦躁不安) by the National Health Service remain rare, but in the past decade they have climbed at a rate of $5\%$ year on year (see chart). In America the number of gender &lt;strong&gt;clinics&lt;/strong&gt;(诊所) treating children has increased from just one in 2007 to perhaps 50 today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has bothered lawmakers. In America several states want to ban giving puberty-blocking drugs to children (see United States section). In Britain the high court is considering the judicial review of a clinic which complainants believe has been handing out puberty blockers too freely (see Britain section).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of such drugs raises &lt;strong&gt;thorny&lt;/strong&gt;(多刺的) questions about who decides what can happen to a child’s body and why. Put aside the culture wars, if you can. This debate should be settled in the interests of the child. Yet those can be very hard to &lt;strong&gt;discern&lt;/strong&gt;(识别).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puberty blockers prevent adolescents from developing secondary sexual characteristics like breasts or a beard. They almost always set off a cascade of interventions that involve “cross-sex” hormones and later may also include gender-reassignment surgery. The main purpose of puberty blockers is to bring comfort to people with gender dysphoria, by &lt;strong&gt;sparing&lt;/strong&gt;(使&amp;hellip;免遭) them the experience of, say, becoming more like a woman if they are a girl who wishes to be a boy. They also make most future surgery less severe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the combination of puberty blockers and cross-sex hormones also leads to irreversible changes which, if they start early in puberty, include &lt;strong&gt;sterility&lt;/strong&gt;(不育). About a dozen studies of gender-dysphoric children who did not take puberty blockers have found that most of them, if supported by counselling, are happy with their sex once they emerge from puberty. The share often cited is $85\%$ and many of them turn out to be gay. One sign that something is wrong is that more people are “detransitioning”—re-identifying with their biological sex. Most of them are girls who wanted to be boys when they were in their teens. If they took puberty blockers and then cross-sex hormones early they would be sterile for life, even if they did not have &lt;strong&gt;hysterectomies&lt;/strong&gt;(子宫切除).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, there is no way to distinguish the $15\%$ or so of children who will transition successfully from the $85\%$ who might have been happy with the gender of their birth if they had received &lt;strong&gt;counselling&lt;/strong&gt;(辅导) alone. Some claim that withholding puberty blockers adds to the burden on vulnerable children with gender-dysphoria and may lead to higher rates of suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing whom to treat is a judgment of Solomon. The decision to intervene is made harder by a &lt;strong&gt;reckless&lt;/strong&gt;(鲁莽的) &lt;strong&gt;disregard&lt;/strong&gt;(忽视) for data. The academic studies &lt;strong&gt;purporting&lt;/strong&gt;(声称) to show the higher suicide risk among trans children are &lt;strong&gt;unconvincing&lt;/strong&gt;(令人难以信服的). Clinics do not publish enough studies on the effects of various treatments on their patients. Too little research compares children who have had treatment with those who have not. The field needs a better understanding of the long-term effects of puberty blockers and cross-sex hormones. Every child who is treated should be enrolled in a long-term follow-up study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be with their informed consent. But so should the treatment itself. Today children and parents are not always fully informed about the potentially grave consequences of starting on puberty blockers. Their effects are often described as largely reversible—and the effects of cross-sex hormones that are almost always taken with them are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ban puberty blockers in all circumstances would be unjustified. Not only would it be harsh on some children, but it would also leave the issue permanently obscured for lack of new research. However, today’s rush into treatment &lt;strong&gt;smacks&lt;/strong&gt;(打) of a &lt;strong&gt;fad&lt;/strong&gt;(时尚). Many adolescents feel unhappy with the way they were made. Transitioning will be &lt;strong&gt;solace&lt;/strong&gt;(安慰) for some. But for others it will be a dreadful mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;take-home message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;puberty: the stage in people&amp;rsquo;s lives when they develop from a child into an adult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dysphoria: severe unhappiness, especially a person&amp;rsquo;s feeling of being very uncomfortable in their body or of being in the wrong body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thorny: A thorny problem or subject is difficult to deal with. e.g., the thorny issue of taxation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discern: to notice or understand something by thinking about it carefully. e.g., Officials were keen to discern how much public support there was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spare: to prevent someone from having to experience something unpleasant. e.g., Luckily, I was spared the embarrassment of having to sing in front of everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;counselling: the job or process of listening to someone and giving that person advice about their problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reckless: doing something dangerous and not worrying about the risks and the possible results. e.g., He was found guilty of reckless driving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disregard: the fact of showing no care or respect for something. e.h., What amazes me is her complete disregard for anyone else&amp;rsquo;s opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;purport: to pretend to be or to do something, especially in a way that is not easy to believe. e.g., The study purports to show an increase in the incidence of the disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;smack: to hit something hard. e.g., I never smack my children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fad: a style, activity, or interest that is very popular for a short period of time. e.g., There was a fad for wearing ripped jeans a few years ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solace: help and comfort when you are feeling sad or worried. e.g., Music was a great solace to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>