<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>新概念 on MH&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/tags/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 新概念 on MH&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 09:38:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://minghaochen.github.io/tags/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》24</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5424/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 09:38:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5424/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beauty&#34;&gt;Beauty&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do glimpses of beauty, either in nature or art, often suggest to the human mind?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;often suggest to xxx 对xxx产生启发的感觉&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A young man sees a sunset and, unable to understand or to express the emotion that it rouses in him, concludes that it must be the gateway to a world that lies beyond. It is difficult for any of us in moments of intense &lt;strong&gt;aesthetic&lt;/strong&gt; experience to resist the suggestion that we are catching a glimpse of a light that shines down to us from a different &lt;strong&gt;realm&lt;/strong&gt; of existence, different and, because the experience is intensely moving, in some way higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;in moments of xxx 在xxx时刻&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;aesthetic  / iːsˈθɛtɪk, ɪs- / Aesthetic is used to talk about beauty or art, and people&amp;rsquo;s appreciation of beautiful things. 审美的&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;resist  / rɪˈzɪst / If you resist something such as a change, you refuse to accept it and try to prevent it. 抵制&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;realm  / rɛlm / You can use realm to refer to any area of activity, interest, or thought. (活动、兴趣、思想的) 领域&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, though the &lt;strong&gt;gleams&lt;/strong&gt; blind and dazzle, yet do they convey a hint of beauty and &lt;strong&gt;serenity&lt;/strong&gt; greater than we have known or imagined. Greater too than we can describe, for language, which was invented to convey the meanings of this world, cannot readily be fitted to the uses of another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gleam  / ɡliːm / If an object or a surface gleams, it reflects light because it is shiny and clean. 闪光&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yet do they xxx； 但它确实xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serenity /si&amp;rsquo;renəti/ 平静，宁静&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;than we have known or imagined； 不曾经历或无法想象&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readily / ˈrɛdɪlɪ / You also use readily to say that something can be done or obtained quickly and easily. For example, if you say that something can be readily understood, you mean that people can understand it quickly and easily. 容易地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That all great art has this power of suggesting a world beyond is undeniable. In some moods, Nature shares it. There is no sky in June so blue that it does not point forward to a &lt;strong&gt;bluer&lt;/strong&gt;, no sunset so beautiful that it does not waken the vision of a greater beauty, a vision which passes before it is fully glimpsed, and in passing leaves an indefinable longing and regret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx is undeniable； 不可否认 既成事实的感觉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in some moods 在某种状态下&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;longing / ˈlɒŋɪŋ / If you feel longing or a longing for something, you have a rather sad feeling because you want it very much. 渴望&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;indefinable / ˌɪndɪˈfaɪnəbəl / An indefinable quality or feeling cannot easily be described. 难以形容的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, if this world is not merely a bad joke, life a &lt;strong&gt;vulgar&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;flare&lt;/strong&gt; amid the cool &lt;strong&gt;radiance&lt;/strong&gt; of the stars, and existence an empty laugh &lt;strong&gt;braying&lt;/strong&gt; across the mysteries; if these &lt;strong&gt;intimations&lt;/strong&gt; of a something behind and beyond are not evil humour born of indigestion, or &lt;strong&gt;whimsies&lt;/strong&gt; sent by the &lt;strong&gt;devil&lt;/strong&gt; to mock and madden us, if, in a word, beauty means something, yet we must not seek to interpret the meaning. If we glimpse the unutterable, it is unwise to try to utter it, nor should we seek to invest with significance that which we cannot grasp. Beauty in terms of our human meanings is meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bray  / breɪ / to make a similar sound, as in laughing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is not merely xx; 不只是&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vulgar  / ˈvʌlɡə / If you describe something as vulgar, you think it is in bad taste or of poor artistic quality. 粗俗的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radiance  / ˈreɪdɪəns / Radiance is a glowing light shining from something. 光辉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intimation /,ɪntɪ&amp;rsquo;meʃən/ 暗示 intimations of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humour  / ˈhjuːmə / If you are in a good humour, you feel cheerful and happy, and are pleasant to people. If you are in a bad humour, you feel bad tempered and unhappy, and are unpleasant to people. 心情&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yyy born of xxx; 由xxx引起的yyy怎么说&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whimsy  / ˈwɪmzɪ /  Whimsy is behaviour that is unusual, playful, and unpredictable, rather than having any serious reason or purpose behind it. 异想天开的行为&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unutterable  / ʌnˈʌtərəbəl / 无法用言语表达的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is unwise to xxxx, nor should we seek to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in terms of 按照xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》22~23</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5422~23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 21:02:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5422~23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;knowledge-and-progress&#34;&gt;Knowledge and progress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does the idea of progress &lt;strong&gt;loom&lt;/strong&gt; so large in the modern world ? Surely because progress of a particular kind is actually taking place around us and is becoming more and more &lt;strong&gt;manifest&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loom / luːm / If something looms over you, it appears as a large or unclear shape, often in a frightening way. 赫然出现;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manifest / ˈmænɪˌfɛst / If you say that something is manifest, you mean that it is clearly true and that nobody would disagree with it if they saw it or considered it. 明显的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although mankind has undergone no general improvement in intelligence or morality, it has made extraordinary progress the accumulation of knowledge. Knowledge began to increase as soon as the thoughts of one individual could be communicated to another by means of speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yyy began to zzz as soon as xxx; 一旦xxx yyy就zzz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by means of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the invention of writing, a great advance was made, for knowledge could then be not only communicated but also stored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for xxx could then be not only yyy but also zzz; xxx不仅能 yyy 而且能zzz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries made education possible, and education in its turn added to libraries: the growth of knowledge followed a kind of compound-interest law, which was greatly enhanced by the invention of printing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in its turn 反过来&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compound interest law 雪球增长的规律&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this was comparatively slow until, with the coming science, the tempo was suddenly raised. Then knowledge began to be accumulated according to a systematic plan. The &lt;strong&gt;trickle&lt;/strong&gt; became a stream; the stream has now become a &lt;strong&gt;torrent&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trickle  / ˈtrɪkəl / When a liquid trickles, or when you trickle it, it flows slowly in a thin stream. 使细流; 细流&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;torrent  / ˈtɒrənt / A torrent is a lot of water falling or flowing rapidly or violently. 急流&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, as soon as new knowledge is acquired, it is now turned to practical account. What is called &amp;lsquo;modern civilization&amp;rsquo; is not the result of a balanced development of all man&amp;rsquo;s nature, but of accumulated knowledge applied to practical life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a balanced development of xxx; xxx的平衡发展&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all man&amp;rsquo;s nature 人的天性&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem now facing humanity is: What is going to be done with all this knowledge ? As is so often pointed out, knowledge is a two-edged weapon which can be used equally for good or evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the problem now facing xxx is yyy; 现在xxx面临的问题是yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now being used indifferently for both. Could any &lt;strong&gt;spectacle&lt;/strong&gt;, for instance, be more grimly &lt;strong&gt;whimsical&lt;/strong&gt; than that of gunners using science to shatter men&amp;rsquo;s bodies while, close at hand, surgeons use it to restore them ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spectacle / ˈspɛktəkəl / A spectacle is a strange or interesting sight. 奇观&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whimsical  / ˈwɪmzɪkəl /  A whimsical person or idea is unusual, playful, and unpredictable, rather than serious and practical. 异想天开的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shatter / ˈʃætə / If something shatters or is shattered, it breaks into a lot of small pieces. 粉碎&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to ask ourselves very seriously what will happen if this twofold use of knowledge, with its ever-increasing
power, continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;twofold  / ˈtuːˌfəʊld / 双重的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ever-increasing 日益增长&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bird-flight&#34;&gt;Bird flight&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No two sorts of birds practise quite the same sort of flight; the varieties are infinite, but two classes may be roughly seen. Any ship that crosses the pacific is accompanied for many days by the smaller &lt;strong&gt;albatross&lt;/strong&gt;, which may keep company with the &lt;strong&gt;vessel&lt;/strong&gt; for an hour without visible or more than occasional movement of wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;albatross  / ˈælbəˌtrɒs / An albatross is a very large white seabird. 信天翁&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vessel  / ˈvɛsəl / A vessel is a ship or large boat. 船; 舰&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The currents of air that the walls of the ship direct upwards, as well as in the line of its course are enough to give the great bird with its immense wings sufficient &lt;strong&gt;sustenance&lt;/strong&gt; and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sustenance / ˈsʌstənəns / Sustenance is food or drink which a person, animal, or plant needs to remain alive and healthy. 食物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;albatross&lt;/strong&gt; is the king of the &lt;strong&gt;gliders&lt;/strong&gt;, the class of fliers which &lt;strong&gt;harness&lt;/strong&gt; the air to their purpose, but must yield to its opposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;glider / ˈɡlaɪdə / A glider is an aircraft without an engine, which flies by floating on air currents. 滑翔机&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harness  / ˈhɑːnɪs / If you harness something such as an emotion or natural source of energy, you bring it under your control and use it. 利用&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yield  / jiːld /  If you yield to someone or something, you stop resisting them. 屈服&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the contrary school the duck is supreme. It comes nearer to the engines with which man has &amp;lsquo;conquered&amp;rsquo; the air, as he boasts. Duck, and like them the pigeons, are &lt;strong&gt;endowed&lt;/strong&gt; with steel-like muscles, that are a good part of the weight of the bird, and these will &lt;strong&gt;ply&lt;/strong&gt; the short wings with irresistible power that they can bore for long distances through an opposite &lt;strong&gt;gale&lt;/strong&gt; before exhaustion follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the contrary school 相对的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it comes nearer to xxx；它更近乎于xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;endow  / ɪnˈdaʊ / You say that someone is endowed with a particular desirable ability, characteristic, or possession when they have it by chance or by birth. 天生赋予&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ply  / plaɪ / If you ply someone with food or drink, you keep giving them more of it. 不断供给&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gale  / ɡeɪl / A gale is a very strong wind. 大风&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exhaustion  / ɪɡˈzɔːstʃən / Exhaustion is the state of being so tired that you have no energy left. 精疲力竭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;strong&gt;humbler&lt;/strong&gt; followers, such as partridges, have a like power of strong &lt;strong&gt;propulsion&lt;/strong&gt;, but soon tire. You may pick them up in utter exhaustion, if wind over the sea has driven them to a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;their humbler followers，such as yyy, zzz；次于他们的xxx，yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humble  / ˈhʌmbəl /  People with low social status are sometimes described as humble. (社会地位) 低下的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propulsion  / prəˈpʌlʃən /  Propulsion is the power that moves something, especially a vehicle, in a forward direction. 推进力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utter  / ˈʌtə / You use utter to emphasize that something is great in extent, degree, or amount. 完全的; 彻底的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;swallow&lt;/strong&gt; shares the virtues of both schools in highest measure. It tires not, nor does it boast of its power; but belongs to the air, travelling it may be six thousand miles to and from its northern nesting home, feeding its flown young as it flies and slipping through a medium that seems to help its passage
even when the wind is adverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;swallow / ˈswɒləʊ / A swallow is a kind of small bird with pointed wings and a forked tail. 燕子&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in highest measure 充分的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it xxx not, nor does it yyy； 既不xxx也不xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slip  / slɪp /&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passage  / ˈpæsɪdʒ /  旅程，行程&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such birds do us good, though we no longer take omens from their flight on this side and that, and even the most &lt;strong&gt;superstitious&lt;/strong&gt; villagers no longer take off their hats to the &lt;strong&gt;magpie&lt;/strong&gt; and wish it good-morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;omen  / ˈəʊmən /  If you say that something is an omen, you think it indicates what is likely to happen in the future and whether it will be good or bad. 预兆&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》21</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5421/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 20:44:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5421/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;william-s-hart-and-the-early-western-film&#34;&gt;William S. Hart and the early ‘Western’ film&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William S. Hart was, perhaps, the greatest of all Western stars, for unlike Gary Cooper and John Wayne he appeared in nothing but Westerns. From 1914 to 1924 he was supreme and unchallenged. It was Hart who created the basic formula of the Western film, and devised the protagonist he played in every film he made, the good-bad man, the accidental, noble-&lt;strong&gt;outlaw&lt;/strong&gt;, or the honest-but-framed cowboy, or the &lt;strong&gt;sheriff&lt;/strong&gt; made suspect by vicious gossip; in short, the individual in conflict with himself and his frontier environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protagonist / prəʊˈtæɡənɪst / A protagonist in a play, novel, or real event is one of the main people in it. (戏剧、小说或真实事件里的) 主人公&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outlaw / ˈaʊtˌlɔː /   An outlaw is a criminal who is hiding from the authorities. 逃犯u&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frame  / freɪm /  If someone frames an innocent person, they make other people think that that person is guilty of a crime, by lying or inventing evidence. 诬陷&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sheriff  / ˈʃɛrɪf /   In the United States, a sheriff is a person who is elected to make sure that the law is obeyed in a particular county. (美国的) 县治安官&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vicious  / ˈvɪʃəs / A vicious remark is cruel and intended to upset someone. 恶毒的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nothing but xxx 只在xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made suspect by xxx 被怀疑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike most of his &lt;strong&gt;contemporaries&lt;/strong&gt; in Hollywood, Hart actually knew something of the old West. He had lived in it as a child when it was already disappearing, and his hero was firmly rooted in his memories and experiences, and in both the history and the mythology of the vanished frontier. And although no period or place in American history has been more absurdly romanticized, myth and reality did join hands in at least one &lt;strong&gt;arena&lt;/strong&gt;, the conflict between the individual and &lt;strong&gt;encroaching&lt;/strong&gt; civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contemporary / kənˈtɛmprərɪ / Someone&amp;rsquo;s contemporary is a person who is or was alive at the same time as them. 同时代的人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mythology  / mɪˈθɒlədʒɪ / Mythology is a group of myths, especially all the myths from a particular country, religion, or culture. 神话&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arena  / əˈriːnə /    An arena is a place where sports, entertainments, and other public events take place. It has seats around it where people sit and watch. 竞技场&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encroach  / ɪnˈkrəʊtʃ / If one thing encroaches on another, the first thing spreads or becomes stronger, and slowly begins to restrict the power, range, or effectiveness of the second thing. 逐步侵犯&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;firmly rooted in xxx 深深地扎根&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men accustomed to struggling for survival against the elements and Indian were &lt;strong&gt;bewildered&lt;/strong&gt; by politicians, bankers and business-men, and &lt;strong&gt;unhorsed&lt;/strong&gt; by fences, laws and alien &lt;strong&gt;taboos&lt;/strong&gt;. Hart&amp;rsquo;s good-bad man was always an outsider, always one of the &lt;strong&gt;disinherited&lt;/strong&gt;, and if he found it necessary to shoot a sheriff or rob a bank along the way, his early audiences found it easy to understand and forgive, especially when it was Hart who, in the end, overcame the attacking Indians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bewilder / bɪˈwɪldə / If something bewilders you, it is so confusing or difficult that you cannot understand it. 使迷惑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unhorse  / ʌnˈhɔːs / to knock or throw from a horse 把人推(扔)下马&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taboo  / təˈbuː / A taboo against a subject or activity is a social custom to avoid doing that activity or talking about that subject, because people find them embarrassing or offensive. 禁忌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disinherit  / ˌdɪsɪnˈhɛrɪt / If you disinherit someone such as your son or daughter, you arrange that they will not become the owner of your money and property after your death, usually because they have done something that you do not approve of. 剥夺财产继承权&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audiences in the second decade of the twentieth century found it pleasant to escape to a time when life, though hard, was relatively simple. We still do; living in a world in which undeclared aggression, war, &lt;strong&gt;hypocrisy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;chicanery&lt;/strong&gt;, anarchy and &lt;strong&gt;impending&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;immolation&lt;/strong&gt; are part of our daily lives, we all want a code to live by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hypocrisy  / hɪˈpɒkrəsɪ / If you accuse someone of hypocrisy, you mean that they pretend to have qualities, beliefs, or feelings that they do not really have. 虚伪&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chicanery  / ʃɪˈkeɪnərɪ / Chicanery is using cleverness to cheat people. 耍花招对他人的哄骗&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impending  / ɪmˈpɛndɪŋ / An impending event is one that is going to happen very soon. 即将发生的 [正式]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》20</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5420/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 18:51:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5420/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;snake-poison&#34;&gt;Snake poison&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How it came about that snakes manufactured poison is a mystery. Over the periods their &lt;strong&gt;saliva&lt;/strong&gt;, a mild, digestive juice like our own, was converted into a poison that &lt;strong&gt;defies&lt;/strong&gt; analysis even today. It was not forced upon them by the survival competition; they could have caught and lived on &lt;strong&gt;prey&lt;/strong&gt; without using poison just as the thousands of non-poisonous snakes still do. Poison to a snake is merely a luxury; it enables it to get its food with very little effort, no more effort than one bite. And why only snakes ? Cats, for instance, would be greatly helped; no running fights with large, fierce rats or &lt;strong&gt;tussles&lt;/strong&gt; with grown rabbits- just a bite and no more effort needed. In fact it would be an assistance to all the carnivores&amp;ndash;though it would be a two-edged weapon -When they fought each other. But, of the &lt;strong&gt;vertebrates&lt;/strong&gt;, unpredictable Nature selected only snakes (and one lizard). One wonders also why Nature, with some snakes &lt;strong&gt;concocted&lt;/strong&gt; poison of such extreme &lt;strong&gt;potency&lt;/strong&gt;.
In the conversion of saliva into poison one might suppose that a fixed process took place. It did not; some snakes manufactured a poison different in every respect from that of others, as different as &lt;strong&gt;arsenic&lt;/strong&gt; is from &lt;strong&gt;strychnine&lt;/strong&gt;, and having different effects. One poison acts on the nerves, the other on the blood.
The makers of the nerve poison include the mambas (树眼镜蛇) and the cobras (眼镜蛇) and their &lt;strong&gt;venom&lt;/strong&gt; is called neurotoxic. Vipers (adders) and rattlesnakes (响尾蛇) manufacture the blood poison, which is known as haemolytic. Both poisons are unpleasant, but by far the more unpleasant is the blood poison. It is said that the nerve poison is the more &lt;strong&gt;primitive&lt;/strong&gt; of the two, that the blood poison is , so to speak, a newer product from an improved formula. Be that as it may, the nerve poison does its business with man far more quickly than the blood poison. This,however,means nothing. Snakes did not acquire their poison for use against man but for use against prey such as rats and mice, and the effects on these of &lt;strong&gt;viperine&lt;/strong&gt; poison is almost immediate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saliva / səˈlaɪvə / Saliva is the watery liquid that forms in your mouth and helps you to chew and digest food. 唾液&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defy  / dɪˈfaɪ /  If something defies description or understanding, it is so strange, extreme, or surprising that it is almost impossible to understand or explain. 使不可能 (理解或解释)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prey / preɪ / A creature&amp;rsquo;s prey are the creatures that it hunts and eats in order to live. 猎物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tussle  / ˈtʌsəl /   If one person tussles with another, or if they tussle, they get hold of each other and struggle or fight. 扭打&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carnivore 食肉类&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vertebrate  / ˈvɜːtɪˌbreɪt / A vertebrate is a creature that has a spine. Mammals, birds, reptiles, and fish are vertebrates. 脊椎动物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concoct  / kənˈkɒkt /  If you concoct something, especially something unusual, you make it by mixing several things together. 调制&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;potency / ˈpəʊtənsɪ / The potency of a drug, poison, or other chemical is its strength. (毒品、药品等的) 效力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arsenic / ˈɑːsənɪk / Arsenic is a very strong poison that can kill people. 砒霜&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venom  / ˈvɛnəm / The venom of a creature such as a snake or spider is the poison that it puts into your body when it bites or stings you. (蛇或蜘蛛等分泌的) 毒液&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;viper / ˈvaɪpə / A viper is a small poisonous snake found mainly in Europe. 蝰蛇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;primitive  / ˈprɪmɪtɪv / Primitive means belonging to a very early period in the development of an animal or plant. 原始的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how it came about that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over the periods 经过漫长时间&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was converted into xxx 演化成xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx to a xxx is xxx  xxx对xxx来说&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it enables it to xxx 他使得xxx能够xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it would be an assistance to xxx 能够从中受益&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a two-edged weapon 双刃剑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be that as it may 不过&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx,however, xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》16~17</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5416~17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:22:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5416~17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-modern-city&#34;&gt;The modern city&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the organization of industrial life the influence of the factory upon the physiological and mental state of the workers has been completely neglected. Modern industry is based on the conception of the maximum production at lowest cost, in order that an individual or a group of individuals may earn as much money as possible. It has expanded without any idea of the true nature of the human beings who run the machines, and without giving any consideration to the effects produced on the individuals and on their descendants by the artificial mode of existence imposed by the factory. The great cities have been built with no regard for us. The shape and dimensions of the skyscrapers depend entirely on the necessity of obtaining the maximum income per square foot of ground, and of offering to the tenants offices and apartments that please them. This caused the construction of gigantic buildings where too large masses of human beings are crowded together. Civilized men like such a way of living. While they enjoy the comfort and *&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;banal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;* luxury of their dwelling, they do not realize that they are deprived of the necessities of life. The modern city consists of &lt;strong&gt;monstrous&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;edifices&lt;/strong&gt; and of dark, narrow streets full of petrol &lt;strong&gt;fumes&lt;/strong&gt;, coal dust, and toxic gases, &lt;strong&gt;torn&lt;/strong&gt; by the noise of the taxi-cabs, lorries and buses, and &lt;strong&gt;thronged&lt;/strong&gt; ceaselessly by great crowds. Obviously, it has no been planned for the good of its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx is based on the conception of yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zzz, in order that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;without any idea of the xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;without giving any consideration to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;depend entirely on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this caused xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;banal / bəˈnɑːl, -ˈnæl /  If you describe something as banal, you do not like it because you think it is so ordinary that it is not at all effective or interesting. 平庸乏味的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monstrous / ˈmɒnstrəs / If you describe an unpleasant thing as monstrous, you mean that it is extremely large in size or extent. (令人不悦的事物) 巨大的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edifice / ˈɛdɪfɪs /   An edifice is a large and impressive building. 大厦&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fume / fjuːm / Fumes are the unpleasant and often unhealthy smoke and gases that are produced by fires or by things such as chemicals, fuel, or cooking. (难闻且常有害的) 烟气&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lorry  / ˈlɒrɪ / A lorry is a large vehicle that is used to transport goods by road. 卡车&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;throng  / θrɒŋ /  When people throng somewhere, they go there in great numbers. (人群) 涌向&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ceaselessly 不停地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the good of xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-man-made-disease&#34;&gt;A man-made disease&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of the settlement of Australia, enterprising settlers unwisely introduced the European rabbit. This rabbit had no natural enemies in the &lt;strong&gt;Antipodes&lt;/strong&gt;, so that it multiplied with that &lt;strong&gt;promiscuous&lt;/strong&gt; abandon characteristic of rabbits. It overran a whole continent. It caused devastation by &lt;strong&gt;burrowing&lt;/strong&gt; and by devouring the &lt;strong&gt;herbage&lt;/strong&gt; which might have maintained millions of sheep and cattle. Scientists discovered that this particular variety of rabbit (and apparently no other animal) was susceptible to a fatal virus disease, &lt;strong&gt;myxomatosis&lt;/strong&gt;. By infecting animals and letting them loose in the burrows, local epidemics of this disease could be created. Later it was found that there was a type of mosquito which acted as the carrier of this disease and passed it on to the rabbits. So while the rest of the world was trying to get rid of mosquitoes, Australia was encouraging this one. It effectively spread the disease all over the continent and drastically reduced the rabbit population. lt later became apparent that rabbits were developing a degree of resistance to this disease, so that the rabbit population was unlikely to be completely exterminated. There were hopes, however, that the problem of the rabbit would become manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ironically&lt;/strong&gt;, Europe, which had &lt;strong&gt;bequeathed&lt;/strong&gt; the rabbit as a pest to Australia acquired this man-made disease as a &lt;strong&gt;pestilence&lt;/strong&gt;. A French physician decided to get rid of the wild rabbits on his own estate and introduced &lt;strong&gt;myxomatosis&lt;/strong&gt;. It did not, however, remain within the confines of his estate. It spread through France where wild rabbits are not generally regarded as a pest but as a sport and a useful food supply, and it spread to Britain where wild rabbits are regarded as a pest but where domesticated rabbits, equally susceptible to the disease, are the basis of a profitable fur industry. The question became one of whether Man could control the disease he had invented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it overran xx 蔓延&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enterprising  / ˈɛntəˌpraɪzɪŋ /  An enterprising person is willing to try out new, unusual ways of doing or achieving something. 有开拓精神的; 有创新精神的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settler / ˈsɛtlə, ˈsɛtəl- / Settlers are people who go to live in a new country. 移民者&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;promiscuous / prəˈmɪskjʊəs /  Someone who is promiscuous has sex with many different people. 淫乱的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;burrow  / ˈbʌrəʊ / If an animal burrows into the ground or into a surface, it moves through it by making a tunnel or hole. 掘地洞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exterminate / ɪkˈstɜːmɪˌneɪt / To exterminate a group of people or animals means to kill all of them. 消灭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;herbage / ˈhɜːbɪdʒ /  草本的总称&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx discovered that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;later it was found that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it effectively 动词 xxxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is unlikely to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ironically / aɪˈrɒnɪkəlɪ /  You use ironically to draw attention to a situation that is odd or amusing because it involves a contrast. 具有讽刺意味的是&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bequeath / bɪˈkwiːð / If you bequeath your money or property to someone, you legally state that they should have it when you die. 遗赠&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pestilence  / ˈpɛstɪləns /  Pestilence is any disease that spreads quickly and kills large numbers of people. 瘟疫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;physician / fɪˈzɪʃən / A physician is a medical doctor. 内科医生&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;domesticate  / dəˈmɛstɪˌkeɪt / When people domesticate wild animals or plants, they bring them under control and use them to produce food or as pets. 驯养; 引种驯化&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》13~15</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5413~15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5413~15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-search-for-oil&#34;&gt;The search for oil&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deepest holes of all are made for oil, and they go down to as much as 25,000 feet. But we do not need to send men down to get the oil out, as we must with other mineral &lt;strong&gt;deposits&lt;/strong&gt;. The holes are only &lt;strong&gt;borings&lt;/strong&gt;, less than a foot in &lt;strong&gt;diameter&lt;/strong&gt;. My particular experience is largely in oil, and the search for oil has done more to improve deep drilling than any other mining activity. When it has been decided where we are going to drill, we &lt;strong&gt;put up&lt;/strong&gt; at the surface an oil &lt;strong&gt;derrick&lt;/strong&gt;. It has to be tall because it is like a giant block and tackle, and we have to lower into the ground and &lt;strong&gt;haul&lt;/strong&gt; out of the ground great lengths of drill pipe which are rotated by an engine at the top and are &lt;strong&gt;fitted&lt;/strong&gt; with a cutting &lt;strong&gt;bit&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The geologist needs to know what rocks the drill has reached, so &lt;strong&gt;every so often&lt;/strong&gt; a sample is obtained with a &lt;strong&gt;coring&lt;/strong&gt; bit. It cuts a clean &lt;strong&gt;cylinder&lt;/strong&gt; of rock, from which can be seen the &lt;strong&gt;strata&lt;/strong&gt; the drill has been cutting through. Once we get down to the oil, it usually flows to the surface because great pressure, either from gas or water, is pushing it. This pressure must be under control, and we control it &lt;strong&gt;by means of&lt;/strong&gt; the mud which we circulate down the drill pipe. We &lt;strong&gt;endeavour to&lt;/strong&gt; avoid the old, romantic idea of a &lt;strong&gt;gusher&lt;/strong&gt;, which wastes oil and gas. We want it to stay down the hole until we can lead it off &lt;strong&gt;in a&lt;/strong&gt; controlled &lt;strong&gt;manner&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deposit / dɪˈpɒzɪt / A deposit is an amount of a substance that has been left somewhere as a result of a chemical or geological process. 沉积物; 矿床&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boring / ˈbɔːrɪŋ / the act or process of making or enlarging a hole 钻孔; 扩洞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diameter / daɪˈæmɪtə / The diameter of a round object is the length of a straight line that can be drawn across it, passing through the middle of it. 直径&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put up: If people put up a wall, building, tent, or other structure, they construct it so that it is upright. 建造&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;derrick / ˈdɛrɪk / A derrick is a tower built over an oil well which is used to raise and lower the drill. 油井塔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;haul / hɔːl / If you haul something which is heavy or difficult to move, you move it using a lot of effort. (用力地) 拉&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fitted: If you fit something somewhere, you attach it there, or put it there carefully and securely. 安装&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every so often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cylinder  / ˈsɪlɪndə / A cylinder is an object with flat circular ends and long straight sides. 圆柱&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strata /&amp;lsquo;strætɚ/ are different layers of rock. 岩层&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by means of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;endeavour / ɪnˈdɛvə / If you endeavour to do something, you try very hard to do it. 努力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gusher  / ˈɡʌʃə /  喷油井&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx has done more to improve zzz than any other yyy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-butterfly-effect&#34;&gt;The Butterfly Effect&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond two or three days, the world’s best weather forecasts are speculative, and beyond six or seven they are worthless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Butterfly Effect is the reason. For small pieces of weather—and to a global forecaster, small can mean thunderstorms and &lt;strong&gt;blizzards&lt;/strong&gt; – any prediction deteriorates rapidly. Errors and uncertainties multiply, cascading upward through a chain of &lt;strong&gt;turbulent&lt;/strong&gt; features, from dust devils and &lt;strong&gt;squalls&lt;/strong&gt; up to continent-size &lt;strong&gt;eddies&lt;/strong&gt; that only satellites can see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern weather models work with a grid of points of the order of sixty miles apart, and even so, some starting data has to be guessed, since ground stations and satellites cannot see everywhere. But suppose the earth could be covered with sensors spaced one foot apart, rising at one-foot intervals all the way to to top of the atmosphere. Suppose every sensor gives perfectly accurate readings of temperature, pressure, humidity, and any other quantity a &lt;strong&gt;meteorologist&lt;/strong&gt; would want. Precisely at noon an infinitely powerful computer takes all the data and calculates what will happen at each point at 12.01, then 12.02, then 12.03&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The computer will still be unable to predict whether Princeton, New Jersey, will have sun or rain on a day one month away. At noon the spaces between the sensors will hide fluctuations that the computer will not know about, tiny deviations from the average. By 12.01, those fluctuations will already have created small errors one foot away. Soon the errors will have multiplied to the ten-foot scale, and so on up to the size of the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blizzard / ˈblɪzəd / A blizzard is a very bad snowstorm with strong winds. 暴风雪&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cascade / kæsˈkeɪd / If water cascades somewhere, it pours or flows downward very fast and in large quantities. 倾泻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;turbulent  / ˈtɜːbjʊlənt /    Turbulent water or air contains strong currents which change direction suddenly. (水流或气体) 湍急的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dust devil: a strong miniature whirlwind that whips up dust, litter, leaves, etc into the air 尘暴&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squall / skwɔːl / A squall is a sudden strong wind which often causes a brief, violent rainstorm or snowstorm. 飑; 突起的狂风(常引起短暂暴雨或暴雪)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eddy /&amp;lsquo;ɛdi/ 漩涡&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meteorologist /ˌmitiəˈrɑlədʒɪst/ 气象学家&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of the order of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppose xxx could be xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;secrecy-in-industry&#34;&gt;Secrecy in industry&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two factors weigh heavily against the effectiveness of scientific in industry. One is the general atmosphere of secrecy in which it is carried out, the other the lack of freedom of the individual research worker. In so far as any inquiry is a secret one, it naturally limits all those engaged in carrying it out from effective contact with their fellow scientists either in other countries or in universities, or even , often enough , in other departments of the same firm. The degree of secrecy naturally &lt;strong&gt;varies considerably&lt;/strong&gt;. Some of the bigger firms are engaged in researches which are of such general and fundamental nature that it is a positive advantage to them not to keep them secret. Yet a great many processes depending on such research are sought for with complete secrecy until the stage at which patents can be taken out. Even more processes are never patented at all but kept as secret processes. This applies particularly to chemical industries, where chance discoveries play a much larger part than they do in physical and mechanical industries. Sometimes the secrecy goes to such an extent that the whole nature of the research cannot be mentioned. Many firms, for instance, have great difficulty in obtaining technical or scientific books from libraries because they are unwilling to have their names entered as having taken out such and such a book for fear the agents of other firms should be able to trace the kind of research they are likely to be undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx either in xxx or in xxx, or even in xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;event xxx are never yyy at all but&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this applies particularly to xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes xxx goes to such a extent that xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xxx, for instance, xxx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》10~12</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5410~12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 23:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B5410~12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;silicon-valley&#34;&gt;Silicon valley&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology trends may push Silicon Valley &lt;strong&gt;back&lt;/strong&gt; to the future. Carver Mead, a pioneer in integrated circuits and a professor of computer science at the California Institute of Technology, notes there are now workstations that enable engineers to design, test and produce chips right on their desks, &lt;strong&gt;much the way&lt;/strong&gt; an editor creates a newsletter on a Macintosh. As the time and cost of making a chip &lt;strong&gt;drop&lt;/strong&gt; to a few days and a few hundred dollars, engineers may soon be free to let their imaginations soar without being penalized by expensive failures. Mead predicts that inventors will be able to perfect powerful customized chips over a weekend at the office—spawning a new generation of garage start-ups and &lt;strong&gt;giving&lt;/strong&gt; the U.S. &lt;strong&gt;a jump on its&lt;/strong&gt; foreign rivals in &lt;strong&gt;getting&lt;/strong&gt; new products &lt;strong&gt;to&lt;/strong&gt; market fast. ‘We’ve got more garages with smart people,’ Mead observes. ‘We really &lt;strong&gt;thrive&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;anarchy&lt;/strong&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on Asians. Already, orientals and Asian Americans &lt;strong&gt;constitute&lt;/strong&gt; the majority of the engineering staffs at many Valley firms. And Chinese, Korean, Filipino and Indian engineers are graduating in &lt;strong&gt;droves&lt;/strong&gt; from California’s colleges. As &lt;strong&gt;the heads of&lt;/strong&gt; next-generation start-ups, these Asian innovators can &lt;strong&gt;draw on&lt;/strong&gt; customs and languages to &lt;strong&gt;forge&lt;/strong&gt; tighter links with crucial Pacific &lt;strong&gt;Rim&lt;/strong&gt; market. For instance, Alex Au, a Stanford Ph.D. from Hong Kong, has set up a Taiwan factory to challenge Japan’s near &lt;strong&gt;lock on&lt;/strong&gt; the memory-chip market. India-born N. Damodar Reddy’s tiny California company reopened an AT&amp;amp;T chip plant in Kansas City last spring with financing from the state of Missouri. Before it becomes a retirement village, Silicon Valley may &lt;strong&gt;prove&lt;/strong&gt; a classroom for building a global business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;much the way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drop / drɒp / If a level or amount drops or if someone or something drops it, it quickly becomes less. 使迅速下降; 迅速下降&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thrive  / θraɪv / If you say that someone thrives on a particular situation, you mean that they enjoy it or that they can deal with it very well, especially when other people find it unpleasant or difficult. 喜欢; 从容应对 (尤指别人不喜欢或认为困难的事)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anarchy / ˈænəkɪ /  If you describe a situation as anarchy, you mean that nobody seems to be paying any attention to rules or laws. 无政府状态&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constitute / ˈkɒnstɪˌtjuːt / If something constitutes a particular thing, it can be regarded as being that thing. 构成&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drove  / drəʊv / a herd of livestock being driven together (被驱赶着一起前进的)畜群&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;draw on If you draw on or draw upon something such as your skill or experience, you make use of it in order to do something. 利用&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forge / fɔːdʒ /  If one person or institution forges an agreement or relationship with another, they create it with a lot of hard work, hoping that it will be strong or lasting. 努力地缔造&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rim  / rɪm / The rim of a circular object is its outside edge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lock on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prove  / pruːv / If something proves to be true or to have a particular quality, it becomes clear after a period of time that it is true or has that quality. 证明是&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-grow-old&#34;&gt;How to grow old&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some old people are &lt;strong&gt;oppressed&lt;/strong&gt; by the fear of death. In the young there is a justification for this feeling. Young men who have reason to fear that they will be killed in battle may &lt;strong&gt;justifiably&lt;/strong&gt; feel bitter in the thought that they have been cheated of the best things that life has to offer. But in an old man who has known human joys and sorrows, and has achieved whatever work it was in him to do, the fear of death is somewhat &lt;strong&gt;abject&lt;/strong&gt; and ignoble. The best way to overcome it-so at least it seems to me&amp;mdash;-is to make your interests gradually wider and more &lt;strong&gt;impersonal&lt;/strong&gt;, until bit by bit the walls of the &lt;strong&gt;ego&lt;/strong&gt; recede, and your life becomes increasingly merged in the universal life. An individual human &lt;strong&gt;existence&lt;/strong&gt; should be like a river&amp;ndash;small at first, narrowly contained within its banks, and rushing passionately past &lt;strong&gt;boulders&lt;/strong&gt; and over waterfalls. Gradually the river grows wider, the banks recede, the waters flow more quietly, and in the end, without any visible break, they become merged in the sea, and painlessly lose their individual being. The man who, in old age, can see his life in this way, will not suffer from the fear of death, since the things he cares for will continue. And it, with the decay of &lt;strong&gt;vitality&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;weariness&lt;/strong&gt; increases, the thought of rest will be not unwelcome. I should wish to die while still at work, knowing that others will carry on what I can no longer do, and content in the thought that what was possible has been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grow old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oppress / əˈprɛs / To oppress people means to treat them cruelly, or to prevent them from having the same opportunities, freedom, and benefits as others. 压迫&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;justification / ˌdʒʌstɪfɪˈkeɪʃən / A justification for something is an acceptable reason or explanation for it. 正当的理由&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abject  / ˈæbdʒɛkt /  You use abject to emphasize that a situation or quality is extremely bad. 糟糕透顶的 [强调]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impersonal  / ɪmˈpɜːsənəl /  If you describe someone&amp;rsquo;s behaviour as impersonal, you mean that they do not show any emotion about the person they are dealing with. 不受个人感情影响的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ego  / ˈiːɡəʊ, ˈɛgəʊ / Someone&amp;rsquo;s ego is their sense of their own worth. For example, if someone has a large ego, they think they are very important and valuable. 自我价值感&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vitality / vaɪˈtælɪtɪ /   If you say that someone or something has vitality, you mean that they have great energy and liveliness. 活力&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;weariness /&amp;lsquo;wɪrɪnɪs/ temporary loss of strength and energy resulting from hard physical or mental work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boulder  / ˈbəʊldə /  A boulder is a large rounded rock. 圆形巨石&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content / ˈkɒntɛnt / If you are content, you are fairly happy or satisfied. 满意的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;banks-and-their-customers&#34;&gt;Banks and their customers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When anyone opens a current account at a bank, he is lending the bank money, repayment of which he may demand at any time, either in cash or by &lt;strong&gt;drawing a cheque&lt;/strong&gt; in favour of another person. Primarily, the banker-customer relationship is that of debtor and creditor&amp;ndash;who is which depending on whether the customer&amp;rsquo;s account is &lt;strong&gt;in credit&lt;/strong&gt; or is overdrawn. But, in addition to that basically simple concept, the bank and its customer owe a large number of obligations to one another. Many of these obligations can give rise to problems and complications but a bank customer, unlike, say, a buyer of goods, cannot complain that the law is &lt;strong&gt;loaded against&lt;/strong&gt; him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank must obey its customer&amp;rsquo;s instructions, and not those of anyone else. When, for example, a customer first opens an account, he instructs the bank to debit his account only in respect of cheques drawn by himself. He gives the bank &lt;strong&gt;specimens&lt;/strong&gt; of his signature, and there is a very firm rule that the bank has no right or authority to pay out a customer&amp;rsquo;s money on a cheque on which its customer&amp;rsquo;s signature has been forged. It makes no difference that the &lt;strong&gt;forgery&lt;/strong&gt; may have been a very skilful one: the bank must recognize its customer&amp;rsquo;s signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason there is no risk to the customer in the modern practice, adopted by some banks, of printing the customer&amp;rsquo;s name on his cheques. If this facilitates forgery it is the bank which will lose, not the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repayment  / rɪˈpeɪmənt / The repayment of money is the act or process of paying it back to the person you owe it to. 偿还&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in favour of 受益人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;primarily / ˈpraɪmərəlɪ / You use primarily to say what is mainly true in a particular situation. 主要地&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in credit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;debit  / ˈdɛbɪt / A debit is a record of the money taken from your bank account, for example, when you write a cheque. 借方&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;loaded / ˈləʊdɪd / If you say that something is loaded in favour of someone, you mean it works unfairly to their advantage. If you say it is loaded against them, you mean it works unfairly to their disadvantage. 有偏向的 [表不满]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in respect of concerning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;specimen / ˈspɛsɪmɪn / A specimen of something is an example of it which gives an idea of what the whole of it is like. 样本&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forge / fɔːdʒ / If someone forges something such as paper money, a document, or a painting, they copy it or make it so that it looks genuine, in order to deceive people. 伪造 (纸币、文件或画作等)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the practice of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complication  / ˌkɒmplɪˈkeɪʃən / A complication is a problem or difficulty that makes a situation harder to deal with. 使情况复杂化的因素&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》7~9</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B547~9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 19:12:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B547~9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;bats&#34;&gt;Bats&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all sounds made by animals &lt;strong&gt;serve as&lt;/strong&gt; language, and we have only to turn to that extraordinary discovery of echo-location in bats to see a case in which the voice plays a strictly &lt;strong&gt;utilitarian&lt;/strong&gt; role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a full appreciation of what this means we must turn first to some recent human inventions. Everyone knows that if he shouts in the &lt;strong&gt;vicinity&lt;/strong&gt; of a wall or a mountainside, an echo will come back. The further off this solid &lt;strong&gt;obstruction&lt;/strong&gt; the longer time will &lt;strong&gt;elapse&lt;/strong&gt; for the return of the echo. A sound made by tapping on the &lt;strong&gt;hull&lt;/strong&gt; of a ship will be reflected from the sea bottom, and by measuring the time interval between the taps and the receipt of the echoes the depth of the sea at that point can be calculated. So was born the echo-sounding &lt;strong&gt;apparatus&lt;/strong&gt;, now in general use in ships. Every solid object will reflect a sound, varying according to the size and nature of the object. A &lt;strong&gt;shoal&lt;/strong&gt; of fish will do this. So it is a &lt;strong&gt;comparatively&lt;/strong&gt; simple step from locating the sea bottom to locating a shoal of fish. With experience, and with improved apparatus, it is now possible not only to locate a shoal but to tell if it is &lt;strong&gt;herring&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cod&lt;/strong&gt;, or other well-known fish, by the pattern of its echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago it was found that certain bats &lt;strong&gt;emit&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;squeaks&lt;/strong&gt; and by receiving the echoes they could locate and &lt;strong&gt;steer&lt;/strong&gt; clear of obstacles&amp;ndash;or locate flying insects on which they feed. This echo-location in bats is often compared with radar, the principle of which is similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utilitarian  / juːˌtɪlɪˈtɛərɪən / objects and buildings are designed to be useful rather than attractive. (物体、建筑等) 实用的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vicinity / vɪˈsɪnɪtɪ / If something is in the vicinity of a particular place, it is near it. (在…) 附近&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elapse / ɪˈlæps /  When time elapses, it passes. (时间) 流逝&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tap / tæp / If you tap something, you hit it with a quick light blow or a series of quick light blows. 轻敲&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apparatus / ˌæpəˈreɪtəs / the equipment, such as tools and machines, which is used to do a particular job or activity. 设备&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shoal / ʃəʊl / A shoal of fish is a large group of them swimming together. 鱼群&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;herring  / ˈhɛrɪŋ /  A herring is a long silver-coloured fish. Herring live in large groups in the ocean. 鲱 (鱼)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cod / kɒd / Cod are a type of large edible fish. 鳕鱼&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emit  / ɪˈmɪt / To emit a sound or noise means to produce it. 发出 (声音或噪音)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squeak / skwiːk / If something or someone squeaks, they make a short, high-pitched sound. 发出短而尖的声音&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;steer / stɪə / If you steer clear of someone or something, you deliberately avoid them. 有意避开某人/某物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;trading-standards&#34;&gt;Trading standards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chickens &lt;strong&gt;slaughtered&lt;/strong&gt; in the United States, claim officials in Brussels, are not fit to &lt;strong&gt;grace&lt;/strong&gt; European tables. No, say the Americans: our &lt;strong&gt;fowl&lt;/strong&gt; are fine, we simply clean them in a different way. These days, it is differences in national regulations, far more than tariffs, that put sand in the wheels of trade between rich countries. It is not just farmers who are complaining . An electric &lt;strong&gt;razor&lt;/strong&gt; that meets the European Union’s safety standards must be approved by American testers before it can be sold in the United States, and an American-made &lt;strong&gt;dialysis&lt;/strong&gt; machine needs the EU’s okay before it &lt;strong&gt;hits&lt;/strong&gt; the market in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, a razor that is safe in Europe is unlikely to &lt;strong&gt;electrocute&lt;/strong&gt; Americans. So, ask businesses on both sides of the Atlantic, why have two lots of tests where one would do? Politicians agree, in principle, so America and the EU have been trying to reach a deal which would eliminate the need to double-test many products. They hope to finish in time for a trade summit between America and EU on May 28th. Although negotiators are optimistic, the details are complex enough that they may be &lt;strong&gt;hard-pressed&lt;/strong&gt; to get a deal at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? One difficulty is to construct the agreements. The Americans would happily reach one accord on standards for medical devices and then &lt;strong&gt;hammer&lt;/strong&gt; out different pacts covering, say, electronic goods and drug manufacturing. The EU-following fine &lt;strong&gt;continental&lt;/strong&gt; traditions—wants agreement on general principles, which could be applied to many types of products and have extended to other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slaughter / ˈslɔːtə / If large numbers of people or animals are slaughtered, they are killed in a way that is cruel or unnecessary. 屠杀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grace / ɡreɪs / If you say that something graces a place or a person, you mean that it makes them more attractive. 使优美&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fowl  / faʊl / A fowl is a bird, especially one that can be eaten as food, such as a duck or a chicken. 家禽&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;razor / ˈreɪzə / A razor is a tool that people use for shaving. 剃刀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dialysis / daɪˈælɪsɪs /   Dialysis or kidney dialysis is a method of treating kidney failure by using a machine to remove waste material from the kidneys. (肾的)透析&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;electrocute  / ɪˈlɛktrəˌkjuːt /  If someone is electrocuted, they are accidentally killed or badly injured when they touch something connected to a source of electricity. 使…触电 (死亡或受伤)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hammer If people hammer out an agreement or treaty, they succeed in producing it after a long or difficult discussion. (经过长时间或艰难的讨论) 制定出&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continental  / ˌkɒntɪˈnɛntəl / Continental is used to refer to something that belongs to or relates to a continent. 大陆的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;royal-espionage&#34;&gt;Royal &lt;strong&gt;espionage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfred the Great acted as his own spy, visiting Danish camps disguised as a &lt;strong&gt;minstrel&lt;/strong&gt;. In those days wandering minstrels were welcome everywhere. They were not fighting men, and their &lt;strong&gt;harp&lt;/strong&gt; was their passport. Alfred had learned many of their &lt;strong&gt;ballads&lt;/strong&gt; in his youth, and could vary his programme with &lt;strong&gt;acrobatic&lt;/strong&gt; tricks and simple &lt;strong&gt;conjuring&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Alfred&amp;rsquo;s little army slowly began to gather at Athelney, the king himself set out to &lt;strong&gt;penetrate&lt;/strong&gt; the camp of Guthrum, the commander of the Danish invaders. These had &lt;strong&gt;settled down&lt;/strong&gt; for the winter at Chippenham: &lt;strong&gt;thither&lt;/strong&gt; Alfred went. He noticed at once that discipline was slack: the Danes had the self-confidence of &lt;strong&gt;conquerors&lt;/strong&gt;, and their security precautions were casual. They lived well, on the &lt;strong&gt;proceeds&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;raids&lt;/strong&gt; on neighbouring regions. There they collected women as well as food and drink, and &lt;strong&gt;a life of ease&lt;/strong&gt; had made them soft. Alfred stayed in the camp a week before he returned to Athelney. The force there assembled was trivial compared with the Danish &lt;strong&gt;horde&lt;/strong&gt;. But Alfred had deduced that the Danes were no longer fit for prolonged battle : and that their &lt;strong&gt;commissariat&lt;/strong&gt; had no organization, but depended on irregular raids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, faced with the Danish &lt;strong&gt;advance&lt;/strong&gt;, Alfred did not risk open battle but &lt;strong&gt;harried&lt;/strong&gt; the enemy. He was constantly on the move, drawing the Danes after him. His &lt;strong&gt;patrols&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;halted&lt;/strong&gt; the raiding parties: hunger &lt;strong&gt;assailed&lt;/strong&gt; the Danish army. Now Alfred began a long series of &lt;strong&gt;skirmishes&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;and within a month the Danes had surrendered. The episode could reasonably serve as a unique &lt;strong&gt;epic&lt;/strong&gt; of royal espionage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;espionage / ˈɛspɪəˌnɑːʒ /  Espionage is the activity of finding out the political, military, or industrial secrets of your enemies or rivals by using spies. 间谍活动&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minstrel / ˈmɪnstrəl /  a minstrel was a singer and musician who travelled around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harp / hɑːp / You play the harp by plucking the strings with your fingers. 竖琴&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ballad / ˈbæləd / A ballad is a long song or poem which tells a story in simple language. 叙事歌; 民间叙事诗&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acrobatic / ˈækrəˌbætɪk / An acrobatic movement or display involves difficult physical acts such as jumping and balancing, especially in a circus. 杂技的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conjuring  / ˈkʌndʒərɪŋ /  the performance of tricks that appear to defy natural laws 魔术&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;penetrate / ˈpɛnɪˌtreɪt / If something or someone penetrates a physical object or an area, they succeed in getting into it or passing through it. 进入; 穿透&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proceeds /&amp;lsquo;prosidz/ The proceeds of an event or activity are the money that has been obtained from it. (某事件或活动带来的) 收入&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;raid / reɪd / When soldiers raid a place, they make a sudden armed attack against it, with the aim of causing damage rather than occupying any of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s land. 突袭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;horde / hɔːd / If you describe a crowd of people as a horde, you mean that the crowd is very large and excited and, often, rather frightening or unpleasant. (通常指熙攘纷扰的) 一大群人&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commissariat  / ˌkɒmɪˈsɛərɪət / a government department before 1946 (前苏联)1946年前的政府部门 (Now called ministry)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harry / ˈhærɪ / If someone harries you, they keep bothering you or trying to get something from you. (不断)骚扰; 纠缠&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patrol / pəˈtrəʊl / When soldiers, police, or guards patrol an area or building, they move around it in order to make sure that there is no trouble there. 在…巡逻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;halt / hɔːlt /  When a person or a vehicle halts or when something halts them, they stop moving in the direction they were going and stand still. 使停住; 停住&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assail  / əˈseɪl / If someone assails you, they attack you violently. 攻击&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skirmish  / ˈskɜːmɪʃ / A skirmish is a minor battle. 小规模战斗; 小冲突&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;epic / ˈɛpɪk / An epic is a long book, poem, or film whose story extends over a long period of time or tells of great events. 史诗; 史诗般的作品&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》4~6</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B544~6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 22:45:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B544~6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lesson-4-seeing-hands&#34;&gt;Lesson 4 Seeing hands&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Soviet Union several cases have been reported recently of people who can read and detect colours with their fingers, and even &lt;strong&gt;see through&lt;/strong&gt; solid doors and walls. One case &lt;strong&gt;concerns&lt;/strong&gt; an &amp;lsquo;eleven-year-old schoolgirl, Vera Petrova, who has normal vision but who can also &lt;strong&gt;perceive&lt;/strong&gt; things with different parts of her skin, and through solid walls. This ability was first noticed by her father. One day she came into his office and &lt;strong&gt;happened&lt;/strong&gt; to put her hands on the door of a locked safe. Suddenly she asked her father why he kept so many old newspapers locked away there, and even described the way they were &lt;strong&gt;done up&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;bundles&lt;/strong&gt;. Vera&amp;rsquo;s curious talent was brought to the notice of a scientific research institute in the town of UIyanovsk, near where she lives, and in April she was given a series of tests by a special &lt;strong&gt;commission&lt;/strong&gt; of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federal Republic. During these tests she was able to read a newspaper through an opaque screen and, stranger still, by moving her elbow over a child&amp;rsquo;s game of Lotto she was able to describe the figures and colours printed on it; and, in another instance, wearing stockings and slippers, to &lt;strong&gt;make out&lt;/strong&gt; with her foot the outlines and colours of a picture hidden under a &lt;strong&gt;carpet&lt;/strong&gt;. Other experiments showed that her knees and shoulders had a similar sensitivity. During all these tests Vera was &lt;strong&gt;blindfold&lt;/strong&gt;; and, indeed, except when blindfold she lacked the ability to perceive things with her skin. lt was also found that although she could perceive things with her fingers this ability ceased the moment her hands were wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concern: /kənˈsɚn/ to relate to (something or someone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perceive /pɚˈsiːv/ to notice or become aware of (something)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;happen: /ˈhæpən/ to do or be something by chance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do up:  to wrap (something).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bundle: /ˈbʌndəl/ a group of things that are fastened, tied, or wrapped together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commission: /kəˈmɪʃən/ a group of people who have been given the official job of finding information about something or controlling something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make out: to see and identify (something)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carpet: /ˈkɑɚpət/ a thick covering : a thick layer of something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blindfold: /ˈblaɪndˌfoʊld/ cover the eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;lesson-5-youth&#34;&gt;Lesson 5 Youth&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are always talking about &amp;lsquo;the problem of youth&amp;rsquo;. If there is one&amp;ndash;which I take leave to doubt&amp;ndash;then it is older people who create it, not the young themselves. Let us &lt;strong&gt;get down to&lt;/strong&gt; fundamentals and agree that the young are after all human beings&amp;ndash;people just like their elders. There is only one difference between an old man and a young one: the young man has a glorious future before him and the old one has a splendid future behind him: and maybe that is where the &lt;strong&gt;rub&lt;/strong&gt; is.
When I was a teenager, I felt that I was just young and uncertain&amp;ndash;that I was a new boy in a huge school, and I would have been very pleased to be regarded as something so interesting as a problem. For one thing, being a problem gives you a certain identity, and that is one of the things the young are busily engaged in seeking.
I find young people exciting. They have an air of freedom, and they have not a &lt;strong&gt;dreary&lt;/strong&gt; commitment to mean ambitions or love of comfort. They are not anxious social climbers, and they have &lt;strong&gt;no devotion to&lt;/strong&gt; material things. All this seems to me to link them with life, and the origins of things. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they were in some sense cosmic beings in &lt;strong&gt;violent&lt;/strong&gt; and lovely contrast with us &lt;strong&gt;suburban&lt;/strong&gt; creatures. All that is in my mind when I meet a young person. He may be &lt;strong&gt;conceited&lt;/strong&gt;, ill-mannered, &lt;strong&gt;presumptuous&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;fatuous&lt;/strong&gt;, but I do not turn for protection to &lt;strong&gt;dreary&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;clichés&lt;/strong&gt; about respect for elders&amp;ndash;as if mere age were a reason for respect. I accept that we are equals, and I will argue with him, as an equal, if I think he is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get down to: to start doing something that is difficult or needs a lot of time or energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rub: /ˈrʌb/ something that causes a difficulty or problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dreary: /ˈdriri/ dull and making you feel sad or bored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;violent: /ˈvajələnt/ very forceful or intense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;suburban: /səˈbɚbən/ boring and typical of people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conceited: /kənˈsiːtəd/ having or showing too much pride in your own worth or goodness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;presumptuous: /prɪˈzʌmptʃuəs/ doing something that you have no right to do and that seems rude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fatuous: /ˈfætʃuəs/ very silly or stupid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clichés: an idea or phrase that has been used so much that it is not effective or does not have any meaning any longer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;lesson-6-the-sporting-spirit&#34;&gt;Lesson 6 The sporting spirit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am always amazed when I hear people saying that sport creates &lt;strong&gt;goodwill&lt;/strong&gt; between the nations, and that if only the common peoples of the world could meet one another at football or cricket, they would have no &lt;strong&gt;inclination&lt;/strong&gt; to meet on the battlefield. Even if one didn&amp;rsquo;t know from concrete examples (the 1936 Olympic Games, for instance) that international sporting contests lead to &lt;strong&gt;orgies&lt;/strong&gt; of hatred, one could &lt;strong&gt;deduce&lt;/strong&gt; it from general principles. Nearly all the sports practised nowadays are competitive. You play to win, and the game has little meaning unless you do your utmost to win. On the village green, where you &lt;strong&gt;pick up sides&lt;/strong&gt; and no feeling of local &lt;strong&gt;patriotism&lt;/strong&gt; is involved, it is possible to play simply for the fun and exercise: but as soon as the question of &lt;strong&gt;prestige&lt;/strong&gt; arises, as soon as you feel that you and some larger unit will be &lt;strong&gt;disgraced&lt;/strong&gt; if you lose, the most &lt;strong&gt;savage&lt;/strong&gt; combative instincts are &lt;strong&gt;aroused&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyone who has played even in a school football match knows this. At the international level sport is frankly mimic &lt;strong&gt;warfare&lt;/strong&gt;. But the significant thing is not the behaviour of the players but the attitude of the &lt;strong&gt;spectators&lt;/strong&gt;: and, behind the spectators, of the nations who work themselves into &lt;strong&gt;furies&lt;/strong&gt; over these &lt;strong&gt;absurd&lt;/strong&gt; contests, and seriously believe&amp;ndash;&lt;strong&gt;at any rate&lt;/strong&gt; for short periods&amp;ndash;that running, jumping and kicking a ball are tests of national &lt;strong&gt;virtue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goodwill: /ˌgʊdˈwɪl/ a kind, helpful, or friendly feeling or attitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inclination: /ˌɪnkləˈneɪʃən/  a feeling of wanting to do something : a tendency to do something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;orgy: /ˈoɚʤi/ something that is done too much and in a wild way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deduce: /dɪˈduːs/ to use logic or reason to form (a conclusion or opinion about something)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;side: a sports team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prestige: /prɛˈstiːʒ/ the respect and admiration that someone or something gets for being successful or important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disgrace: /dɪˈskreɪs/ to cause (someone) to feel ashamed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;savage: /ˈsævɪʤ/ very cruel or violent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;arouse: /əˈraʊz/ to cause (an emotional or mental state)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;warfare: /ˈwoɚˌfeɚ/ military fighting in a war&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spectator: someone who is watching an event or game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fury: /ˈfjuri/ violent anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;absurd: /əbˈsɚd/ extremely silly, foolish, or unreasonable : completely ridiculous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at any rate: anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;virtue: /ˈvɚtʃu/ morally good behavior or character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《新概念4》1~3</title>
      <link>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B541~3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 18:44:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minghaochen.github.io/post/%E6%96%B0%E6%A6%82%E5%BF%B541~3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;finding-fossil-man&#34;&gt;Finding Fossil man&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can &lt;strong&gt;read of&lt;/strong&gt; things that happened 5,000 years ago in the Near East, where people first learned to write. But there are some parts of the world where even now people cannot write. The only way that they can preserve their history is to &lt;strong&gt;recount&lt;/strong&gt; it as sagas&amp;ndash;legends &lt;strong&gt;handed down&lt;/strong&gt; from one generation of story-tellers to another. These legends are useful because they can tell us something about migrations of people who lived long ago, but none could write down what they did. &lt;strong&gt;Anthropologists&lt;/strong&gt; wondered where the remote ancestors of the Polynesian (波利尼西亚人) peoples now living in the Pacific Islands (太平洋群岛) came from. The sagas of these people explain that some of them came from Indonesia (印度尼西亚) about 2,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the first people who were like ourselves lived so long ago that even their sagas, if they had any, are forgotten. So &lt;strong&gt;archaeologists&lt;/strong&gt; have neither history nor legends to help them to find out where the first &amp;lsquo;modern men&amp;rsquo; came from. Fortunately, however, ancient men made tools of stone, especially &lt;strong&gt;flint&lt;/strong&gt;, because this is easier to shape than other kinds. They may also have used wood and skins, but these have &lt;strong&gt;rotted away&lt;/strong&gt;. Stone does not decay, and so the tools of long ago have remained when even the bones of the men who made them have disappeared without trace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recount: /rɪˈkaʊnt/ to tell someone about (something that happened).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;saga: /ˈsɑːgə/ a long and complicated story with many details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hand down: to pass (something) from a person who is older (such as a parent) to a person who is younger (such as a child).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anthropologist: /ˌænθrəˈpɑːləʤi/ the study of human races, origins, societies, and cultures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;archaeologist: /ˌɑɚkiˈɑːləʤi/  a science that deals with past human life and activities by studying the bones, tools, etc., of ancient people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flint: /ˈflɪnt/ a hard type of rock that produces a small piece of burning material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;句型&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way that &amp;hellip; is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These &amp;hellip; are useful because &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sth explain that &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spare-that-spider&#34;&gt;Spare that spider&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, you may wonder, should spiders be our friends ? Because they destroy so many insects, and insects include some of the greatest enemies of the human race. Insects would make it impossible for us to live in the world; they would &lt;strong&gt;devour&lt;/strong&gt; all our crops and kill our flocks and herds, if it were not for the protection we get from insect-eating animals. We owe a lot to the birds and beasts who eat insects but all of them put together kill only &lt;strong&gt;a fraction of&lt;/strong&gt; the number destroyed by spiders. Moreover, unlike some of the other insect eaters, spiders never do the least harm to us or our belongings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiders are not insects, as many people think, nor even nearly related to them. One can tell the difference almost at a glance for a spider always has eight legs and an insect never more than six.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many spiders &lt;strong&gt;are engaged in&lt;/strong&gt; this work on our behalf ? One authority on spiders made a census of the spiders in a grass field in the south of England, and he estimated that there were more than 2,250,000 in one &lt;strong&gt;acre&lt;/strong&gt;, that is something like 6,000,000 spiders of different kinds on a football &lt;strong&gt;pitch&lt;/strong&gt;. Spiders are busy for at least half the year in killing insects. It is impossible to make more than the wildest guess at how many they kill, but they are hungry creatures, not content with only three meals a day. It has been estimated that the weight of all the insects destroyed by spiders in Britain in one year would be greater than the total weight of all the human beings in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spare: /ˈspeɚ/ to not destroy or harm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;devour: /dɪˈvawɚ/  to destroy (something) completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a fraction of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be engaged in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pitch: /ˈpɪtʃ/ an area that is used for playing sports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;句型&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has been estimated that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;matterhorn-马特洪峰-man&#34;&gt;Matterhorn (马特洪峰) man&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern &lt;strong&gt;alpinists&lt;/strong&gt; try to climb mountains by a route which will give them good sport, and the more difficult it is, the more highly it is regarded. In the pioneering days, however, this was not the case at all. The early climbers were looking for the easiest way to the top because the summit was the prize they sought, especially if it had never been attained before. It is true that during their explorations they often faced difficulties and dangers of the most perilous nature, equipped in a manner which would make a modern climber &lt;strong&gt;shudder&lt;/strong&gt; at the thought, but they did not go out of their way to court such excitement. They had a single aim, a solitary goal&amp;ndash;the top!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard for us to realize nowadays how difficult it was for the pioneers. &lt;strong&gt;Except for&lt;/strong&gt; one or two places such as Zermatt (策马特) and Chamonix (夏蒙尼), which had rapidly become popular, Alpine (阿尔卑斯山的) villages tended to be &lt;strong&gt;impoverished settlements&lt;/strong&gt; cut off from civilization by the high mountains. Such &lt;strong&gt;inns&lt;/strong&gt; as there were were generally dirty and &lt;strong&gt;flea-ridden&lt;/strong&gt;; the food simply local cheese accompanied by bread often twelve months old, all washed down with coarse wine. Often a valley boasted no inn at all, and climbers found shelter wherever they could&amp;ndash;sometimes with the local priest (who was usually as poor as his parishioners), sometimes with shepherds or cheesemakers. Invariably the background was the same: dirt and poverty, and very uncomfortable. For men accustomed to eating seven-course dinners and sleeping between fine &lt;strong&gt;linen&lt;/strong&gt; sheets at home, the change to the Alps must have been very hard indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;词汇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alpinist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shudder: /ˈʃʌdɚ/ to shake because of fear, cold, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;except for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impoverish: /ɪmˈpɑːvərɪʃ/ poor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;settlement: /ˈsɛtl̟mənt/ a place where people have come to live and where few or no people lived before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cut off + from: to be separate or alone: They are cut off from (contact with) the outside world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flea: /ˈfliː/ a very small insect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ridden: /ˈrɪdn̩/ filled with or containing something unpleasant or unwanted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boast: /ˈboʊst/ to have (something that is impressive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;linen: /ˈlɪnən/ a smooth, strong cloth made from flax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>